<string_table>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 12.7x55 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-12.7x55-fmj">
		<text>12.7x55 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-12.7x55-fmj_s">
		<text>12.7x55 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-12.7x55-fmj_descr">
		<text>The 12.7x55 is a subsonic round used primarily by the VKS Vykhlop. Its large size in combination with its ability to be fired over a great distance means that it delivers a massive amount of kinetic energy when impacting with a target.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------>
	<!----- 5.7x28 ----->
	<!------------------>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-ap">
		<text>5.7x28 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-ap_s">
		<text>5.7x28 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-ap_descr">
		<text>The armour piercing variant of this round boasts light anti-material capabilities, able to penetrate armour to a greater extent than what would be expected from the 9x19 round it was designed to replace.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-fmj">
		<text>5.7x28 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-fmj_s">
		<text>5.7x28 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-5.7x28-fmj_descr">
		<text>Originally created for the FN P90 and FN Five-seven, the 5.7x28 round is a small-calibre, high-velocity cartridge designed in response to NATO requests for a replacement for the ageing 9x19.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 12.7x99 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-50-bmg">
		<text>12.7x99 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-50-bmg_s">
		<text>12.7x99 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-50-bmg_descr">
		<text>More commonly known as the .50 BMG, the 12.7x99 round was developed at some point in the late 1910s and is effectively a greatly scaled up version of the 7.62x63 round. Over the years it has found itself being used by heavy machine guns during World War II and by anti-material sniper rifles in the modern day.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 7.62x25 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-p">
		<text>7.62x25 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-p_s">
		<text>7.62x25 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-p_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x25 Tokarev is a bottle-necked pistol cartridge widely used in former Soviet Union and its satellite states. The cartridge has largely been replaced in most capacities by the 9x18.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-ps">
		<text>7.62x25 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-ps_s">
		<text>7.62x25 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x25-ps_descr">
		<text>A steel-core variant of the standard 7.62x25 round allowing for much greater penetration when fired at soft targets.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 7.62x39 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-ap">
		<text>7.62x39 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-ap_descr">
		<text>A steel-core variant of the standard 7.62x39 round, as if it wasn't powerful enough already, a weapon firing this round will be able to punch even harder through tough materials and will decimate lightly armoured soft targets.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
		<text>7.62x39 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-fmj_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x39-fmj_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x39 round is a rifle cartridge of Soviet origin that was designed during World War II. Due to its use in, and the the worldwide proliferation of Kalashnikov pattern rifles, the cartridge is used by both militaries and civilians alike and is extremely common.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 7.62x51 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-ap">
		<text>7.62x51 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x51 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-ap_descr">
		<text>An armour piercing variant of the standard round, it uses a hardened steel-core to give the round increased penetration.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-fmj">
		<text>7.62x51 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-fmj_s">
		<text>7.62x51 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x51-fmj_descr">
		<text>The 7.62x51 round is a rimless bottlenecked rifle cartridge developed in the 1950s as a standard for small arms among NATO countries until it was largely superseded by the 5.56x45 round.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------->
	<!----- 7.62x54 ----->
	<!------------------->

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>7.62x54 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
		<text>7.62x54 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x54-7h1_descr">
		<text>7.62-calibre high precision armour-piercing sniper rounds. Typically used with the SVD and SVU sniper rifles.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------>
	<!----- 8.6x70 ----->
	<!------------------>

	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-8.6x70-fmj">
		<text>8.6x70 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-8.6x70-fmj_s">
		<text>8.6x70 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-8.6x70-fmj_descr">
		<text>The 8.6x70 round, also known as the .338 Lapua Magnum, is a rimless, bottlenecked, centerfire rifle cartridge. It serves as both an anti-personnel and anti-material round for sniper rifles. However its anti-material capabilities are hindered by its low kinetic energy.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!------------------------>
	<!----- VANILLA AMMO ----->
	<!------------------------>
	
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-og-7b">
		<text>PG-7VL warhead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>PG-7VL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-og-7b_descr">
		<text>Fragmentation warhead for anti-personnel warfare used with the RPG-7 grenade launcher. The main purpose of the warhead is to kill enemies in cover outside the range of hand grenades using the RPG-7 launcher.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
		<text>Cheap 7.62 calibre machine gun round. Its design makes it unsuitable for sniper rifles, so it is used only with the PKM machine gun.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-vog-25_descr">
		<text>Regular fragmentation grenade for the GP-25 Kostyor under-barrel grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="st_dxr_ammo-m209_descr">
		<text>40 mm grenade for the M203 under-barrel grenade launcher. This round has a 5 meter kill zone.</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>