<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_meat">
		<text>Flesh meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_meat_description">
		<text>Tough and bitter flesh meat is a frequently eaten meal in the Zone. Inexpensive, but most stalkers would prefer overpriced canned goods given the choice.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_boar_chop">
		<text>Boar chop</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_chop_description">
		<text>Much tougher to chew than their non-radioactive counterpart outside the Zone. Mutated boar chops will fetch a low but reasonable price.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_dog_meat">
		<text>Blind dog meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_meat_description">
		<text>Commonly harvested and traded in the Zone. Preferred over flesh meat because of its less bitter taste. Trades for a low but acceptable price.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_meat">
		<text>Pseudodog meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_meat_description">
		<text>Harder to obtain than dog meat, but tastes almost exactly the same. Most stalkers won't pay a substantial amount because of this.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_meat">
		<text>Bloodsucker meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_meat_description">
		<text>A stringy portion of bloodsucker meat. Despite the risks involved to kill one, it is often sold cheap because of its putrid taste.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_snork_hand">
		<text>Snork hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_hand_description">
		<text>The severed hand of a snork. Not drastically different from that of a person, but entirely grey, and covered in blisters and open wounds.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_fracture_hand">
		<text>Fracture hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_fracture_hand_description">
		<text>A hand which once belonged to a fracture. Whilst thin and very boney, it also has extraordinary long and pointy fingers.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_zombi_hand">
		<text>Zombie hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_zombi_hand_description">
		<text>A dirty and disgusting hand from a zombie. After losing all but their basic instincts, zombified stalkers resort to using their hands as weapons.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_chimera_meat">
		<text>Chimera meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_meat_description">
		<text>A heavy slab of meat harvested from a chimera. Not many get the chance to feast upon such a horrifying beast, so naturally the meat is found sold at high prices.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_meat">
		<text>Rodent meat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_meat_description">
		<text>Whilst it comes in small portions there is also quite a large supply. As a result the meat is quite inexpensive, worth about the same as that from a blind dog.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
		<text>Flesh eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
		<text>Completely different from those of the farm pigs they descended from, the eyeball of a flesh is heavy, large and entirely brown in colour.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
		<text>Boar hoof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
		<text>Boar hoofs are often worn by some stalkers around their necks as a good luck charm. Whilst others believe they have more 'exotic' uses when ground into a fine powder.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
		<text>Dog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
		<text>A long, hairless tail formerly attached to the rear of a blind dog. With no real practical use, they are the cheapest of all mutant body parts found in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
		<text>Psuedodog tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
		<text>The fur covering the tail of a pseudodog is a great insulator, and is often sewn into clothing and armoured suits when nearing the colder parts of the year.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
		<text>Bloodsucker tentacles</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
		<text>Tentacles from a bloodsucker produce a ferment that can dissolve through even the toughest mutant hides whilst simultaneously preventing blood from clotting. Many researchers, including the Ecologists, believe that they hold many secrets to great medical advances.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
		<text>Snork foot</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
		<text>Highly elasticated tendons found in the feet and legs of snorks give them the ability to make extraordinarily long leaps, much further than regular human beings.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_chimera_cogot">
		<text>Chimera tooth</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_cogot_description">
		<text>A tooth extracted from the mouth of a chimera. Unusually, the chimera sheds and replaces is teeth throughout the entirety of its lifetime, meaning most that are found usually broken or worn, and not very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_chimera_claw">
		<text>Chimera claw</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_chimera_claw_description">
		<text>Whilst able to tear through several sheets of Kevlar without struggle, they are often worn down through such extreme use, and much like their teeth, are shed and replaced frequently making them an inexpensive commodity.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_head">
		<text>Tushkano head</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_tushkano_head_description">
		<text>The eyes, ears, mouth and nose of a tushkano in a small, tiny package. Not very useful, nor very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_controller_brain">
		<text>Controller brain</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_controller_brain_description">
		<text>The brains of controllers are highly developed, able to take over the minds of other beings. For this very reason they are highly sought after by the Ecologists and can be sold for much more than most other mutant parts.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_controller_hand">
		<text>Controller hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_controller_hand_description">
		<text>A controller's hands are believed to assist its brain with some of its mental abilities, such as directing psychic bolt attacks. As such, they are highly sought after by the Ecologists, who value them equally as important as the controller's brain.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_cat_tail">
		<text>Cat tail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_cat_tail_description">
		<text>Cats in the Zone are believe to have evolved from local population of wild Lynx. Theirs tails are carried by stalkers as a symbol of awareness, giving them at least some value unlike those of their canine counterparts.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_pseudogigant_hand">
		<text>Pseudogiant hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_pseudogigant_hand_description">
		<text>A large, muscled hand from a pseudogiant which are ironically one of the smallest body parts of the creature. Not very useful but hard to obtain, so they can still get a good price if sold to the right buyer.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_pseudogigant_eye">
		<text>Pseudogiant eye</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_pseudogigant_eye_description">
		<text>A large, grotesque eyeball formerly belonging to a pseudogiant. It is interesting to note that a pseudogiant's eyeballs are usually two different sizes. While not particularly interesting, they can usually sell for a good price.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand">
		<text>Burer hand</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
		<text>The hands of a burer are directly linked to their psychic abilities, able to move objects, shield themselves and cause shock-waves from a distance. Naturally they are of particular interest to the Ecologists, and are very valuable.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_karlik_ear">
		<text>Karlik ear</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_karlik_ear_description">
		<text>A pointy ear from a karlik. About the only scientifically interesting body part, as the majority of the brain and its cells are destroyed by a release of chemicals upon death. Very valuable due to the luck and skill required to obtain them.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="mutant_crow_beak">
		<text>Crow beak</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mutant_crow_beak_description">
		<text>Somehow the Zone's crows are the only creatures not to have undergone drastic mutations. As such, researchers are interested in any body parts that can be retrieved, believing they have a strong immunity to the effects of radiation.</text>
	</string>
	
	
</string_table>
