<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<!-- FIND WEAPON FOR NIMBLE TASK -->
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_nimble_task_1_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_nimble_task_1_text">
		<text>Nimble has asked you to find a specific firearm. It needs to be in mint condition. Return to him when you find what he is looking for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_nimble_task_1_about">
		<text>I have a client looking for a specific firearm and I need someone to help me find it. If you are interested I will give you more details. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_nimble_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>%s... That is what I need, but it must be in mint condition. The client is paying top dollar and he doesn't want a rusty piece of shit that will jam up in a life or death situation. I'll give you most of the profit since you are doing all the work. Come back when you find it, man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_nimble_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>This is a fine weapon. I think my client will be pleased when I deliver this to him. Here is what I owe you.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ASSAULT BANDIT BASE FOR SIDOROVICH TASK -->
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_1_name">
		<text>Assault the car park</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_1_text">
		<text>Stage an assault on the car park and eliminate the bandits that occupy the location.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_1_about">
		<text>Bandits have taken up base in the old car park. These assholes mug or kill anyone who use the roads leading in and out of the camp. It is disrupting local activities for my clients and the stalkers who take refuge in camp. It's hurting business! I need you to "take care" of them. If you want, talk to Fanatic, he may be able to offer you assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_1_finish">
		<text>Great work, stalker! You and I will be best of friends if you keep this up! Here is what I promised.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR SIDOROVICH TASK -->
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_2_name">
		<text>Contract killer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_2_text">
		<text>Sidorovich contracted you to run a hit. Find and eliminate the target then return to Sidorovich for payment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_2_about">
		<text>I have a list of outstanding bounties and stalkers that need taken care of. The worst kind of scum and villainy usually end up on this list... For various reasons. The Zone needs its trash taken out from time to time. What do you say, stalker, will you be my hired gun?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_m_trader_task_2_finish">
		<text>Good, you got rid of that asshole! Here is what I promised.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ELIMINATE MUTANTS FOR WOLF TASK -->
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_wolf_task_1_name">
		<text>Clear area of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_wolf_task_1_text">
		<text>Wolf asked you to purge an area of all mutant threats in order to ensure the safety of rookie village; as well as the stalkers who pass through Cordon. Reach the location and eliminate all mutants around the area. Return to Wolf for payment after you job is complete.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_wolf_task_1_about">
		<text>Stalker, I need someone to who is a bit more experienced than the rookies for a task. Cordon is becoming a very dangerous place with all this rampant mutant breeding going on. I need you to hunt around an area that I will mark on your PDA. The job is to kill any mutants you see. If you do this for me, it will earn you some cash. So will you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_2_12_stalker_wolf_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thank you, the rookies will be much safer now because of you. Here is your payment.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 1 TOOLS FOR XENOTECH TASK -->
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_1_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_1_text">
		<text>%s are required by Xenotech to install basic equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_1_about">
		<text>I need a favour, man. A lot of stalkers come by here asking if I can tune their weapons a certain way but I can't. I just don't have the right tools. I would be able to perform upgrades on a greater variety of equipment if I can just get my hands on the right tools. Please, man, will you help me out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a set of basic tools. It should contain what I need. If you can bring some back for me I will be grateful, I will even offer you a discount from here on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Okay, yeah, this is exactly what I need. Here, I promised you payment; take it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 2 TOOLS FOR XENOTECH TASK -->
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_2_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_2_text">
		<text>%s are required by Xenotech to install advanced equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_2_about">
		<text>My business is booming now, more and more stalkers come to me when they need their weapon fine-tuned. But I could really use more tools. You brought me a quality toolkit last time but I need an even higher quality set. If you are interested, I will tell you what I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an %s. If you can bring one back for me I will be grateful, I will even pay you for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Yes, yes! Here is some cash, you deserve it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 3 TOOLS FOR XENOTECH TASK -->
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_3_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_3_text">
		<text>%s are required by Xenotech to install expert equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_3_about">
		<text>My business is booming now, more and more stalkers come to me when they need their weapon fine-tuned. But I could really use more tools. You brought me a quality toolkit last time but I need an even higher quality set. If you are interested, I will tell you what I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an %s. If you can bring one back for me I will be grateful, I will even pay you for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_smart_terrain_5_7_loner_mechanic_stalker_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Yes, yes! Here is some cash, you deserve it.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
