<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<!-- ELIMINATE MUTANTS FOR BEARD TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_1_name">
		<text>Clear area of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_1_text">
		<text>Mutants are about. Hunt them down and clear the area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_1_about">
		<text>Shh... Listen, hear that? Some mutants howling. Still gives me the chills after all this time. How about you go out there and take care of them? I'll make it worth your while.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_1_finish">
		<text>Haha! Well done stalker! Have a drink on Beard!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND ARTEFACT FOR BEARD TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the "%s" artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_2_text">
		<text>Beard wants you to find the "%s" artefact for him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_2_about">
		<text>I deal in artefacts. I usually don't buy them from stalkers, but there is one in particular I would like to get my hands on. Do you want to try to get it for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I'm looking for the %s artefact. You ever seen one? If you can find it I will pay you well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Good hunting stalker! Have a drink on the house!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR BEARD TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_3_name">
		<text>Diplomat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_3_text">
		<text>Convince the military commander to call off his search for a fellow stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_3_about">
		<text>You see that guy in the corner there? Spetsnaz is looking for him. He's been hiding out here for weeks. They say he ran through the Brain Scorcher to escape them. I don't know how he survived, though he ain't quite right in the head any-more. Anyway, you want to help the poor fellow? I happen to know where the military commander who wants him is stationed. Maybe you can convince him to leave the guy alone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_barmen_task_3_finish">
		<text>Ah, you killed him! Well, that's effective diplomacy! Good man! Free drinks for you!</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 1 TOOLKIT FOR CARDAN TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_text">
		<text>%s are required by Cardan to install basic equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_about">
		<text>Not only do I need some more booze I can really use a good set of tools, stalker. If you are interested in helping me out, I will tell you what I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a set of basic tools. It should contain what I need. If you can bring some back for me I will be grateful, I will even offer you a discount from here on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Great, stalker. You brought exactly what I've asked. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 2 TOOLKIT FOR CARDAN TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_2_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_2_text">
		<text>%s are required by Cardan to install advanced equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_2_about">
		<text>I could really use more tools and vodka. But the vodka is easy to find. What I need from you is more tools; better tools. Can you do this for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a set of advanced tools. It should contain what I need. If you can bring some back for me I will be grateful, I will even offer you a discount from here on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Fantastic! Feel free to stop by any time for a drink or if you need me to take a look at your gear.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 3 TOOLKIT FOR CARDAN TASK -->
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_3_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_3_text">
		<text>%s are required by Cardan to install expert equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_3_about">
		<text>I could really use more tools and vodka. But the vodka is easy to find. What I need from you is more tools; better tools. Can you do this for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a set of expert tools. It should contain what I need. If you can bring some back for me I will be grateful, I will even offer you a discount from here on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a2_stalker_mechanic_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Fantastic! Feel free to stop by any time for a drink or if you need me to take a look at your gear.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
