<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<!-- Jup A6 Yar -->
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_1_name">
		<text>Special delivery</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_1_text">
		<text>You need to deliver a message. How did you get caught up in the middle of this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_1_about">
		<text>Alright, I have a very simple job for you. I need you to deliver a message to my pal, Ashot. He needs his PDA fixed - tell him to bring it over here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_1_finish">
		<text>Haha, we were just playing a prank on you, stalker. I can't believe you put up with this shit for so long.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_task_1_dm_query">
		<text>I'm here to deliver a message</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ESCORT ECOGS TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_1_name">
		<text>Escort the Ecologists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_1_text">
		<text>Scientists have hired you to guide them to a specific location for study. Once their research has been successfully conducted, return them safely to camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_1_about">
		<text>We need an experienced stalker to lead a few of our the colleagues out into the field for study. Are you up for the task?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Thank you for your protection, stalker. Please, take this as a token of our gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND ARTEFACT FOR ECOGS TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_2_name">
		<text>Find the "%s" artefact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_2_text">
		<text>You have been asked to retrieve the %s artefact. Bring it back to Tukarev if you happen to get your hands on one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_2_about">
		<text>We are looking for certain kinds of artefacts. If you are interested, I will tell you what we need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need you to bring us back a %s. You ever heard of it? We have something we can give you in return that I think you will find useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Great! You've found exactly what we are looking for. Take this suit, it offers great protection against the Zone and I'm sure you can command a good price for it.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ELIMINATE MUTANTS FOR TRAPPER TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_1_name">
		<text>Clear area of mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_1_text">
		<text>Mutants have been spotted near this location making the area dangerous for some of the locals. You have been tasked to eliminate the mutant threat within the area. Report back to Trapper after the job is done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_1_about">
		<text>I've been looking for someone to help keep the area around Yanov a bit safer by depopulating the various mutant lairs found in area. Would you like the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_1_finish">
		<text>Thank you, stalker. The area will be much safer for others because of you. Here is your payment.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- ASSASSINATION FOR TRAPPER TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_2_name">
		<text>Assassinate target</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_2_text">
		<text>Trapper has a high value target that needs to be eliminated.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_2_about">
		<text>I have a dangerous threat that needs to be eliminated. Not a mutant this time, but a man. He will not be easy to get to but I promise to pay you well. Are you up for the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_2_finish">
		<text>Excellent work stalker. Here is your payment.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND WEAPON FOR TRAPPER TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_3_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_3_text">
		<text>Trapper is looking for a specific firearm in perfect condition. Return to him if you find one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_3_about">
		<text>One of my trappers is in the market for a specific firearm that I don't have available. Would you be able to track one down for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a %s. The trapper who wants it goes after dangerous game so he needs it to be in excellent condition. I can pay you well if you find one.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Ah, perfect. This will do nicely. Here is the money I promised you.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND MUTANT PARTS FOR TRAPPER TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_4_name">
		<text>Procure "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_4_text">
		<text>Trapper says he will pay well if I can bring him %s.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_4_about">
		<text>I have a bounty out on a particular type of mutant. Are you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_4_fetch_about">
		<text>Kill this mutant and bring me its %s and I will pay you well, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_task_4_fetch_finish">
		<text>Ah, another threat eliminated and a new decoration for the camp. Well done, stalker.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 1 TOOLKIT FOR NITRO TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_1_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_1_text">
		<text>%s are required by Nitro to install basic equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_1_about">
		<text>I need new tools, stalker, something that is hard to come by in the Zone. If you are interested in helping me out, I will tell you what I need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_1_fetch_about">
		<text>I need a set of basic tools. It should contain what I need. If you can bring some back for me I will be grateful, I will even offer you a discount from here on out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_1_fetch_finish">
		<text>Perfect! This is just what I need, stalker. If you need any of your equipment fine-tuned, now I can do it properly.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 2 TOOLKIT FOR NITRO TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_2_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_2_text">
		<text>%s are required by Nitro to install advanced equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_2_about">
		<text>The toolkit you brought me is great, but it doesn't have everything I need. Do you think you can find me a better set?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_2_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an %s. I'm not sure where you can get one of these, but if you can find one, I need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_2_fetch_finish">
		<text>Whoa! You found a nice set of tools for me. Here, I promised you some money in return.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- FIND LEVEL 3 TOOLKIT FOR NITRO TASK -->
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_3_name">
		<text>Find "%s"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_3_text">
		<text>%s are required by Nitro to install expert equipment upgrades, you should bring them back to him if you find any.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_3_about">
		<text>The toolkit you brought me is great, but it doesn't have everything I need. Do you think you can find me a better set?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_3_fetch_about">
		<text>I need an %s. I'm not sure where you can get one of these, but if you can find one, I need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_task_3_fetch_finish">
		<text>Whoa! You found a nice set of tools for me. Here, I promised you some money in return.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
