<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other">
		<text>Anomalies (Other)</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_emission">
		<text>Emission</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_emission_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Emissions%c[default], also known as %c[guide_blue]Blowouts%c[default], are sudden releases of massive amounts of radiation.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nStrong winds, storm clouds and a scarlet red sky all appear with the onset of an emission, followed by numerous eruptions of thunder and a deep rumbling underfoot.\n
			\nThese events begin with a sharp surge in radioactive, abnormal and psionic activity - and end with destroying most life in their wake as waves of radiation cover the Zone.\n
			\nDespite being extremely deadly, it is still quite easy to survive an emission by taking cover within buildings or underground tunnels until the event has run its course.\n
			\nMuch in the same way as a psi-storm, the massive amount of energy released by an emission appears to "recharge" many anomalies, allowing stalkers to farm new artefacts from them.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_phantom">
		<text>Phantom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_phantom_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Phantoms%c[default] are illusory beings that exist within the mind, rather than physically.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWhilst difficult to classify as either an anomaly or a mutant, a phantom is an involuntary mental projection of a mutant currently found somewhere within the Zone.\n
			\nThese projections are always accompanied by a audible "howling" noise and appear glowing and transparent, gradually floating toward the victim through walls and across the air.\n
			\nIt is unknown why they only take the form of mutants, including those of which a stalker has never encountered, and as to why they never take the appearance of those that are now extinct, such as the tark.\n
			\nA leading theory about this phenomenon suggests that the Zone's living mutants are in some way strongly connected to the noosphere, and that through this a psi-field unintentionally imprints their visual appearance and hostile nature into the minds of its victims.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_psistorm">
		<text>Psi-storm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_anomalies_other_psistorm_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Psi-storms%c[default] consist of multiple psi-vortices, which release lethal amounts of psionic energy.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nThese unusual weather anomalies are a very recent arrival to the Zone, and there is much speculation as to what causes their occurrence.\n
			\nBeginning with a purple/pink haze and large formations of storm clouds, it takes very little time for a psi-storm to form and start wreaking havoc upon the Zone.\n
			\nIf a stalker's equipment gives the wearer great protection against psionic damage, or makes use of drugs to provide a similar effect, it is possible to survival the discharge of individual psi-vortices during the storm without taking cover.\n
			\nThis is provided that they immediately medicate themselves afterwards, as even the most prepared stalkers will still find themselves in a very delicate situation after such exposure.\n
			\nSimilar to emissions, the massive amount of energy dispersed by a psi-storm appears to "recharge" many anomalies, allowing stalkers to farm new artefacts from them.
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>