<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_historic">
		<text>Mutants (Historic)</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_historic_rat_wolf">
		<text>Rat wolf</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_historic_rat_wolf_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Rat wolves%c[default] were a rare subspecies of mutated rats.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nMuch more dangerous than their existing cousins currently found in the Zone, the rat wolf was an indiscriminate killing machine.\n
			\nOften leading packs of regular rats, these creatures were easy to spot in comparison as they frequently grew to be about two or three times as large.\n
			\nAside from this there were only a few slight differences in their appearance, such as having larger and entirely black eyeballs, whilst their upper bodies were swollen and fat.\n
			\nNatural selection eventually played its part, as due to their unnatural size they often stood out and were easy pickings for the Zone's cats and other similar mutants.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Statistics%c[default]
			\n• Attacks: Melee\n• Health: Average\n• Speed: Average\n• Traits: None\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Trivia%c[default]
			\n• All that is known about this mutant is from game design documents.
			\n• This mutant was cut from S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Shadow of Chernobyl.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_historic_tark">
		<text>Tark</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_mutants_historic_tark_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Tarks%c[default] are extinct horse-like creatures, likely mutated from the Przewalski's horse.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nThis creature bore little resemblance to its ancestors due to massive exposure to radiation upon the Zone's inception.\n
			\nIts hind legs were atrophied whereas those at its anterior had become visibly exaggerated, whilst its tail and much of its mouth had all but decayed or disappeared.\n
			\nSimilar in ways to a flesh, the tark's body was greatly swollen and bloated, and were also frequently seen hunting in large groups - though probably as more of an instinctual relic than any natural form of a herd.\n
			\nUnlike other mutants in the Zone they were incredibly feral animals, with their madness often overwhelming their perception of fear and likely contributing to their eventual downfall.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Statistics%c[default]
			\n• Attacks: Melee\n• Health: Average\n• Speed: Fast\n• Traits: Frenzied\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Trivia%c[default]
			\n• All that is known about this mutant is from what accompanied its submission.
			\n• This mutant lost to the Snork in the Monster Ball competition by GSC Game World.
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>