<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>

	<string id="ls_header">
		<text>NIMBLE'S HANDBOOK</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_number">
		<text>Excerpt #</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_1">
		<text>Rank has eight different levels starting at 'Rookie' and finishing at 'Legend'. It can be increased through almost any in-game activity, and certain features may require reaching a high rank before they can be used.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_2">
		<text>Achievements can be unlocked through certain in-game accomplishments or by reaching statistical milestones. Every achievement is unlocked with an appropriate reward which can be viewed in the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_3">
		<text>Basic, advanced and expert tools are required by most mechanics in order to perform certain upgrades on weapons and outfits. Such items can often be found in stashes received as rewards for completing tasks.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_4">
		<text>Sleep deprivation is an optional feature where the passage of time and using consumables will gradually drain the player - eventually requiring them to rest when prompted. Failing to do so may have dire consequences.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_5">
		<text>Helicopter gunships can be seen patrolling many of the Zone's locations. When engaged in combat members of the helicopter's faction may often call on it for air support to help destroy attacking or defending forces.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_6">
		<text>Ironman mode gives a true sense of mortality. When the player is killed all saves for that specific character are deleted and can never be restored. Pick your faction and starting location wisely.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_7">
		<text>Gunsmith and sewing kits are used to repair your weapons and outfits respectively when out in the field. Each allows up to three uses and are best used to repair items of greater value than the kits themselves.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_8">
		<text>Backpacks can be bought or found and then used to create a custom stash. Stashes created by the player are never de-spawned nor are they ever looted by other stalkers. They are permanent until all items are removed.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_9">
		<text>Sleeping bags are a great way to rest in the Zone if you are unable to find a decent bed to sleep in. They can be purchased from most major traders or potentially found in another stalker's stash.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_10">
		<text>Truck Cemetery is a large graveyard of irradiated agricultural, civilian and military vehicles. As a great place to hide a stash, an eagle-eyed stalker may find many valuables among the wreckage.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_11">
		<text>Artefact types are indicative of the anomalies they are found in. Want one that boosts your burn resistance? Search for a 'Burner' or 'Comet' anomaly and go hunting with your detector.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_12">
		<text>Completing tasks for factions will increase your goodwill with them. As it increases their traders will gradually offer you greater discounts on their goods and services.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_13">
		<text>As you achieve more in-game your rank will increase, the available ranks are as follows: 'Rookie', 'Trainee', 'Experienced', 'Professional', 'Veteran', 'Expert', 'Master' and 'Legend'.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_14">
		<text>Most tasks can be cancelled after you agree to complete them. You can do this by speaking with the stalker who gave you the task. Just remember that cancelling a task will decrease your reputation and goodwill.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_15">
		<text>Reputation is a representation of how a stalker is viewed by their faction. It is gained and lost by helping or harming non-hostile stalkers respectively.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_16">
		<text>Reputation is dynamic and can frequently change, the available reputations are as follows: 'Terrible', 'Dreary', 'Awful', 'Bad', 'Neutral', 'Good', 'Great', 'Brilliant' and 'Excellent'.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_17">
		<text>Darkscape is a large forest between Cordon and Dark Valley. While there are few reasons to visit, it is frequently used as a hideout by loners and bandits with a bounty placed on their heads.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_18">
		<text>Remember to ask regular stalkers if they have any jobs available. Just because they aren't anybody important doesn't mean they won't be willing to pay you to do their dirty work.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_19">
		<text>Rostok's arena hosts two types of competitions: the traditional fights where stalkers battle each other for cash rewards, or challenges where they attempt to kill increasingly harder mutants.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_20">
		<text>Online exclusion radius can be set via the game options and defaults to 25m. It creates a no-spawn area around the player preventing mutants and other stalkers spawning unfairly and dangerously close.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_21">
		<text>Freedom completely occupies Yanov Station in Jupiter after a mysterious stalker assisted them several years ago. Some of their well-known members have since relocated to their new northern base.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_22">
		<text>The 'Completionist' achievement is received for unlocking all other available achievements. How many achievements are available to you depends on your faction and whether or not story mode is enabled.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_23">
		<text>It is much easier to avoid detection when travelling during the night or through heavy rain. However, you risk encountering fierce nocturnal mutants.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="ls_tip_24">
		<text>You won't be able to issue orders to companions if you leave them behind. Companions in Wait or Patrol modes will not travel with you to new map locations.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
