<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay">
		<text>Options (Gameplay)</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_ai_die_to_anomalies">
		<text>AI die to anomalies</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_ai_die_to_anomalies_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]AI die to anomalies%c[default] removes anomalies as a factor in the AI's pathfinding.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWith this feature enabled mutants and other stalkers will lose their clairvoyant ability to know exactly where anomalies are located.\n
			\nAs such, they will now find themselves placed at the full mercy of the Zone's environment no different from your own character.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_aoe_pickup_mode">
		<text>AoE pickup mode</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_aoe_pickup_mode_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Area-of-effect pickup mode%c[default] enables picking up of multiple items at once.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWhen enabled, this feature allows you to pick up multiple items and put them in your inventory with a single key-press, just as you could in S.T.A.L.K.E.R.: Call of Pripyat.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_artefact_degradation">
		<text>Artefact degradation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_artefact_degradation_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Artefact degradation%c[default] causes artefact abilities and bonuses to degrade when activated.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWith this feature enabled having the best artefacts is no-longer the end of the line for artefact hunters.\n
			\nArtefacts will become weaker the more they are used, promoting their further hunting and accumulation, instead of becoming just a quick source of income.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is enabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_delayed_repairs">
		<text>Delayed repairs</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_delayed_repairs_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Delayed repairs%c[default] allows technicians to retain your equipment.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWith this feature enabled, broken weapons, outfits, and other items which you bring to a technician will be kept in their possession until they have completed all repairs.\n
			\nAfter handing over your items you can speak with the technician again to ask whether they are ready for pick-up, to which they will either return them or tell you how much time is still required.\n
			\nThis adds a somewhat realistic enhancement to the traditional repair system, suitable if you are seeking a harder experience, as it will no-longer work instantaneously and instead emphasise the use of gunsmith and sewing kits.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_difficulty">
		<text>Difficulty</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_difficulty_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Difficulty%c[default] establishes how easy or hard the game should be to play.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nAs of update 1.5 the difficulty settings have been completely revamped and replaced, as confusing names and uncertainty as to what they did have convinced many players that they were fundamentally broken.\n
			\nGameplay is balanced with the "Normal" difficulty in mind, which is the recommended selection if you are attempting to learn (or re-learn) how to play the game successfully.\n
			\nOther options also exist with two giving you the choice between making the game either easier or harder, and a third which turns everything up to the maximum and makes the Zone feel truly unforgiving.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Highlights%c[default]
			\n• Ballistics mean your choice of ammunition and weapon is crucial to survival.
			\n• Bleeding isn't trivial and requires more attention than before.
			\n• Higher difficulties are genuinely challenging and require skill.
			\n• Lower difficulties aren't tedious and now do what they were supposed to.
			\n• Mutant encounters might be something you choose to run from.
			\n• Obtaining high-end equipment won't make you feel invulnerable.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_enhanced_recoil">
		<text>Enhanced recoil</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_enhanced_recoil_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Enhanced recoil%c[default] adds much more varied and realistic handling of weapons.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nNormally when firing your weapon the only effect that the built-in recoil system provides is that it gradually raises your reticle, animates your weapon, and slightly increases the spread of your bullets.\n
			\nBecause of this the normal system is somewhat flawed as by firing in short bursts and slowly moving your mouse downward at the same time, you can almost completely negate a weapon's recoil with little practise.\n
			\nWith this feature enabled a much more randomised and multi-directional recoil is created when firing your weapon - this restores the challenge of mastering your weapon and makes your choice of upgrades and ammunition much more influential.\n
			\nIt is highly recommended to only enable this feature if your system can maintain at least a steady thirty frames-per-second, although fifty or above is much more preferable.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_hardcore_ai_aim">
		<text>Hardcore AI aim</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_hardcore_ai_aim_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Hardcore AI aim%c[default] increases AI aim predictability and decreases reaction times.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWith this feature enabled it becomes harder for you to avoid being hit whilst strafing and sprinting, with the use of cover becoming much more essential to your long-term survival.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_helicopter_patrols">
		<text>Helicopter patrols</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_helicopter_patrols_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Helicopter patrols%c[default] enables factions the use of air support to defend strategic areas.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nFactions who have friendly aircraft patrolling in the area will be able to call on them for support in attacking, or defending from, enemy stalkers (including you) and mutants.\n
			\nDespite their intimidating appearance they can be easily taken down after receiving a light amount of damage to the tail rotor.\n
			\nIf the sound of rotor blades become an annoyance but you don't wish to turn off the feature, they can be turned off independently.\n
			\nThese features can be toggled from the game options menu and are enabled by default.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Locations%c[default]
			\n• Agroprom\n• Cordon\n• Darkscape\n• Great Swamp\n• Limansk
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_localisation">
		<text>Localisation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_localisation_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Localisation%c[default] allows you to set the language in which you play the game.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nUpon changing your localisation the majority of texts will update automatically, however some will still require a game restart to be changed.\n
			\nThis feature can be adjusted from the game options menu and is set to "eng" by default.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Supported languages%c[default]
			\n• English: eng\n• Russian: rus
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_online_exclusion">
		<text>Online exclusion</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_online_exclusion_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Online exclusion%c[default] creates a no-spawn zone around your character.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nAs you explore near the edges of levels and their entry/exit points you could be attacked by enemies arriving from other levels. With online exclusion enabled these spawns are delayed until you are safely out of the way.\n
			\nIt should be noted that this system revolves entirely around you; any enemies already at a location whilst you are changing levels will not be de-spawned upon your arrival.\n
			\nThis feature can be adjusted from the game options menu and is set to 25 by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_population_factors">
		<text>Population factors</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_population_factors_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Population factors%c[default] modify the number of stalkers and mutants found in the Zone.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nStalker and mutant population factors can be adjusted independently from one another, allowing you to decide how wild or settled the Zone should be without the need to modify any of the game's files.\n
			\nIt should be noted that the effect is greatest when starting a new character, as if the factors are changed during a playthrough in progress, they will only be realised as stalkers and/or mutants die and then respawn in greater or smaller numbers.\n
			\nThese features can be adjusted from the game options menu and are set to 0.5 by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_quicksave_count">
		<text>Quicksave count</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_quicksave_count_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Quicksave count%c[default] allows the game to cycle between multiple quicksaves.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nWhen making a quicksave the filename will be appended with a number on the end - these numbers are used by the game to help with tracking of multiple different quicksaves.\n
			\nBy allowing you to make multiple different quicksaves before they start being replaced, you will be able to revert to previous progress if you accidentally save at a bad moment.\n
			\nIn short: the higher the value you give to this setting the more quicksaves you will allow the game to cycle through.\n
			\nThis feature can be adjusted from the game options menu and is set to 5 by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_radio_music">
		<text>Radio music</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_radio_music_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Radio music%c[default] allows for custom music tracks to be played at certain locations.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nCertain relaxed areas within the Zone have radios installed nearby, with each playing a selection of musical tracks to keep stalkers entertained.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is enabled by default.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Locations%c[default]
			\n• Agroprom: Military base\n• Cordon: Sidorovich's bunker\n• Great Swamp: Clear Sky base\n• Dark Valley: Bandit base\n• Rostok: 100 Rads\n• Red Forest: Forester's tower
		</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_sleep_deprivation">
		<text>Sleep deprivation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="encyclopedia_options_gameplay_sleep_deprivation_text">
		<text>
			%c[guide_blue]Sleep deprivation%c[default] allows time and the use of consumables to fatigue your character.\n
			\n%c[guide_green]Information%c[default]
			\nThroughout the Zone you will find many beds and sleeping bags, normally they are only used to allow you to skip time by sleeping, however with this feature enabled they become an essential part of gameplay.\n
			\nAs time passes your character will slowly begin to feel tired, with the screen beginning to blur and shake. These effects will proceed to get worse until you find a suitable place to rest or the effects of sleep deprivation cause you to collapse from exhaustion.\n
			\nTiredness can be accelerated through consuming items such as medical kits and vodka, and negated with those such as high-caffeine energy drinks - however using too many will leave you unable to rest until their effects wear off.\n
			\nThis feature can be toggled from the game options menu and is disabled by default.
		</text>
	</string>
	
</string_table>