<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_11">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_111">
		<text>I have to speak to Jack. It's about Vano's debt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_1111">
		<text>Go on, then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_11111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_112">
		<text>I'm just taking a walk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_guard_dialog_1121">
		<text>This ain't a public park, buddy. Take a hike.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_0">
		<text>Do you know who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_1">
		<text>No, but I have my own shit to worry about... You lost some material things but I could lose my life...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_about_stolen_items_2">
		<text>Theft, deception... Man, what is the world coming to? I didn't see anyone, but whoever did it is long gone, I'm sure of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_0">
		<text>Let's go see Zulu.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_1">
		<text>Of course. We should pay a visit to Hawaiian on the way to buy my suit back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_11">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_goto_zulus_2">
		<text>I'd be happy to, but I don't feel like being caught by an emission with my pants down. Let's wait a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_need_outfit_0">
		<text>We'll need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to get to Pripyat. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_need_outfit_1">
		<text>Man, that sucks! My suit has one - you can stick your head into an oven and breathe just fine, but I pawned it at Hawaiian's. If only we could get it back - I'm broke and we'll need 5 grand...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_0">
		<text>I could give you money for the suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_1">
		<text>Just like that? Are you serious?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_11">
		<text>Here, take your 5 grand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_111">
		<text>You're really saving my ass here, friend. I'll follow you wherever now!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_12">
		<text>I'd give you the money but I don't have 5 grand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_121">
		<text>It happens to the best of us, friend... Believe me, I know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_13">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_131">
		<text>Of course... It's your money, after all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_outfit_money_yes_2">
		<text>So, will you give it to me or what?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>I'm putting a team together to go to Pripyat. Wanna join me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>You helped me, friend, so I'll help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>I'd love to, man, but I can't leave here while I've got this debt hanging over me.  That wouldn't be right, and besides if we ran into them on the way they'd shoot me down like a dog. Those bastards don't care who they kill...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_ready_0">
		<text>So, are you ready to head to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_ready_1">
		<text>I'm like more than ready and stuff!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_11">
		<text>Well, come in. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_12">
		<text>You've paid the debt, now get outta here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_1_0">
		<text>They were arrogant bastards - I had to take them out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_2_0">
		<text>I paid the money, so you're not in debt anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_2_1">
		<text>Wow, thanks man! I won't forget this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_3_0">
		<text>Not great, they made me pay interest, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_3_1">
		<text>That's not good... But they'd charge me even more, believe me. Thanks for your help! I won't forget this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_4_0">
		<text>I haven't been to see them yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_4_1">
		<text>Hurry up before they make you pay more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_5_0">
		<text>I went to see them but they're demanding interest on the debt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_5_1">
		<text>What are they, crazy? I barely put that much together... Do you think you can convince them to forget the interest? You'll need a good weapon - force is the only thing they respect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_0">
		<text>What did you say about your debt?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1">
		<text>Well... I had an old suit that was starting to wear out, so I figured I need a new one. Soon as I thought that, I saw a brand spanking new suit for sale... It had a closed-cycle respiratory module and everything... I counted my money this way and that but came up short every time... Then Jack, the seller, said to me, "Don't worry Vano, you can pay me the rest later." I was like, "What a nice guy!" and all that...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11">
		<text>OK, and?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111">
		<text>I sold my old suit, got all my cash and brought it to him. Jack was like, "Well done, Vano, but what about the interest?" I thought, "Yeah, he's right... I need to get the interest to him..." I put together some more cash and took it to him. When I got there he said, "While you were out, more interest built up, Vano." Seems the interest grows so fast I can't catch up... I had to pawn the new suit and my weapons, too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111">
		<text>So, what now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11111">
		<text>I want to pay him the money I've earned. There's nothing more important than Vano's reputation... But I'm scared. Could you go see Jack instead of me to pay my debt?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111111">
		<text>OK, I will.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111111">
		<text>The only thing is, when you go see him make sure to whip out a powerful gun or something. Show them you're not one to mess with and they'll give you some respect...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_11111111">
		<text>I'll work it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111112">
		<text>I'm too busy right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1112">
		<text>I've had enough.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_2">
		<text>So, can you go see Jack instead of me to pay my debt?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_11">
		<text>OK, OK, don't shoot, I'll pay the debt... Err, sorry, I thought you were someone else...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_12">
		<text>How did it go with the bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_13">
		<text>Hey man, it's good that you came!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_14">
		<text>Hey.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_11">
		<text>We have visitors... A stalker to see Shishak for a word... You come carrying gifts or you got business to discuss? Either way, spit it out, buddy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_12">
		<text>I didn't think you'd be back... So, what do you have for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_dialog_13">
		<text>What else is there to discuss, stalker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_0">
		<text>What do you want? You tired of dragging your loot around or something? We can help you with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_1">
		<text>I need to talk to your boss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_11">
		<text>Hey buddy, I ain't got time for this shit. Get outta my face, pronto! Do it now or I'll help you on your way with this here shotgun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_111">
		<text>OK, OK - I'm leaving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_2">
		<text>I'm here about the captive stalker - I want to see your chief.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_21">
		<text>Hrm... Go on then, but you keep it clean and tidy or we'll put you in the ground in no time... Keep going straight and then through the passage in between the containers. Got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_211">
		<text>Yep.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_3">
		<text>I was just passing by, I'll disappear now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_start_4">
		<text>I'm here about the captive stalker - I want to see your chief.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_visited_0">
		<text>What else do you want? Screw off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_guard_visited_1">
		<text>OK...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_0">
		<text>Lookit, sucker, you tryin' to insult me or somethin'? You brought enough dough for your punk ass friend, but you ain't paid us for safe passage! That's poor thinking on your part, ya feel me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_1">
		<text>How much are we talking about? I've gotta get to the base though, so keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_11">
		<text>Oh, you really are a funny guy! This ain't no whorehouse, buddy, we ain't got no friggin' price list... Empty your pockets, bitch!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_111">
		<text>OK, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_11111">
		<text>OK, I'm going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_112">
		<text>What?! You want to take all my loot? No way!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_2">
		<text>I paid the ransom. There's nothing else to discuss.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_11">
		<text>OK, stalker, we've earned our fee now. Time to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_111">
		<text>Thanks, guys. See you next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_112">
		<text>Wait. There could be more bandits hiding in cover.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_12">
		<text>OK, time to go. The kid didn't make it, but we've done the best we could...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_13">
		<text>Wait, we ain't done yet!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_merc_done_dialog_131">
		<text>Got ya!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_actor_dialog_0">
		<text>Come to Pripyat with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_actor_dialog_1">
		<text>I'd best stay here for now and make sure that Mitay stays out of trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_11">
		<text>Hey, stalker! Thanks a bunch for getting Mitay out! We were already starting to put a squad together... Here, take this as a token of our gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_12">
		<text>Hey, stalker! Thanks a bunch for getting Mitay out! You're a beast, taking all those bandits on by yourself... Here, take this as a token of our gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_13">
		<text>Hey, stalker! Thanks for helping get Mitay out! Personally, I didn't think that paying the ransom would work out too good... I'm sure you could use a little cash, so take this. You have our gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_14">
		<text>Hey, stalker! Thanks for helping get Mitay out! I was right about the whole thing. You can never give in to bandits! You gotta put some heat on them... And you got the balls for it too. Here, take this - everyone got a piece so it ain't much, but we are truly grateful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_15">
		<text>So, how did it go with the ransom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_151">
		<text>Still working on it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_16">
		<text>So, what's up? When are you gonna put some heat on the bandits?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_161">
		<text>Soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_17">
		<text>Did you change your mind or are you having trouble with the bandits?... Oh well, do what you need to do but do it fast - we don't want them losing patience and wasting Mitay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_171">
		<text>I'll work it out. It'll be all right.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_18">
		<text>I'm glad to see a pro like you, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_19">
		<text>Man, that was a good guy we lost there... Poor Mitay... We couldn't save him - good friends we are!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_assaulter_after_scene_dialog_191">
		<text>What can you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_actor_dialog_0">
		<text>Come to Pripyat with me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_actor_dialog_1">
		<text>I only came to this place to keep my friends company, so I'll stay here with them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_11">
		<text>Hey, thanks for Mitay... We were just about to head over there with the ransom money. Things worked out real good, that's for sure...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_12">
		<text>Hey, thanks for Mitay... How did you manage to convince them? Man, I've got a lot to learn from you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_13">
		<text>Hey, thanks for Mitay... I was right, wasn't I? Negotiation is the key to success!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_14">
		<text>Hey, thanks for Mitay... I still think it's better to negotiate, but things worked out all right in the end, so it's all good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_15">
		<text>Back off - I don't feel like talking to you right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_151">
		<text>OK, take it easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_16">
		<text>Hello, Mr. Pro!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_17">
		<text>Poor Mitay... He was just a kid... He had his whole life in front of him...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_diplomat_after_scene_dialog_171">
		<text>What can you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_0">
		<text>Great, we're all here. Grizzly told me about you... The plan is simple: the boys get in position to attack around the perimeter and I pick off the sentry from my position - that's the signal to begin the assault... Take note of our positions and do whatever you feel is best. I'm sure you've got your own idea of what to do... Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_1">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_give_art_dialog_2">
		<text>Wait, let me think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_0">
		<text>You feel like taking a trip to Pripyat with me, Mitay?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_0">
		<text>The scientists are looking to hire some people, how do you feel about working for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_1">
		<text>What's the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_11">
		<text>Guarding their bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_111">
		<text>Nah man, my bandit adventure was enough. I'll just sit tight right here and take it easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_12">
		<text>Taking measurements in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_employ_stalkers_121">
		<text>Hrm... That's interesting. I've worked for the scientists before and since it's you asking - sure, I'll do it. Me, Grizzly and Torba will head for the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_0">
		<text>Tell me how you got captured.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_1">
		<text>Man, don't ask! It was my own fault. The bandits warned me about it but you know... They started demanding a share of my loot, but the Zone don't belong to nobody, so why should I pay them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_111">
		<text>Me and the boys told them where to shove it and it seemed like we got away with it. But the bandits turned out to be pretty crafty - they set up an ambush. So, when I was stupid enough to go looking for artifacts on my own they jumped out behind me and tied my hands together before I could even get my shooter out... So that's how it was.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_11">
		<text>Thanks for paying the ransom for me! I won't forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_12">
		<text>Thanks for freeing me, stalker! I won't forget it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_13">
		<text>Thanks for helping to pay the ransom for me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_14">
		<text>Thanks for helping to free me, stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_15">
		<text>Thanks for helping, stalker... My friends will definitely reward you when we get back... Let's go to the base together, it'll be quicker that way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_151">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_dialog_152">
		<text>You go, I'll drop by later. I've got some business to finish up here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_11">
		<text>Man, I thought I was gonna die here... Wow, did Grizzly and Torba hire all these people?! Holy cow! I ain't seen a shootout like that in my life! Can we get out of here now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_111">
		<text>Wait a minute, there could be more bandits around here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_112">
		<text>Yes. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_12">
		<text>Man, I thought this was gonna be the end of me... Wow, you took on all these bandits on your own! You da man! They won't believe me when I tell this story... Can we get out of here now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_121">
		<text>Wait a minute, there could be someone left around here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_hide_until_walk_out_dialog_122">
		<text>Yes. Let's get out of here right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_11">
		<text>Thank you, stalker! Let's move before the bandits change their mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_111">
		<text>Let's move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_thank_bandits_base_dialog_21">
		<text>We gotta get out here, fast!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_dialog_0">
		<text>We can't give in to the bandits' demands. This problem calls for a forceful solution.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_dialog_1">
		<text>Exactly! I know a few fellas who'd be happy to help out... We'll pay you too if you don't mind going in as a team.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm ready to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_1">
		<text>Great! I know a group of stalkers who used to serve in a special police unit. You'll have to meet them at an agreed location after 1AM - they'll be waiting for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_power_take_dialog_11">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_dialog_0">
		<text>Torba's right. There's no point starting a bloodbath while they've got a hostage. We must negotiate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_dialog_1">
		<text>Hrm, you two might be right... Only thing is, if me and Torba go, the bandits won't want to let us out, seeing as we refused to follow their rules. They said they'd bury us alive next time they see us. Now, if you could act as a negotiator...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_0">
		<text>Sure, I'll do it. Give me the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_1">
		<text>Be careful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_ransom_take_dialog_11">
		<text>It's gonna be fine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_0">
		<text>We can argue till the cows come home... Our success depends on whoever drives this thing. I'll deal with the bastards myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_1">
		<text>Man, I didn't expect that... Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_self_dialog_11">
		<text>I'll be back soon.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_actor_wait_dialog_0">
		<text>I agree, but I need some time to prepare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_11">
		<text>Stalker, help get our buddy Mitay out of trouble, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_111">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_1111">
		<text>Mitay is in real trouble... The bandits have started putting their foot down and demanding a cut of the artifacts stalkers find. We told them to take a hike, 'cause we figured stalkers don't owe nobody shit, and that seemed to be the end of it... But they ambushed the poor bastard when he went hunting for loot on his own and now they're demanding a ransom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_11111">
		<text>What are you going to do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_111111">
		<text>Torba is suggesting giving them an artifact as ransom... I reckon we shouldn't give them shit. If we do, that means stalkers are working for the bandits... We should sell the artifact, hire us a solid crew and attack the bandit base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_112">
		<text>Let's deal with this a bit later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_12">
		<text>So, will you help us save Mitay? Torba still reckons we should give them an artifact as ransom. And I'm still insisting that we gotta attack the bandit base. We'd have to sell the artifact and hire some fighters to do that... We still haven't decided what to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_13">
		<text>You ready? We'll give you the artifact to buy Mitay out with and we'll wait for you at the bar.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_15">
		<text>You paid the bandits a visit yet?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_151">
		<text>Not yet, I'm still getting ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_152">
		<text>Yeah, but it hasn't come to much yet. I'll let you know when things become clearer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_barmen_oasis_art_sell_0">
		<text>I was at the Oasis recently and I found an artifact there. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_barmen_oasis_art_sell_1">
		<text>Hah, you don't expect me to believe that, do you? I've heard a lot about the Oasis but I've NEVER heard of anyone who has actually been there. No offense, but I won't be taking your word for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_0">
		<text>I have documents from the Jupiter plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_11">
		<text>Yeah, take them all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_12">
		<text>Yeah, take the evacuation order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_13">
		<text>Yeah, take the meeting minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_14">
		<text>Yeah, take the delivery schedule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_15">
		<text>Yeah, take the note from the repair workshop.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_16">
		<text>Maybe next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
		<text>Who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
		<text>Not my men, that's for sure. Could be someone from Freedom. If we had full control of Yanov things like that would never happen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_0">
		<text>Tell me about Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1">
		<text>What exactly do you wanna know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1111">
		<text>What is it that you do here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11111">
		<text>Same thing we always do. Protecting stalkers from all kinds of vermin. You've seen how many mutants there are around here and these ain't the cute little puppies you get at the Cordon. For instance, I saw a chimera with my own eyes last night. It was getting dark, so we didn't chase it... Mutants ain't the only problem around here, either. We've also got to investigate and collect evidence from the abandoned laboratories before those Freedom morons get to them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1112">
		<text>What brought you to the center of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11121">
		<text>Are you kidding me? And what brought you here? I'm gonna venture a wild guess and say we're here for the same reason. The center of the Zone has always been an unreachable objective, a place where we were hoping to get answers to all our questions. We wanted to find out how the Zone was created and how it can be destroyed. That's why as soon as we heard the rumor that the Brain Scorcher had been disabled, we made a move for the center.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_111211">
		<text>And what did you find out?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1112111">
		<text>Plenty, but that's confidential. All I can say is that there is more to the Zone that meets the eye. Some of our people believe that the Zone is a tumor that must be removed at any cost. Given what I've seen, I'm more inclined to believe that the Zone is a living organism and we are nothing more than bacteria that live inside. Even if we combined the military might of every country on the planet, we still couldn't destroy the Zone. That's why we have to be smarter than that: we have to find the reason for the Zone's existence and eliminate it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11121111">
		<text>What if you can't eliminate that reason?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_111211111">
		<text>Well, if we can't then we'll have to think of something else, but there's still hope. We must do our duty and stay positive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1113">
		<text>How did you end up in Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11131">
		<text>That's a boring story and there's no heroism involved. As soon as the Zone appeared, Lenya, a friend of mine, decided to come here and check it out. I was a field officer at the time and Lenya was in the intelligence service. Now, we weren't suckers or anything, but we ended up in a real mess. We crawled for hours, wounded and bleeding, until finally Duty picked us up. I made it, Lenya didn't. I had no friends in the Zone, so I decided to stick around here, with Duty. Plus, I've had a thing against the Zone ever since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1114">
		<text>What's your relationship with Freedom like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11141">
		<text>Officially we're at war, but life in the center of the Zone has its own set of rules. There are few safe places here and neither Freedom nor Duty boast a lot of manpower. So what's the point of killing each other? That's why the unspoken rule is that we stay out of each other's way. This rule doesn't apply outside Yanov though: out there we're still at war and it's for real, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_1115">
		<text>OK, forget about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_about_you_11151">
		<text>Oh... OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_0">
		<text>I wanted to talk about a member of Freedom called Flint.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1">
		<text>I don't care about Freedom people as long as they stay away from us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11">
		<text>Flint, also known as Magpie, set up stalker hunters at Zaton, took all their loot and made off with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_111">
		<text>So? That doesn't surprise me, 'cause Freedom is full of scum like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1111">
		<text>There's something else: I met a stalker at the quarry. Before he died, he told me that Flint left him in an anomaly, took the loot and left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11111">
		<text>Ah, see, that kind of shit stalkers don't forget... even in Freedom. Thanks for that information - we'll make sure it's put to good use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1112">
		<text>I've got enough dirt on him. I mean, the jackass actually has the nerve to openly boast about doing things that I did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11121">
		<text>That'll deal a heavy blow to Freedom's reputation. Thanks for the information. We'll make sure it's put to good use.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_13">
		<text>Never mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_131">
		<text>OK, it's your choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_0">
		<text>I have the PDA of your supply officer, Morgan.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_11">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_12">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_21">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_2111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_3">
		<text>Let's have a look... So that bastard was doing business on the side and using our name as cover... If this comes out, our reputation will go straight down the toilet. How about I buy this PDA from you? I'll give you a good price. Will 4,000 do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_1">
		<text>That's a serious allegation. Show me the PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_11">
		<text>Here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_111">
		<text>It's fair to say I had my own suspicions about him... Now we'll address them fully. Thank you, stalker! I hope nobody ever finds out about this conversation. I have a modest reward for you - you saved Duty's reputation, after all...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_12">
		<text>I'll hold on to it for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_2">
		<text>Another one... Very interesting... I'll add it to the case file.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_21">
		<text>Here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_211">
		<text>Thanks! Here's modest compensation for your efforts...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_22">
		<text>Let me hold on to it as a keepsake.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
		<text>I met a group of fighters that want to join Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
		<text>We're always looking for good men. They should pay me a visit and we'll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
		<text>There's one thing though... They're former Monolith fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
		<text>What do you mean "former" Monolith fighters? In my experience Monolith fighters fit into two categories: current and dead. I've never met any "former" ones.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
		<text>It looks like they were under someone’s control - because they don’t remember what happened to them after they left for the CNPP. Now they’re not aggressive at all and they simply don't know what to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
		<text>Well, if they’re not aggressive that's a good thing... I mean, I’d find them something that's easy as pie to do and I’d make sure they’ve got their heads straight, too. I’m just not 100% sure about them at the moment... Can you vouch for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111111">
		<text>Yes. I trust them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111111">
		<text>Hrm... Trouble is, I can’t trust you either... yet. Sorry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111112">
		<text>OK, but remember that if they screw up, you'll answer for it. The fact is they won't make it to Yanov on their own. What you're gonna do is take my boys and lead them to the Monolith squad. They'll talk to them and if everything is cool, they'll be accepted into Duty. Tell me when you're ready to head out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111112">
		<text>No. I don’t trust them much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_3">
		<text>We don't accept just anybody into our faction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_0">
		<text>I'm ready to lead your people to the Monolith squad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_1">
		<text>Good. I'll send two people with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_11">
		<text>Good.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_12">
		<text>Let's do it later, something's come up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_2">
		<text>Hold it! You do what you want, but I won't let my boys out to get hit by an emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_0">
		<text>I found the Duty founder's PDA. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_1">
		<text>Let's have a look... So that's how it went down... I don't think the others need to know this. It would be better if nobody ever sees this PDA again. Let the legend of Duty's creation stay as it is. Will you sell me this PDA?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_11">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_111">
		<text>Thanks. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_pda_12">
		<text>I'll consider your offer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_sell_pda_0">
		<text>Take the Duty founder's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_duty_founder_sell_pda_1">
		<text>Thank you! You have done me a big favor. Here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_0">
		<text>I need fighters to work for the scientists. Can you help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_1">
		<text>We're always happy to help the scientists. What needs doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_11">
		<text>They're looking for people to protect their bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_111">
		<text>Of course, I'll send some of my boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_121">
		<text>Of course, I'll send some of my boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_2">
		<text>I'd be happy to, but they're already employing Freedom. Sending our squad there would only intensify what is a pretty heated situation already.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>I'm planning to make for Pripyat. Will you give me a few fighters for this mission?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>We're short on manpower as it is! Talk to Strider - he doesn't feel at home in Duty by the looks of things, so maybe he'll find what he's looking for with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>We're short on manpower as it is! I'm not sending anyone on a hopeless mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Talk quickly, leave even quicker. What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_12">
		<text>I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Glad to see you alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_0">
		<text>I have documents from the Jupiter plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_1">
		<text>I doubt there's anything interesting there. The plant was looted even before the stalkers got there. Although... hrm, there's some decent info here. I'd like to show these to someone. Sell them to me, would you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_11">
		<text>Yeah, take them all.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_12">
		<text>Yeah, take the evacuation order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_13">
		<text>Yeah, take the meeting minutes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_14">
		<text>Yeah, take the delivery schedule.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_15">
		<text>Yeah, take the note from the repair workshop.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_a9_sell_info_16">
		<text>Maybe next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
		<text>Who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
		<text>I ain't a guard and it ain't my job to watch your box! My boys didn't take it for sure - they know better than that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_0">
		<text>Tell me about Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1">
		<text>It's a long story. What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1111">
		<text>What is it that you do here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11111">
		<text>We're making sure that various officials don't conceal anything from the common folk. You know how it is: as soon as they find a new lab or some documents that shed light on the secrets of the Zone, they immediately organize a military operation and clean everything up better than a friggin' hoover. The only way of finding shit out is by getting there first.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1112">
		<text>What brought you to the center of the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11121">
		<text>Well, the boys felt like taking a stroll in a new place. Just kidding. It's an opportunity to find stuff that the world ain't seen before. Neither the army nor stalkers have been here before, so there's something new everywhere you look.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_111211">
		<text>Did you find anything?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1112111">
		<text>A couple of locked doors and some weird new artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1113">
		<text>How did you end up in Freedom?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11131">
		<text>Well, I was friends with Freedom leaders back when there was no Zone. Mind you, in those days they weren't leaders, they were regular hippies. So when I made a move into the Zone in search of artifacts and ran into familiar faces, I figured I might as well go with what I know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1114">
		<text>What do you think about Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11141">
		<text>They're idiots, that's what I think. I mean, why the hell would they want to destroy the Zone? It's not consuming precious resources or getting bigger... or anything. They could just sit there and study it to their heart's content - just think of how many scientific discoveries could be made... I mean, in the history of man-kind, no one has never been able to understand antigravitation, right? And in the Zone you've got ready-made antigravitation devices lying all over the place. It wouldn't hurt to kick their asses out of here, but it's too much hassle. By the way, don't be confused by our relations here at Yanov. We are at war... it's just that Yanov has been made neutral territory, if you know what I mean.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_1115">
		<text>OK, forget about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_about_you_11151">
		<text>No problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_0">
		<text>I wanted to talk to you about one of your stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1">
		<text>Really? Go ahead. I hope you're not here to snitch on someone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11">
		<text>Your stalker Flint is known at Zaton by the name of Magpie. Local stalker hunters are looking for him because he set them up and ran off with their loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_111">
		<text>And you expect me to believe you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1111">
		<text>Just listen to the stories he tells at the bar. First he swindled those stalkers and now he's lying to you lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11111">
		<text>OK, chill. I'll contact Beard and see what's what. If what you say checks out, we'll deal with Flint Freedom-style.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_11121">
		<text>Hrm... I was wondering how he managed to get that artifact so quickly. I guess half of his story was complete bullshit. I'll speak to my boys. If what you said checks out, we'll deal with him Freedom-style.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_13">
		<text>Never mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_131">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_11">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_12">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_21">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_2111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
		<text>I met a group of fighters that want to join Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
		<text>Well, we’re always open to good people. They’re welcome to join if they’re up for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
		<text>There’s a small problem - they’re former Monolith fighters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
		<text>A "small" problem? I prefer to see Monolith fighters through my scope. Anything else is out of the question.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
		<text>These ones are peaceful. It looks like they were under someone’s control - because they don’t remember what happened to them after they left for the CNPP. They simply don't know what to do now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
		<text>Sorry, but I'm still skeptical. What if you're lying to me on purpose?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11112">
		<text>Well, maybe it wouldn't hurt to talk to them and find out what's what. I’ll send a couple of my boys with you. They’ll have a chat and we’ll accept your Monolith fighters into Freedom if it works out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_3">
		<text>How about you piss off? I can't believe you're suggesting that we accept all kinds of scum into Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_0">
		<text>I'm here about accepting that Monolith squad into Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_1">
		<text>My men are ready to go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_11">
		<text>OK, have them follow me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_12">
		<text>A bit later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_redy_to_go_2">
		<text>Let's wait a bit. Emissions ain't healthy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_0">
		<text>I found the Duty founder's PDA. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_1">
		<text>Well, as long as it's got something useful on it... Wow, that's real interesting. They keep spreading their bullshit propaganda throughout the Zone, but as it turns out their own history is full of crap. I'd love to give this a thorough read. Listen, I'll pay you well for this PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_11">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_111">
		<text>Thanks. Here's your cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_founder_pda_12">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_sell_founder_pda_0">
		<text>Take the Duty founder's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_duty_sell_founder_pda_1">
		<text>Thanks. Here's your cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_0">
		<text>The scientists are looking to recruit some people. Can you send anyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_1">
		<text>Well, it depends on the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_11">
		<text>The scientists need their bunker protected.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_111">
		<text>Of course, I'll send some of my boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_121">
		<text>Of course, I'll send some of my boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_2">
		<text>I'd be happy to help, but Duty is already there. We spend enough time together with those bastards at Yanov, so we'll pass, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>Will you give me a squad to go to Pripyat with?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>Talk to our new recruit, Strider. He ain't happy here, so maybe you can give him what he wants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>If I had anyone to spare I probably would, but I don't - sorry. We've got enough on our plate here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_11">
		<text>So, what have you got to say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_12">
		<text>What's your business here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_start_dialog_13">
		<text>Good to see you, man! I've heard some good things about you in Freedom. What can I do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_jup_b1_0">
		<text>I found a strange item in the railroad tunnel. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_jup_b1_1">
		<text>Hrm, nah. It's junk. It looks like an artifact but it ain't got any effects. We normally give that kind of crap to the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_0">
		<text>I found a strange item at Zaton, you interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1">
		<text>What am I supposed to do with it? I'm not even that interested in normal artifacts, so you know... Show it to the scientists - they pay well for all kinds of junk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_guards_0">
		<text>I'm looking for people to guard the scientists' bunker. You know anyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_guards_1">
		<text>You won't find anyone better than Freedom. You could also try to work something out with stalkers, but they're not exactly trustworthy. If they let you down, how are you gonna be able to find them later? I definitely wouldn't suggest you speak to Duty about it. Those fanatics are only good for purging mutants and that's it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_helpers_0">
		<text>I'm looking for people to collect samples for the scientists. You know anyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_about_sci_helpers_1">
		<text>Of course.  Go see Loki - he'll be glad to help you with that. You could also try to work something out with stalkers, but some of them ain't too trustworthy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b202_about_stole_0">
		<text>Someone stole things from my box. Do you know who it might have been?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b202_about_stole_1">
		<text>What is this place coming to, man? I doubt it was anyone from Duty 'cause they've got strict discipline in their faction, too strict for my liking. Nobody in Freedom needs your junk, so it's gotta be one of the stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
		<text>I met a Monolith squad recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
		<text>Wow, I've never seen any! Though I did hear some real bone-chilling stories from the boys. Something about the Monolith people being complete lunatics. Must have been a hard fight, eh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
		<text>There was no fight. They're peaceful fellas. They told me it was like a veil lifted from their eyes and they regained control of themselves. They simply don't know what to do now, so I'm looking to get them into a faction or something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
		<text>Wow, that's an interesting one. Well, stalkers aren't an option 'cause they'd probably shoot them down in view of their past encounters and all that... Try talking to Loki. Nobody will touch them if they put on Freedom uniforms.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_duty_founder_pda_0">
		<text>Who could be interested in the truth about the founder of Duty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_duty_founder_pda_1">
		<text>I really don't know. It seriously depends on how different this truth is from the official Duty line. Show it to Loki, he'll tell you straight.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_jup_b217_pda_sell_0">
		<text>I have the PDA of Duty's supply officer. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_jup_b217_pda_sell_1">
		<text>Not in a million years. I know where to buy everything he sells a lot cheaper. There's nothing else there that could interest me either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>Who could go to Pripyat with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>Pripyat? Wow! Well, I'd love to just drop everything and take off, but I'm real busy right now...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>Pripyat? Wow! You should ask Loki for some people. I reckon he won't turn a good man like you down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_12">
		<text>You come to chill? My drinks ain't nothing special but this is a welcoming and friendly place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_13">
		<text>I got all the shit you're ever gonna need. What are you after? You fancy some chow, a drink or feel like firing off a few rounds?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_guards_0">
		<text>I'm looking for people to guard the scientists' bunker. Can you suggest anyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_guards_1">
		<text>Talk to the stalkers. I'm guessing they would be happy to do some work for the eggheads... After all, that would give them an official permit to be in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_helpers_0">
		<text>I'm looking for people to collect samples for the scientists. Can you suggest anyone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_about_sci_helpers_1">
		<text>I suggest that you don't get involved with inexperienced stalkers. They won't find anything and they might even lose something if you know what I mean.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
		<text>I met a Monolith squad recently and I wanted to ask you something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
		<text>You know, every other person that's come across Monolith fighters I've met usually had a few extra holes in them and no pulse. You, on the other hand, look quite alive, so what is it you wanted to ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11">
		<text>This squad isn't like that. I talked to them, I didn't have to fight them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_111">
		<text>No way!?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1111">
		<text>Yes way. They told me it was like a veil was lifted from their eyes and they don't know what to do now. They asked me for advice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_11111">
		<text>Well, my advice is that they stay well away from stalkers, 'cause they've got too good a memory to let them live. I suppose you could try helping them join a faction, but I don't know whether Duty or Freedom would want to get involved in this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_duty_founder_pda_0">
		<text>I have a PDA with the truth about the founder of Duty on it. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_duty_founder_pda_1">
		<text>I don't do gossip, remember that. If you want to sell information, Owl is the one to see. He loves that kind of shit. Then again, given the nature of your info, Loki or Shulga might be interested in it too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_jup_b217_pda_sell_0">
		<text>I've got the PDA of Duty's supply officer. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_jup_b217_pda_sell_1">
		<text>I have a feeling that this PDA would mean problems with Duty and I don't need that. Try talking to Owl instead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_1">
		<text>Let's have a look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_111">
		<text>That's better.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>Who could go to Pripyat with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>Talk to Vano, a stalker. He's straight as an arrow, to the point that it gets him into all kinds of trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>There ain't that many crazy folk around here, buddy, so you'll have to look elsewhere.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_start_dialog_0">
		<text>You looking for medical supplies or just here for a chat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
		<text>Someone stole things from my box. Do you know who it might have been?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_12">
		<text>Do you know that stalker's name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_121">
		<text>I heard he's fairly new here... What's his friggin' name... Is it Snob? Snack... No, no. Something kinda dead... Snag, that's it! His name is Snag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11">
		<text>Wassup, bro'?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_111">
		<text>Hey. I've got important business to discuss with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1111">
		<text>Cool, let's have a drink first to make sure we take this important business as seriously as we should!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11111">
		<text>OK, let's drink!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_11112">
		<text>Nah, I don't feel like drinking right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_12">
		<text>So, what's this business you mentioned?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_121">
		<text>I'm planning to go to Pripyat via the underground passage that goes under the Jupiter plant. Nitro can get the entrance open.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1211">
		<text>Hrm... Going to Pripyat underground... That's an idea... And that calls for another drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_12111">
		<text>Cheers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13">
		<text>Ehh, this is good stuff. I hope you're not planning on tackling this mission on your own? No... That won't do... I'll go with you... and we're gonna need others, too. A couple of trustworthy people are always useful in this kind of thing...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_131">
		<text>Nitro advised me to get a squad together...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1311">
		<text>Yeah, that's a good idea... Let's have another drink to the success of this mission...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13111">
		<text>Bottoms up!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_132">
		<text>I can do it on my own, you know... I mean, at Zaton I took out a bloodsucker lair on my own... A couple of gas tanks and it's party time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1321">
		<text>Wow, respect man. Let's drink to always having a gas tank to hand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13211">
		<text>Amen!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_133">
		<text>Trustworthy, huh? Well, this place is full of scum... I met a trader at Zaton but it turned out he was from Duty...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1331">
		<text>Wow, so Duty's rotting from within, huh... What's the world coming to? Oh well, let's stop worrying about it and have a drink.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_13311">
		<text>I yield to your wisdom. Cheers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14">
		<text>Mmm... nice, ain't it? A squad is a good idea, we need at least three people... You got anyone in mind?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_141">
		<text>I'll find some folks... We're also gonna need suits with closed-cycle respiratory modules...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1411">
		<text>Yeah, safety first and all that... About that: don't worry about me 'cause my suit is all good, but we will need them for the others and it may take a little work - those suits aren't exactly common around here. Here's to a successful search.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14111">
		<text>Cheers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_142">
		<text>You know this weird fella called Noah? He locked himself in on a barge with all kinds of goodies... His version of hello is unloading  both barrels of his shotgun on you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1421">
		<text>Yeah, I haven't seen him for a while. He and I worked together a while back. He was a good fighter... too bad he's gone off the deep end like that. Let's drink to him and his mental health!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14211">
		<text>To Noah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_143">
		<text>I met Vano at Yanov some time back and he couldn't seem to pay off his debt to the bandits... Anyway, I helped the poor bastard out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1431">
		<text>Cool, the trip is sure to be more fun with him around, plus he can carry all the supplies. To Vano!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14311">
		<text>You can say that again, brother!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_144">
		<text>There's a military guy in the scientists' bunker... He hasn't got anything to do, so he might agree...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1441">
		<text>Yeah, we could use an army type... Let's drink to the hope that he joins us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14411">
		<text>Let's.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_145">
		<text>You won't believe it but I helped a Monolith squad the other day... Suddenly the loose screws in their heads tightened up or something and they didn't know what to do... So I helped them out and they're chilling at Yanov now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1451">
		<text>Hrm... Looks like this vodka went straight to your head, hah! Oh well, can't have too much of a good thing!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_14511">
		<text>True.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15">
		<text>OK, well that seems to be it - the main thing is to make sure we don't get lost underground...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_151">
		<text>Don't worry - I've got the schematics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1511">
		<text>Cool. Let's drink another to the success of our mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15111">
		<text>I'll drink to that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_152">
		<text>Ah, relax man... I found the Oasis the other day... That same one nobody else could get to...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_1521">
		<text>Wow, you're a real pathfinder, man. We'll find the way to Pripyat in no time with you around. Cheers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_15211">
		<text>Cheers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_21">
		<text>Howdy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_0">
		<text>I think we've got enough people. We can move out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_1">
		<text>You sure? Another pair of hands wouldn't hurt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_11">
		<text>I'm sure. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_12">
		<text>You're right. I'll try to find some more people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_2">
		<text>Good. Let's roll, folks!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_21">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_3">
		<text>Fighters are good but have you made sure to protect yourself? You need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module before we go... I ain't dragging your dead ass anywhere - my beast of a cannon and ammo is heavy enough for me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_31">
		<text>Yeah, I got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_go_to_pripyat_4">
		<text>Let's wait this one out. Emissions ain't too healthy!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_0">
		<text>Where can I find fighters to join our squad?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_1">
		<text>Ask the folk around Jupiter... The guys who stayed at Zaton won't go to Pripyat for sure. We need fellas that ain't got nothing holding them back... They've got to be willing to join what is basically a desperate mission. Do you remember meeting anyone like that? Maybe someone owes you or you know someone who ain't settled down...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_fighters_2">
		<text>We've got enough people now. There's no need to put a division together... We'll use small squad tactics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_about_0">
		<text>What do you think about Strider?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_about_1">
		<text>Monolith people are usually fanatical, fierce fighters... I'm not sure about former members though. Strider looks calm on the outside, but appearances can be deceiving.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_11">
		<text>Wow! Monolith armor. Where the hell did you get that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_111">
		<text>It was part of a set. This is Strider, a former Monolith fighter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_monolith_start_1111">
		<text>I didn't realize there were "former" Monolith fighters. Oh well, we'll see what he's like when the real shit starts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_about_0">
		<text>What are your thoughts on Sokolov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_11">
		<text>That fella's got an interesting suit on him, scientific and all. I haven't seen one like that for a couple of years, at least.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_111">
		<text>That's Sokolov, the co-pilot of the military chopper that crashed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_start_1111">
		<text>Well, I can see he ain't no scientist by the way he carries himself. A good soldier will always come in handy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_about_0">
		<text>How long have you known Vano?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_about_1">
		<text>We met at 100 Rads a couple of times. They say he's honest, optimistic and a good stalker... But he's way too gullible and that's a fatal flaw in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_stalker_start_11">
		<text>So Vano's along for the ride, eh? Great, we've got ourselves someone to carry all our supplies... Hah, relax man - I'm just kidding.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
		<text>Who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
		<text>Your things were stolen? That sucks. I don't know what to say. I haven't seen anything suspicious around here... If I find something out, I'll let you know for sure. We don't need no rats at our base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_testimony_0">
		<text>I heard there was some shooting around here recently...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_tech_b202_about_testimony_1">
		<text>Ah, that was me. Some idiots decided to get together by the tower... They had an argument or something, started shouting and shit. I fired off a couple MG rounds and they bolted towards the substation. That was it for the moron convention, hehe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_0">
		<text>I've decided to hand over the Oasis artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_1">
		<text>A wise decision - please pass it to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_11">
		<text>Here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_111">
		<text>Splendid, this miracle must be studied immediately... Oh, by the way, thank you for your services - here is your fee. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_0">
		<text>Do you need help with something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1">
		<text>Thank you - we already have a stalker squad working for us. Although... there is a theory, in fact it's more of a legend... Have you ever heard of the Oasis?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1111">
		<text>I'll try to find the Oasis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1112">
		<text>Sorry, I have too much on my plate at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_12">
		<text>No, I haven't heard of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_121">
		<text>Then listen. Many people talk about it but it seems that nobody has ever seen it. It's like healing waters. If you walk in, your wounds heal and your energy is replenished. There are many rumors making the rounds, one more incredible than the next... Some claim to have seen it in their dreams... but as a scientist I am obliged to ask, "How do you know it really was the Oasis?" If you agree to look for it... Well, I can't promise you a massive fee, but if the Oasis exists, its discovery would help us make a giant stride in our research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_0">
		<text>I found the Oasis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1">
		<text>Really?! It exists, then?! Please don't consider me a skeptic, but did you bring something back as proof?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11">
		<text>Yes, I found something that looks like an artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111">
		<text>Pass it to me, quickly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1111">
		<text>Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11111">
		<text>Splendid, this miracle must be studied immediately... Oh, by the way, thank you for your services - here is your fee. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1112">
		<text>I don't think so. It might be of use to me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_11121">
		<text>That is extremely selfish of you. Not to mention dangerous. The exact properties of this artifact are unknown. What are you going to do tomorrow if you find your legs are paralyzed? Or your skin is turning green? I assure you that such objects are best handled by scientists - at the very least we strive to protect ourselves from them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111211">
		<text>Your scare tactics won't work on me. I'm keeping the artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_111212">
		<text>OK, fine. Take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_12">
		<text>No, I didn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_121">
		<text>You didn't? So what do you expect me to study? Do you know what makes scientists different from others? The fact that for us any theory must be supported by facts! I need proof!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1211">
		<text>OK, I'll go back there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_1212">
		<text>I've spent too much time on it as it is. I can't go back now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_proof_12121">
		<text>If you don't care about your fee then think about new medical opportunities the Oasis would open up! If I am not mistaken, the Oasis is anomalous in nature... that's the way of things in the Zone. If that is so, it's the first ever anomaly with healing properties!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_11">
		<text>What brings you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_12">
		<text>Did you see the mercenaries who were guarding us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_13">
		<text>It's wonderful to see another intelligent person. How can I help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_start_14">
		<text>Can you believe it? The mercenaries who were guarding us were killed right outside our bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_0">
		<text>Hermann, do you know anything about the Oasis?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_1">
		<text>The Oasis? Hah. It's a lie, pure and simple. People like to believe in a cure-all panacea, so they make up these fairytales. Believe me, the Oasis is nothing more than a figment of someone's inflamed imagination.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_11">
		<text>Many people talk about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_111">
		<text>Too many. But none of them have ever been there. I stick to the scientific point of view: what hasn't been proven to exist, doesn't.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_nuclear_physicist_oasis_legend_12">
		<text>OK, I see... Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_0">
		<text>OK. Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_1">
		<text>Cool... We'll be back before you can say "bloodsucker" - hah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_11">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_agreed_2">
		<text>Cool... But let's wait for the emission to finish and then we'll go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_11">
		<text>Good day to you, stalker. I'm Uncle Yar... I guess you're tired from the road, eh... Have a bite to eat, since you're here. You chose a good time to show up, too - I need some help. At my age there are things I can't do on my own. Back in the day, though...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_12">
		<text>So, feeling fresh? You feel like a walk now? You'd help an old man out...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_start_13">
		<text>How's life? You look better by the day...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_where_to_0">
		<text>What's the job?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_where_to_1">
		<text>Easy as pie... The two of us make our way over to Kopachy - it's not far from here. The rest you'll see for yourself when we get there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_why_me_0">
		<text>Won't your Freedom friends help you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_base_why_me_1">
		<text>I don't want to bother them with this stuff... The two of us can handle it, no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_come_with_me_0">
		<text>Will you go to Pripyat with me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_come_with_me_1">
		<text>Nah... If I was younger... I remember I used to walk to Siberia and back, but I try to keep my trips short these days... Getting old, I suppose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_0">
		<text>Take care.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_1">
		<text>Wait. If you're going to Yanov, maybe we could go together? Having someone to talk to is always nice...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_11">
		<text>Thanks, I'd prefer to go on my own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_bye_12">
		<text>Let's go to Yanov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_start_11">
		<text>Thanks for helping an old man out... Take this. If you have any questions - ask away. I'll answer as best I can...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_me_0">
		<text>Why didn't you ask Freedom members for help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_me_1">
		<text>What's the point of getting the mercs angry with Freedom? We had one war and that was enough. This is a personal matter... No point involving them, you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_mercs_0">
		<text>What happened here anyway?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_done_why_mercs_1">
		<text>Some lads came here to kill me... You see, I was hiding in the bushes minding my own business when a mercenary squad showed up. Their leader was yapping away on his PDA about a central lab in Pripyat, an urgent order, this and that... Then I stepped on a stupid branch and alerted them to the fact that I was there. So I grabbed my rifle and made a run for it, but I always had the feeling that they'd come for me. That's the price we pay for eavesdropping nowadays.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_prepare_start_11">
		<text>The main thing is don't be surprised at anything. Follow me quietly... If we keep it hush hush and don't move, things will be nice and easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_prepare_start_111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_st_go_to_exit_0">
		<text>We need to get out of here. We'll talk later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_st_go_to_exit_1">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_1_come_with_me_0">
		<text>I'm putting a squad together to go to Pripyat with. Wanna join me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_1_come_with_me_1">
		<text>Tempting... but no, thanks. The scientists promised me a permit to be in the Zone and they pay well, too. Sorry, but I'm going to stay here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_0">
		<text>Ready to take measurements in anomalies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_1">
		<text>We're always ready, as long as you cover us. Which anomaly shall we go for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_11">
		<text>Let's go to Fen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_12">
		<text>Let's go past Kopachy village to the Ash Heap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_13">
		<text>Wait, I've changed my mind about going now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2">
		<text>We're ready all right, but we should probably wait for the emission to pass...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_21">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_0">
		<text>Measurements taken, let's move.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_1">
		<text>I don't like hanging around here either. Where to next?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_11">
		<text>Let's go to Fen.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_12">
		<text>Let's go past Kopachy village to the Ash Heap.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_13">
		<text>To the scientists' bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_2_14">
		<text>Wait, let me think.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_0">
		<text>You ready to head back to the bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_1">
		<text>We're more than ready...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_11">
		<text>Well, let's go then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_about_scrutiny_3_12">
		<text>OK, just wait a sec for me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_0">
		<text>I have a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1">
		<text>Ask them and I'll do my best to answer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1110">
		<text>I think that's it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111">
		<text>I want to ask about the scientists' mission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11111">
		<text>Ah, the tunnel... There's something there, a strange artifact or something like that. That place is just too weird. At first it was really calm and then I could feel something in my head... It was also crawling with hamsters but don't worry about them - we'll deal with them easy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111111">
		<text>You've been there before?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111111">
		<text>Yes. We didn't go far in - we were taking some measurements for Hermann when the hamsters came out in force. When we got back, the scientists got so excited about the results that I thought they were gonna take off. They wanted us to search the whole tunnel from end to end, but I ain't going in there! Now they've hired you and we're only there to provide cover.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111112">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112">
		<text>Well, we've taken measurements before, so we'll manage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111121">
		<text>Where did you take measurements before?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1111211">
		<text>Well, measurements is a big word for a small job. We only did it once for real - the anomalous psyfield in that friggin' tunnel. Even that time, as soon as we turned the devices on, the hamsters started flooding out of every hole - Mace barely made it out with his bits in one piece.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112111">
		<text>Don't you think that's strange? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111121111">
		<text>No, why would I? The Zone doesn't like nosy people, so that's normal. That's what Ozersky told me, and it checks out. Ask him if you want, maybe he knows something but ain't sharing it with the rest of us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11112112">
		<text>I understand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111122">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112">
		<text>What can you tell me about the people who live in the bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11121">
		<text>Well, it's some group, I'll tell you... Two scientists, Hermann, the top dog around here, and Ozersky. They employ Novikov who handles the technical stuff and Garry is their guide. Then there's us - they recruited us recently to take measurements and do other science stuff. Oh, Garry also brought some army dude into the bunker the other day. That's about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111211">
		<text>Can you tell me more about Hermann?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112111">
		<text>Hermann is the boss around here - he's a professor from some institute, probably a secret one... He organized the expedition, so they dropped this bunker in here almost immediately after the Brain Scorcher was disabled. He was also the one to recruit Garry and us - he pays well and even promised us an official permit for entry into the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11121111">
		<text>Let's talk about something else.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111212">
		<text>Can you tell me more about Ozersky?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112121">
		<text>He's a good, friendly fella and he's the number two around here. Hermann does listen to his advice now and again, though. I don't know much more about him - Hermann is the one we deal with most of the time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111213">
		<text>Can you tell me about Novikov?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112131">
		<text>He's like Einstein on vacation, man. He knows exactly what he's doing when it comes to installing technical things; in fact, he's better than just about anyone you'll meet. I don't know how he ended up here but you can tell he's no stranger to the Zone - he knows more about it than we do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111214">
		<text>Can you tell me about Garry?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112141">
		<text>Garry is a great guy and he was one of the first to show up here. He told me the scientists were being dropped off just as he got here, so he joined them right then. He's been getting bored lately, 'cause he ain't one to sit around, but he can't leave before his contract with the scientists is complete. If you want to know something else, ask him yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111215">
		<text>Tell me about the army guy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112151">
		<text>Hah. Garry met him as he was running away from zombies. He was lucky it was Garry, too, 'cause most others would have taken him out for sure. He doesn't leave the bunker much anymore and I don't blame him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111216">
		<text>What are the mercs doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1112161">
		<text>Those friggin' cutthroats are guarding the bunker. They showed up some time ago, had a chat with Hermann and stayed. I suppose Hermann ain't too pleased with them either... Their leader is called Black and he's got a personality to match.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116">
		<text>What can you tell me about this area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_11161">
		<text>Well, there is an old military base not far from here... Then Kopachy village to the north of it, and a train station to the east of that, which is where stalkers hang out. Oh, there's also a train on the railroad nearby... That’s not a fun place, believe you me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111611">
		<text>Tell me about the old military base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116111">
		<text>Well, there's not much to say... Anything of value got looted a long time ago, so there's not a lot there now except mutants and zombies. There's also a small bunker there - enough to take cover from an emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111612">
		<text>Tell me about the village.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116121">
		<text>Well, it's not much of a village - just a few mounds, really. It was buried back in 86 to prevent it from emitting radiation. People don't go there 'cause it's not a healthy place and there ain't nothing of value there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111613">
		<text>Tell me about the train station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_111614">
		<text>Can you tell me anything about the train?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_116131">
		<text>Well... Yanov station is worth a visit if you've haven't been there before. It's a good place to grab a cold one and catch up with other stalkers, plus it's the only other safe place besides our bunker in these parts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_squad_thanks_0">
		<text>I see you're sporting new equipment?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_squad_thanks_1">
		<text>Yeah baby. We're now officially known as Iskra scientific research & investigation team! Don't be thinking that we forgot all about you now that we're scientists, haha! My "colleagues" and I have discussed this matter in great depth and our conclusion is... That you've earned this, buddy! If you find yourself in an anomaly or hit by an emission, God forbid, take a moment to send us a thank you note. We'll receive the message, trust me!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_11">
		<text>Hey.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_12">
		<text>Howdy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_13">
		<text>So you ready to move or shall we wait a bit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_14">
		<text>I thought I'd be left to rot in that tunnel as a brainless zombie! How can I help the man who saved me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_15">
		<text>Feel like stretching those legs a bit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_16">
		<text>Hey brother.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_17">
		<text>We owe you and I won't forget that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_18">
		<text>I have a feeling we're done here and it's time to get the hell away from this place...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_0">
		<text>So, what's the story with this tunnel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_1">
		<text>There's no dust there, not a single little bit of it. Hermann says it's because of the Tesla, but I have a hard time believing that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_2_2">
		<text>Ask the boss, I don't know what I can tell you and what I should keep quiet about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_0">
		<text>Tell me what you found while you were measuring the psyfield.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_1">
		<text>I saw footprints on the ground. They looked like they were human, but who would be crazy enough to walk barefoot in that place?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_3_2">
		<text>You mind kinda goes fuzzy and everything you look at starts assuming these weird shapes. It's that friggin' psyfield, you know what I mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_0">
		<text>So what did you find underground?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_1">
		<text>Not much, just a couple of dead hamsters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_ab_tu_4_2">
		<text>Heh... nothing you can't find everywhere else in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_1_0">
		<text>Are you OK?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_1_1">
		<text>I'm all right, thanks to you! I'll give you a set of coordinates, as a token of my gratitude. Anything you find there is yours to keep - it's not much, but comes from the heart...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_2_0">
		<text>How do you feel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_2_1">
		<text>Man, thanks a lot! Thanks to you... I'm lost for words. Take these coordinates of our stash - a token of our gratitude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_3_0">
		<text>You alive?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_3_1">
		<text>Thanks, I won't forget this. Here, take the coordinates of our stash - you deserve them...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_4_0">
		<text>Your brain still working?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_4_1">
		<text>Man, the shit I saw when I was... That's gonna stay with me for life...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_0">
		<text>So, back to the bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_1">
		<text>You betcha!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_11">
		<text>Let's go, then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_after_end_go_home_12">
		<text>You go ahead, I'll see you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_0">
		<text>Is your squad ready to head for the tunnel?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1">
		<text>Just say when.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_11">
		<text>When. Let's move out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_12">
		<text>Wait a bit longer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_13">
		<text>I'll go on my own. See you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_14">
		<text>I'll go on my own. See you there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_141">
		<text>No, we don't trust you and time is money, so either you go with us or we stay right here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1411">
		<text>In that case, let's go together now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_1412">
		<text>In that case, you'll have to wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_go_to_2">
		<text>No way... No point risking it during an emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_0">
		<text>So, here we are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_1">
		<text>So... let's start?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_11">
		<text>Yes, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalkers_about_tunnel_dialog_start_miss_12">
		<text>Give me a second to get my bearings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11">
		<text>What the hell do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_111">
		<text>I was just passing by.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_1111">
		<text>Well, keep walking then.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_11112">
		<text>Relax, moron.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_bandit_meet_actor_112">
		<text>None of your business!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_11">
		<text>Oh... Hi...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_111">
		<text>Nimble told me that you're a deceitful bastard. I figure you've cheated many a stalker...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1111">
		<text>What are you talking about? I've never done anything like that in my life! Nimble's messed up in the head!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_112">
		<text>What did you tell the bandits about me? Why were they waiting for me by the dock cranes?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1121">
		<text>You must've taken me for someone else - I have no business with bandits!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_113">
		<text>Nimble told me about you... I suggest you give me the shooter and make it easy for both of us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_1131">
		<text>What could he tell you?! I don't have anything that ain't mine!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_11312">
		<text>Take a hike, buddy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21">
		<text>Help me out, bro - I need a medkit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_211">
		<text>Tell me where you hid my stuff first!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_2111">
		<text>I'm sorry man, I really needed the money... I'll tell you everything, just help me! Honestly, I'm done with that shit, I've gone straight!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21111">
		<text>OK, here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_211111">
		<text>Thanks, man! I hid the stuff in my stash in the sewers behind the substation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_2111111">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_21112">
		<text>I don't believe you. You ain't getting a medkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_212">
		<text>Take this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_213">
		<text>You ain't getting it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_31">
		<text>Thanks. I didn't think you'd help me...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_0">
		<text>Who could I hire to protect the scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_1">
		<text>Duty, of course. Who else? They're the best fighters in the Zone, after all! Heavy assault guards - how does that sound?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_guards_2">
		<text>They're employing Freedom at the moment? In that case, I really don't know. I was going to suggest Duty, but they don't go well together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_0">
		<text>Who could I hire to take measurements for the scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_1">
		<text>Try talking to Shulga. They're not all rocket scientists over there, but he's got some bright fellas in his employ.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_sci_helpers_2">
		<text>Are they still paying Freedom to protect them? If so, I would advise against recruiting Duty... That's about all the advice I can give you on that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_underpass_0">
		<text>When we got into the underpass the elevator stopped working...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_about_underpass_1">
		<text>Hah, you went down using the only operational generator... And it's the backup one at that. I barely got it working, so it did its job done and then died. You should be grateful it didn't go out halfway... That elevator doesn't have an emergency exit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b202_about_stole_0">
		<text>Who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
		<text>Damn! I really don't know. What I can tell you is that if Shulga was running things at Yanov, that would never have happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b33_open_package_dialog_0">
		<text>Can you break into a steel container?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b33_open_package_dialog_1">
		<text>I'm not the guy, man. Metal ain't my thing... If you have any electronic issues - give me a shout.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_0">
		<text>A group of peaceful Monolith fighters is looking for refuge. Who could help them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1">
		<text>Are you serious? I heard they're animals... Well, stalkers won't give them the time of day, that's for sure... You should probably speak to Shulga. If the Lieutenant Colonel lets them join Duty, they'll be safe. They might even find something useful to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_0">
		<text>Can you decrypt a black box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_1">
		<text>Let's have a look... This is gonna be some work. It'll take about three hours and it won't be cheap. I'll do the work and then we'll talk... go take a walk while I do this, so I can concentrate...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_2">
		<text>Let's have a look... This is gonna be some work. It'll take about three hours and it won't be cheap. I'll do the work and then we'll talk... Meanwhile why don't you look for the components I need? You'll earn some cash and I'll charge you less for this job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_11">
		<text>What? I'm still working on it. Damn, this box is a friggin' nightmare...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12">
		<text>I'm done with your black box... A shitty job if I've ever done one...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121">
		<text>What do I owe you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1210">
		<text>3,000, at least.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12101">
		<text>Take this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12102">
		<text>I don't have that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121021">
		<text>Well, I can give you a discount when you bring me the components.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_121022">
		<text>Well, don't be a stranger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_12103">
		<text>Too rich for my blood... I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1211">
		<text>I'll give you a discount. Only 2,850.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1212">
		<text>I'll give you a discount. Only 2,700.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1213">
		<text>I'll give you a discount. Only 2,550.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1214">
		<text>I'll give you a discount. Only 2,400.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1215">
		<text>I'll give you a discount. Only 2,250.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1216">
		<text>I'll give you a big discount. Only 2,100.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1217">
		<text>I'll give you a big discount. Only 1,950.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1218">
		<text>I'll give you a big discount. Only 1,800.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_1219">
		<text>I'll give you the very best price for this. Only 1,650.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_13">
		<text>Heh, obviously I don't know why you need the recording, but for what it cost you I sure hope it's gonna be useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_131">
		<text>We'll see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_blackbox_start_14">
		<text>I'm still working on the black box... Why don't you make yourself useful and get me those components?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_drunk_1">
		<text>Senka? Back when I was making my way through Zaton he stuck with me and he's been with me since... He's a professional drunk with extensive experience... hah! I use him to run errands here and there...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_duty_founder_pda_0">
		<text>Who might be interested in information about Duty's founder?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_duty_founder_pda_1">
		<text>Shulga, of course... Duty remembers its beginnings. You know what they say: unless you study history, it will repeat itself... The main thing is that Freedom doesn't get its hands on this information, because they'd distort it, that's for sure. Not out of any malice, simply due to poor memory...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_0">
		<text>I brought you tools.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_1">
		<text>Great... So, which ones are for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_11">
		<text>The ones for basic work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_111">
		<text>Great! Now I just need tools for fine work and calibration...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_12">
		<text>The ones for fine work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_121">
		<text>Great! Now I just need tools for basic work and calibration...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_13">
		<text>The ones for calibration.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_131">
		<text>Great! Now I just need tools for basic work and also ones for finer work...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_14">
		<text>None, for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_141">
		<text>Cool! Some calibration tools and I'm all set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_151">
		<text>Cool! Some tools for fine work and I'm all set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_161">
		<text>Cool! Some tools for basic work and I'm all set.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_171">
		<text>Wow! Where the hell did you find them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_0">
		<text>If you need any tools, I can get them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_1">
		<text>That would be awesome. At the moment, it's like working in the Stone Age. The only difference is that the soldering iron has replaced the shaman's staff... If I had tools, I could do some top upgrades and you better believe there'd be coin in it for you too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_11">
		<text>OK. I'll look for them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_12">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_instruments_work_3">
		<text>Good idea. I can do upgrades and you can earn cash...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_jup_b207_pda_sell_0">
		<text>I have the Duty trader's PDA. You know anyone who would be interested in it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_jup_b207_pda_sell_1">
		<text>A trader in Duty? No kidding... Give the PDA to Shulga and he'll deal with it. Not a word to Freedom, you get me? They'll use one asshole to sabotage the reputation of the whole faction...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_0">
		<text>I found some documents. They describe a way of getting to Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_1">
		<text>Let's have a look... Yeah, yeah, yeah... So, to summarize, there's an underground underpass designated Pripyat 1, which runs under the city of Pripyat, with one section that ends in a lock located in the Jupiter plant's transportation section. Impressive! Judging by the notes it has been sealed, filled with gas and the power to it has been cut. I suppose I could try to revive the generator and open the lock. Only...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_3">
		<text>...Only I ain't going through Jupiter without protection, and I suggest that you don't even think about going underground on your own. You'll need to have a couple of buddies with you, at least. You're all going to need suits with closed-cycle respiratory modules, too, otherwise you won't last a minute down there... Listen, Zulu lives in a tower not far from here - try talking to him. If you guys hit it off, he'll tell you how to put a squad together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_about_0">
		<text>You mentioned materials...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_about_1">
		<text>Right, finding materials to use for working with radio equipment is damn near impossible around here. I've used everything I could find and there's nobody supplying any materials here, because you can make more cash selling guns... I heard there could be something left at the cement factory, though...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_all_0">
		<text>I found the materials, here you go. I searched the cement factory from top to bottom!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_all_1">
		<text>Wow, bro - I'm impressed! I'll make a note right here: free labor on all repairs and upgrades for my favorite stalker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_some_0">
		<text>I managed to find some of the materials you wanted. Here you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_transfer_some_1">
		<text>Wow! Discounts galore for you, my friend!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_volunteer_0">
		<text>I can get the materials for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_volunteer_1">
		<text>That would be great! If you find anything like colophonium or capacitors, bring them to me... hell, I would even be grateful for some textolite. I can't promise you lots of cash, but you'll get a discount, that's for sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_what_for_0">
		<text>What do you need the materials for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_what_for_1">
		<text>Well, I do work with shooters and equipment... I mean, a man's gotta do what a man's gotta do to eat... But my passion is radio equipment. You know that feeling when you put something together and it works? I remember I once built a jammer... It was real useful - I turned it on when the announcements by 100 Rads kept waking me up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_where_from_0">
		<text>Why would there be radio materials at the cement factory?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_materials_where_from_1">
		<text>Cement factory is just a name... It stopped making cement long before the Chernobyl disaster. They disassembled what they could and started using the building to make electrical appliances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_0">
		<text>I found some documents at Jupiter. Will you have a look?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_1">
		<text>So... Nothing of interest here... just some administrative crap...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_minor_info_2">
		<text>Hrm... There's something of interest here and there, but I can't be certain of anything... We need the complete information. Try checking the places mentioned in the documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_11">
		<text>I really need some friggin' materials. How am I supposed to work like this?... Oh, hello. What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_12">
		<text>Howdy! You need something technical done? Obviously, I don't have any materials, but I can still repair your kit and do minor upgrades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_13">
		<text>Oh, hey. Listen, I've been thinking... It turns out that all those materials I need are simply collecting dust at the cement factory... Just the thought of it drives me crazy...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_14">
		<text>Hey! Did something break or have you put some dough together for an upgrade? Remember, you've got a lifetime discount!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_start_15">
		<text>Hello, brother! How can I help you? Remember, you get the best prices possible from yours truly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_0">
		<text>Can you unblock a memory module?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_1">
		<text>I think so... I've never done it before, so I'll need at least three hours. I'd be happy to give it a shot, though... Bearing all that in mind, I'll give you a good price - just 1,000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_11">
		<text>I can wait, so let's call it a deal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_111">
		<text>Great! I'll get to work and you take your time... I'll let you know when I'm done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_12">
		<text>I don't have that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_121">
		<text>Well, come back if you still want the job done. You won't get it done cheaper anyhow.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_13">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repair_2">
		<text>I told you I'll be able to do it in about three hours. 1,000 is a great price, so I'd take it if I were you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_0">
		<text>So, did you unblock the memory module?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_1">
		<text>No, I'm still working on it... Don't worry, I'll let you know when it's ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_ufo_memory_repaired_2">
		<text>Huh? You didn't get the module?... You must have missed Senka - I had sent him your way to deliver the module... Well, never mind. Basically, other than soil layer thickness and vegetation density readings, it also contained the coordinates of three radio beacons. I'll upload them to your PDA...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_0">
		<text>Did you try tracking the chimeras down?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_1">
		<text>The wounded one went to Zaton. Gonta's group is following it... Then again, I heard they're lacking an experienced hunter. If you help them out, I'll make it worth your while... The other one, the one that killed Fox... Well, I lost it. It was as if it just vanished... Poor Fox... He was a good man, but age sure takes its toll...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_chimera_2">
		<text>Well, you dealt with one, the wounded one... The other one, the one that killed Fox... Well, I lost it. It was as if it just vanished... Poor Fox... He was a good man,but age sure takes its toll...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_himself_0">
		<text>What do you do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_himself_1">
		<text>Well, I'm Trapper and until recently I hunted mutants that were a danger to stalkers... Nowadays, I take orders and give them to younger hunters. I train them and teach them hunting tactics...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_0">
		<text>Tell me about hunting mutants...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1">
		<text>Well, mutants require different approaches... Burers and poltergeists require one, pseudogiants and controllers need another... And chimeras are a real special case.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1111">
		<text>Tell me about burers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11111">
		<text>Burers use gravitation attacks... When at close proximity they'll throw you and when they're far away they'll try to throw something at you... Your best bet is to keep them at medium range from you and keep moving, unless you enjoy getting hit by something heavy... But be careful to conserve your energy! Burers can use directed gravitational impulses to yank weapons out of your hands and if you're tired it might just work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1112">
		<text>Tell me about poltergeists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11121">
		<text>There are two types of poltergeists. The first type sends items crashing into the enemy using gravitation, while the second type is the fire poltergeist that uses flames to burn its victims. Inexperienced hunters try to circle around them to evade their attacks... The trick is to know that poltergeists can't see or hear in the usual sense of those words and use that to your advantage. They sense objects that move in the gravitational field... So a seasoned hunter freezes as soon as he sees a poltergeist, fires and then freezes again, rinse repeat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1114">
		<text>Tell me about controllers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11141">
		<text>They use your own mind against you. When you're hunting a controller, it's important to use cover, because it must see you to affect your mind... Also, they're quite slow, so if your life is at stake, use grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1115">
		<text>Tell me about chimeras.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11151">
		<text>They're very dangerous nocturnal predators. They try to get behind you under cover of darkness and leap on top of you. If you know there's a chimera around, keep checking your back and cover your friends' asses...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1116">
		<text>Tell me about pseudogiants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_11161">
		<text>The most difficult thing about hunting pseudogiants is killing them. They can take incredible punishment without so much as batting an eyelid... All I can say is that you may want to try using a shotgun at close range. Just remember that pseudogiant attacks can detach anything that's not been fixed to concrete. Attack it from above... and make sure that whatever you're standing on can withstand some damage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_mutants_1117">
		<text>OK, forget about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_retire_0">
		<text>Why don't you hunt anymore?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_retire_1">
		<text>I’m getting old, man. That’s why Fox died... He was my partner and friend. We hunted many a beast together, shoulder to shoulder... Then we ran into these two chimeras by Zaton that haven’t been seen in the Zone for eighteen months... One knocked Fox to the ground before I could even get my shotgun out. When I wounded the other one, they ran off... I hope they burn in hell forever!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_stolen_items_0">
		<text>Who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_about_stolen_items_1">
		<text>Hrm... Don't know... That kind of thing just doesn't happen among the hunters. Piss enough people off and you might find them saving their ammo when you've got a bloodsucker getting close and personal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_bloodsucker_lair_hunted_1">
		<text>Desperate times call for desperate measures... Knowing what I know about bloodsuckers, I would think a couple of them were out hunting... But now that they've not got anywhere to come back to, they won't be a danger to stalkers anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_0">
		<text>You got any other work for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_1">
		<text>Sure. A stalker squad went into the tunnels to the north of the plant the other day and ran into a mutant lair. They were all so shocked that none of them can even explain what kind of mutants they were, but two of the stalkers didn't make it out of there alive. After that the folks at Yanov got real scared about the whole thing, so they put together a 5,000 reward for anyone who's willing to deal with this lair. It's a dangerous job, so you decide for yourself... Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_11">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_111">
		<text>You're a brave man... Good luck. You'll need it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_12">
		<text>Not now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_121">
		<text>I don't blame you... I doubt anyone will have the balls to take on a whole lair of mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_2">
		<text>Same as before. Unidentified mutants in the tunnels to the north of the Jupiter plant. 5,000 reward... Will you do it after all?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunt_3">
		<text>Stalkers are worried about the mutants in the tunnels at the moment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_0">
		<text>The mutants in the tunnels were mutated dwarfs. Now they're dead mutated dwarfs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_1">
		<text>I'm guessing they must have been burers. That explains why the folks at Yanov got all excited about the whole thing... Well, seeing as they're dead, the reward is yours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_burers_hunted_2">
		<text>I'm guessing they must have been burers... The ones that killed two stalkers recently. That explains why the folks at Yanov came up with a reward for killing them. Well, seeing as they're dead, the reward is yours!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunt_0">
		<text>I'm ready to deal with the chimera.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunt_1">
		<text>Great. The hunter who found that bastard saw it just as it got dark. It was headed towards the ventilation complex. Chimeras are nocturnal and territorial, so it was probably going to its hunting grounds... I think that's where you should look for it come nightfall. Then again, it's more active when it's dark... Be careful and good hunting.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunted_0">
		<text>The chimera is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_jupiter_chimera_hunted_1">
		<text>Thank you... Thank you! You have avenged Fox and he can now rest in peace. Here's your money - you've earned it... There's something else. Take my shotgun. You brought me something a lot more important - some peace at last...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_11">
		<text>I'm Trapper... There's no need to introduce yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_12">
		<text>What brings you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_13">
		<text>Thanks for coming... I need a reliable and experienced hunter and you're the best Yanov has to offer. After all that has happened, I can't let the chimera escape again... I'm putting up all my savings for this : 10,000. I want to make sure the job is done right... Fox must be avenged!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_14">
		<text>I'm begging you to deal with the chimera. If you don't want to rid Yanov of this mutant killer, then do it for the money... 10,000 is a lot of cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_15">
		<text>What's the situation with the chimera?... Time is of the essence, for it could move on to new hunting grounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_start_16">
		<text>Good to see you!... What's new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_0">
		<text>You got any other work for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_1">
		<text>Of course... A group of swamp bloodsuckers has been spotted in Fen, behind the cement factory. They seem to be keeping to their swamp for now... But local stalkers want to make sure they stay there forever, if you know what I mean. The price for the whole group is 3,000. Will you do it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_11">
		<text>I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_111">
		<text>Great. Happy hunting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_12">
		<text>Not now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_121">
		<text>Up to you... There's still time to change your mind before other hunters take the job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_2">
		<text>Same as before... The group of swamp bloodsuckers in Fen, behind the cement factory. The reward is 3,000... You game?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunt_3">
		<text>Nothing other than the bloodsuckers in Fen at the moment...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_0">
		<text>I killed the swamp bloodsuckers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_1">
		<text>Now stalkers can relax a little. Here's your fee as agreed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_swamp_bloodsuckers_hunted_2">
		<text>Yeah, the local stalkers will be happy to be rid of those neighbors. They even put together reward money for it, 3,000 to be precise... Here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_0">
		<text>Me and Gonta killed the chimera at Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_1">
		<text>Thank you for that. The fewer of those beasts around, the better it is for us all. Now, if you could track down that other one...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_zaton_chimera_hunted_2">
		<text>Thank you for dealing with the second beast, too. It's good to know that those chimeras won't take another stalker's life...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_about_controller_0">
		<text>Tell me how you killed the controller.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_about_controller_1">
		<text>Listen and learn, my friend, listen and learn... I went to my stash to pick up my loot and when I got there, I clocked a controller sitting right on top of it. So I grabbed a metal grate that was on the ground and used it to shield myself as I was sneaking up on it. By the time it woke up to what was going on, I'd pumped half a clip into the cocksucker's head. Just as it started trying to control me, I gave it a final bash with my rifle butt and that was that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_0">
		<text>Tell me about the artifacts at the quarry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1">
		<text>Hah! There's not much to say, 'cause there's jack shit left in the quarry now. There's no point looking in anomalies Flint has looked in, everyone knows that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_11">
		<text>So it was you who left your buddy to die in the quarry!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_111">
		<text>What?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_11111">
		<text>You can't prove anything. You're just bullshitting... It's your word against the word of a Freedom member - good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_111111">
		<text>We'll see about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1112">
		<text>Nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_12">
		<text>Thanks, bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_0">
		<text>Tell me the story about the bloodsuckers at Zaton.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_1">
		<text>When I was at Zaton, bloodsuckers made life real difficult for stalkers. Stalkers kept at 'em day and night but it didn't help one bit. I decided to help them out, so I took my shotgun and went straight for the bloodsucker lair. After some quality time with yours truly the bloodsucker problem at Zaton is all but over.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_11">
		<text>You probably don't even know where that lair is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_111">
		<text>Scram.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_112">
		<text>What do you want? Go spew your horseshit somewhere else!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_113">
		<text>Take a hike, buddy... It's your word against the word of a Freedom member - good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_1131">
		<text>We'll see about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_bloodsucker_12">
		<text>Thanks, bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_0">
		<text>Tell me the story about the shortcut to Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_1">
		<text>Well, the guide used to take a massive detour on his way from Zaton. I decided to go straight... so I did. I tried a few places and worked out the way through the anomalies pretty quick. So I sold that info to the guide and now he takes everyone that way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_11">
		<text>How about we ask Pilot who got him the maps?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_111">
		<text>Scram.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_112">
		<text>What do you want? Go spew your horseshit somewhere else!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_113">
		<text>You can't prove shit. It's your word against the word of a Freedom member - good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_1131">
		<text>We'll see about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_guide_12">
		<text>Thanks, bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_0">
		<text>Tell me about your trip to the Oasis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_1">
		<text>I was the first person to ever get to the Oasis. It's free of mutants and anomalies - just peace and quiet, all 'round. Full of artifacts too, just take your pick and walk on home.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_11">
		<text>Bullshit. I've been to the Oasis and it's nothing like that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_111">
		<text>Scram.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_112">
		<text>What do you want? Go spew your horseshit somewhere else!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_113">
		<text>Bullshit yourself. It's your word against the word of a Freedom member - good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_1131">
		<text>We'll see about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_oasis_12">
		<text>Thanks, bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_0">
		<text>Tell me about your work with the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_1">
		<text>I visited their bunker the other day. They were real happy and said, “you're exactly what we need right now, Flint!” It turns out they wanted their devices set up under anomalies. So I was like, “that's a piece of cake” - and I did everything they wanted easy. Getting those nerds to fork up the reward money was the hard part.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_11">
		<text>Stop claiming the credit for other people's achievements. I did that, not you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_111">
		<text>Scram.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_112">
		<text>What do you want? Go spew your horseshit somewhere else!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_113">
		<text>Lies... You can't prove anything. It's your word against the word of a Freedom member - good luck with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_1131">
		<text>We'll see about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_argue_scientist_12">
		<text>Thanks, bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_11">
		<text>Hey. You want to listen to my stories too?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_21">
		<text>You want to ask something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_start_31">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_0">
		<text>Buddy... shit... I'm dying...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1">
		<text>Take this medkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_11">
		<text>Thanks friend... but it won't help... Listen... I was here with a member of Freedom... We found an artifact... I walked into a gas anomaly on the way back... If he had helped me, I could have made it... But... He took the artifact and left me here. He claimed he was going to get help... Find him. I want people to know that he can't be trusted...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1111111">
		<text>I'll find him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_1111112">
		<text>I doubt I'll be able to prove anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_2">
		<text>Grab on to my shoulder, we'll get you to a medic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_start_3">
		<text>Shit happens. Bye.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_0">
		<text>I have something for you...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_11">
		<text>A Meat Chunk, here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_111">
		<text>Thanks. Scientists pay well, but I care more about the permit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_112">
		<text>Thanks a hell of a lot, friend! Now I can finally make a move for Pripyat - I just need to think of a way to get there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_12">
		<text>A Kolobok, here, take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_121">
		<text>Thanks. Scientists pay well, but I care more about the permit .</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_122">
		<text>Thanks a hell of a lot, friend! Now I can finally make a move for Pripyat - I just need to think of a way to get there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_13">
		<text>A Meat Chunk and a Kolobok, here, take them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_131">
		<text>Thanks a hell of a lot, friend! Now I can finally make a move for Pripyat - I just need to think of a way to get there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_14">
		<text>None.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_boredom_0">
		<text>Is it boring around here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_0">
		<text>You mentioned your contract...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1">
		<text>Well, I signed up to do some work for the scientists, thinking it would be easy. What I failed to notice was that the contract only expires when all the work is done. The scientists promised to give me an official permit to be in the Zone at the end of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_111">
		<text>I've completed every damn clause of the contract, except one little thing. I have to find all chemical artifacts in existence. Who could have known that you can't get Meat Chunks or Koloboks around here? If I could get those two, I would have headed towards Pripyat a long time ago, but I can't!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1111">
		<text>I might be able to help you with those artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_1112">
		<text>That's a pity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_2">
		<text>Yeah... A Meat Chunk and a Kolobok and I'm off to Pripyat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_0">
		<text>What's so special about Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_1">
		<text>Nobody knows how to get there... We're in the Zone, after all, so you can't just walk straight there. They say it's a real treasure trove of artifacts... Either way, there've been so many legends circulating around Pripyat that I'm just plain curious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>I'm putting a squad together to go to Pripyat with. Want to join us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>Actually, I've been thinking of heading over there myself... But it would be on my own. Nothing personal, I'm just used to working solo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>Hah, I'm actually setting out to Pripyat soon... But it will be on my own. Nothing personal, I'm just used to working solo...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_11">
		<text>Welcome to boredom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_12">
		<text>Man, I really want to go to Pripyat!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_13">
		<text>I just need to work out a way of getting to Pripyat and I'll be there in no time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_14">
		<text>It's good here! This is life like it's meant to be lived!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_start_15">
		<text>It's good to feel safe, for sure. I just wish it wasn't so boring!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_volunteer_0">
		<text>I might be able to help you with those artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_way_0">
		<text>Do you really know the way to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_way_1">
		<text>I don't, but if it's full of artifacts like people say, I'm ready to find one right now. I mean, I'm a trailblazer like no other - I was one of the first to find the way to Jupiter. But I always work solo - I ain't got time to watch someone else's back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_0">
		<text>Will you take me to Jupiter?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_1">
		<text>Of course. You ready to go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_11">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_12">
		<text>Not yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_jupiter_2">
		<text>Not during an emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_0">
		<text>Will you lead me to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_1">
		<text>I'll give it a shot for 5,000. I like it there!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_11">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_12">
		<text>No, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_121">
		<text>OK, it's your choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_13">
		<text>I don't think I have enough cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_pripyat_2">
		<text>I'll give it a shot for 5,000... Let's just wait for the emission to finish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_0">
		<text>Can you lead me to Zaton?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_1">
		<text>Nah, man - it's way too boring there. There's Pilot over there - he's the one you want for the safe but tedious work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_2">
		<text>Well, I can lead you to Yanov and for 3,000 I can get Pilot to take you to Zaton. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_21">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_22">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_221">
		<text>Up to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_23">
		<text>I don't have enough cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_3">
		<text>Well, I can lead you to Yanov and for 1,000 I can get Pilot to take you to Zaton. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_4">
		<text>Nah, man - it's way too boring there. There's Pilot over there - he's the one you want for the safe but tedious work - ask him after the emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_5">
		<text>Well, I can lead you to Yanov and for 3,000 I can get Pilot to take you to Zaton... Once the emission is over, obviously.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_to_zaton_6">
		<text>Well, I can lead you to Yanov and for 1,000 I can get Pilot to take you to Zaton... Once the emission is over, obviously.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_11">
		<text>They say you made it through the tunnels?... I also came from Jupiter - I found a passage underground. I can take you back there for free if you need... I'm, you know, happy to provide any assistance required to the authorities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_12">
		<text>Long time no see! They say you made it through the tunnels?... I found a passage underground. I can take you back for free if you need... I'm, you know, happy to provide any assistance required to the authorities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_13">
		<text>Long time no see! They say you made it through the tunnels?... You won't believe it but I managed to get out of my contract and still get the permit... As soon as I did, I headed here and found a passage underground. I can take you back for free if you need... I'm, you know, happy to provide any assistance required to the authorities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_pripyat_start_14">
		<text>Long time no see! They say you made it through the tunnels?... I found a passage underground. I can take you back for free if you need... I'm, you know, happy to provide any assistance required to the authorities. By the way, thanks for helping me complete that contract with the scientists... I've had a little look around here and found this - take it. I'm sure you'll find a use for it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_ask_topol_about_guard_0">
		<text>Topol, why don't you protect the scientists' bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_ask_topol_about_guard_1">
		<text>Well, we're employed to take measurements and collect samples. We're almost scientists at this stage. Plus, while I don't have anything against the job per se, I'm not sure I can handle the eggheads' new enemies. I don't feel like dying from a merc bullet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_11">
		<text>You're in the wrong place, buddy! And you better leave before we make it the wrong time, too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_12">
		<text>You looking for trouble or something? Get out of here before you find it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_merc_guards_start_13">
		<text>Get lost, buddy. Do that, and we'll keep it peaceful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_0">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_1">
		<text>We're going to Yanov station soon. Come with us, if you like.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_11">
		<text>Yeah, that's on my way. I'll join you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_go_home_12">
		<text>Nah, that's out of my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_squad_start_dialog_0">
		<text>It's a good thing you brought them to us - they wouldn't have lasted long on their own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_duty_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Thanks for making an arrangement with Duty.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_0">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_1">
		<text>We're going to Yanov station soon. Come with us, if you like.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_11">
		<text>Yeah, that's on my way. I'll join you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_go_home_12">
		<text>Nah, that's out of my way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_squad_start_dialog_0">
		<text>You did the right thing, man. You helped those dudes and brought us reinforcements. Respect.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_freedom_start_dialog_0">
		<text>Thanks for making an arrangement with Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_about_stolen_items_0">
		<text>Do you know who could have stolen things from a personal box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_about_stolen_items_1">
		<text>I don't know - there's all kinds of folk around here... You could try asking Bonesetter, he knows almost everyone in this place...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_0">
		<text>Let's go see Zulu.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_1">
		<text>OK. I hope he's not going to shoot when he sees my old armor! We need to pick it up on the way... and return the one I'm wearing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_11">
		<text>Let's go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_goto_zulus_2">
		<text>Wait. Emissions ain't healthy... Let's wait a bit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_0">
		<text>What happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1">
		<text>Well... We don’t remember how we got here. I remember that we were a Monolith squad... We had this burning desire to reach the center of the Zone. That’s where the Monolith is - it’s a meteor, that brought the beginnings of new life from other planets... I remember reaching the CNPP together... And then it’s all fragmented. I remember a bright light... cosmic cold... and a clear voice...  Everything was just... perfect. I don't remember what that voice ordered me to do now. Several years of my life... just gone. The boys are the same... We don’t know what to do. We definitely need somewhere to take cover from emissions... and mutants, right? Do you have any ideas about where we would be safe?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_11">
		<text>There's a stalker base not far from here, I can point it out to you on a map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_111">
		<text>I’m not sure that’s safe... When we were on our way to the CNPP, we were treated with suspicion...  I think we actually killed stalkers afterwards. Do you know how people treat our faction right now? They’ll probably start shooting... Can you help us? Could you tell everyone at the stalker camp that we’re not killers anymore? Could you speak to them and get them to accept us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1111">
		<text>No problem, I'll speak to them the next time I'm at the base.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_1112">
		<text>Sorry, I can’t help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_0">
		<text>What kind of help do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_1">
		<text>We need somewhere to take cover from emissions... and mutants, right? Can you find a place where we would be safe?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_11">
		<text>OK. I’ll ask the folks at Yanov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_help_2_12">
		<text>Sorry, I can’t help you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_outfit_0">
		<text>You'll need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to get to Pripyat. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_need_outfit_1">
		<text>That's fine - I kept my Monolith armor and it comes with exactly that. The problem is that I can't be seen wearing it at Yanov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_0">
		<text>I'm putting a squad together to go with me to Pripyat. Will you join us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_1">
		<text>I'd go... I mean, I'm more than curious to find out what happened to us there. But I can't go now. I can't leave my boys here . They've been through a lot as it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_2">
		<text>Yes, I'll go with you. I want to know what happened to us. I have my fingers crossed that we'll find the answer to that question in Pripyat. I just have to warn Loki, but I doubt he'll object.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_group_3">
		<text>Yes, I'll go with you. I really want to know what happened to us. I hope to find the answer to that question in Pripyat. I just have to warn Shulga, but I doubt he'll object.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_ready_0">
		<text>Are you ready to go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_ready_1">
		<text>Ready.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_11">
		<text>Hello, stalker. Could you help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_12">
		<text>Hello. Did you find out if we can go to the stalker base?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_121">
		<text>No, I'm still working on it...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_1211">
		<text>Hurry up, 'cause you never know what could happen here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_13">
		<text>Hello. Thanks for helping us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_start_14">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_wassup_0">
		<text>How are things?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_wassup_1">
		<text>Things are OK, the squad is in order, but I really want to know what happened to us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_mercs_0">
		<text>What are the mercenaries doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_mercs_1">
		<text>You should speak to Hermann about that. He deals with all administrative aspects of the laboratory. As far as I am aware, the mercenaries have made an agreement with Hermann concerning the protection of our laboratory. I am not familiar with the details of this arrangement. However, I must point out that they have proven themselves as reliable fighters on numerous occasions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_0">
		<text>What are you doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1">
		<text>A rhetorical question, don't you think? We are researching. Are you interested in something specific?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1111">
		<text>What is the purpose of your research?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11111">
		<text>We have no specific objective in mind. We're scientific scouts, if you will. We are seeking to identify correlations in certain phenomena, develop theories and prove or disprove them. Some of our theories have no practical purpose as we know it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1112">
		<text>What do you know about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11121">
		<text>I can only hypothesize at this stage... I believe that the Zone was formed as a consequence of some new force. Electromagnetic fields, physical force or radiation couldn't have changed the biosphere so quickly. Obviously, some mutations can be explained by radiation... But, excuse me! An ordinary pig would need hundreds, if not thousands, of years to mutate into flesh! In the Zone the mutation occurred in a couple of years. It's as if someone directly altered the genetic information in individual animals. The thought of that is enough to send shivers down my spine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1113">
		<text>How long have you been in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_11131">
		<text>No more than a week. It took tremendous effort to cut through all the red tape and organize this expedition. If it weren't for Hermann, we might've still been waiting on the borders of the Zone, while stalkers removed invaluable items from it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scientists_1114">
		<text>That's all I wanted to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_0">
		<text>Ozersky, why did Hermann hire me to protect the squad during the taking of measurements?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_1">
		<text>It was my idea. He didn't see the point, but I convinced him. My research indicates that the effects of our high wave equipment on anomalous fields induces a heightened state of aggression in nearby mutated species, as well as, boosts their activity levels. Long story short, they start looking for something to kill.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_0">
		<text>Ozersky, I've got news.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_1">
		<text>Yes? I'm listening.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_11">
		<text>You were right. The mutants wouldn't let us rest for a moment while we were taking measurements, but as soon as the devices were switched off, things calmed down.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_111">
		<text>What?! If... if my hypothesis proved correct, it is probable that mutated animals that acquired the ability to access informational fields can telepathically receive signals from outside... artificial signals... in which case... the unnatural similarity in mutations and these typical changes in cell structure... are not accidental...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_1111">
		<text>Could you be more specific? And could you actually make some sense this time?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_about_scrutiny_learned_11111">
		<text>No! These are but my conjectures. Oh, how terribly rude of me! Thank you very much for your assistance in our research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_0">
		<text>What needs to happen for you to talk to Hermann about a suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_1">
		<text>An area filled with a previously unknown anomalous plant has appeared near the edge of the quarry. I really want a sample of this plant, but stalkers refuse to go near the place. If I had one of those plants, I could speak to Hermann about rewarding you with one of the spare suits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_11">
		<text>I'll find the plant for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_111">
		<text>OK, I uploaded the anomaly coordinates to your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_12">
		<text>Maybe next time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_grove_121">
		<text>Drop in if you change your mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_plant_0">
		<text>Here, I brought the plant you wanted. Now how about that suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_anomalous_plant_1">
		<text>Great. Hah, Sokolov has actually let slip that the suit is for him. Well, it doesn't matter. I'll show Hermann the plant and he'll agree to hand over the suit in no time. Tell Sokolov to come and collect it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_aproach_0">
		<text>I can find some new guards for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_aproach_1">
		<text>That would be kind of you. Please speak to Hermann about this matter since it falls within the scope of his responsibilities.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_0">
		<text>I'd like to check my resistance to the psy-field.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_1">
		<text>Hah, so Hermann sent you to see me? OK, let me explain this as simply as I can. In order to properly analyze your resistance to psy-emissions, I will need a scientific research complex and years of study. What I actually have is a field kit with a couple of dirty test tubes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_11">
		<text>It's impossible, then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_b1_psi_emission_dialog_111">
		<text>Not so fast. We're not talking about a full analysis. For our aims we merely need to assess the resistance of your neurons to psy-emissions.  A basic examination will do just fine. So... It seems that your head is in order. That is to say that you can be affected by relatively high levels of psy-emissions without losing consciousness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_0">
		<text>What about the hypothesis concerning increased mutant aggression?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_1">
		<text>I have two theories about that. The first is that mutant aggression may be caused by the intrusion of several people into their territory, in which case that is normal behavior for most unmutated species, including humans. The other theory is that mutants are somehow capable of receiving the active emissions of our measurement devices. Clearly, the latter theory is far more intriguing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_11">
		<text>How could this be tested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_about_111">
		<text>The measurement device should be activated in an area where there was no previous mutant activity. Furthermore, in order to minimize the human intrusion effect, the experiment should be conducted by a maximum of one person.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_0">
		<text>I brought the scanner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_1">
		<text>What results did you get?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_11">
		<text>I don't know what your device will show, but I believe the hypothesis fully checks out. After I activated the scanner, it took all of five minutes for snorks to come charging at me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_confirmed_111">
		<text>That's what I thought. For some reason, it is usually the most undesirable theories that prove to be right. In any case, it is a good thing that you tested this. Now we'll have to make sure any squad we send out to take measurements is ready for some rough stuff. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_0">
		<text>I'm ready to try to confirm or disprove the hypothesis. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_1">
		<text>I'm delighted that there are still people in the world who are willing to make sacrifices for the greater scientific good. The best place to conduct the experiment is the landslide on the southern edge of the quarry - that area is full of gravitational anomalies that mutants normally try to avoid. The device I am giving you has a built-in mutant detection sensor. When you return the device after you have completed the experiment, I will be able to track the effects of emission levels on mutant aggression. Are you prepared to do this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_11">
		<text>Yeah, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_hypotheses_volunteer_12">
		<text>Not at the moment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_soldier_outfit_0">
		<text>Is there any way I could get a scientific suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_soldier_outfit_1">
		<text>That's against protocol. We have to account for every item of equipment we have. Then again, knowing Hermann, he probably ordered more than we need. I think that in certain circumstances, he could be convinced to part with one of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_stalker_assistant_rival_0">
		<text>Do you need any artifacts found?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_biochemist_stalker_assistant_rival_1">
		<text>No, sorry. We don't send random people on artifact hunting assignments anymore. We signed a contract with an experienced artifact hunter, and whatever we may need, he gets it for us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_aproach_0">
		<text>I can find some new guards for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_aproach_1">
		<text>That would be good. The Zone is never peaceful... Talk to Hermann about it - he's the boss around here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_0">
		<text>You're supposed to issue me with scanners for anomaly research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_1">
		<text>Take this. Three, as Hermann said.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_b32_give_scanner_2">
		<text>Take this. Two more, as Hermann said.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_soldier_outfit_0">
		<text>How can I get a scientific suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_soldier_outfit_1">
		<text>Hermann is in charge of inventory. But I'll save you the trouble of asking: you won't get anything from him. Try talking to Ozersky instead. On the one hand, he's a bit more laid back, on the other - he can influence Hermann.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_11">
		<text>What brings you here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_12">
		<text>Listen, where did those mercs go? The ones who were protecting you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_13">
		<text>How's life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_14">
		<text>Listen... Someone gunned down those mercs who were protecting you. I didn't like them much myself, but that's going a bit far...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_start_15">
		<text>CS-3a - cool! That's pretty good armor... Reminds me of the good old days...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_0">
		<text>Can you unblock a memory module?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_1">
		<text>Let's have a look... No problem. I've done this before... It won't take more than an hour. I'll do it for... hrm, 2,000. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_11">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_111">
		<text>Good. I'll let you know once I've unblocked it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_12">
		<text>I haven't got that much money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_121">
		<text>Hrm. Well, you know where to find me. I doubt anyone can do a better job of this than me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_13">
		<text>I'll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repair_2">
		<text>Like I said, I'll do it in an hour for 2,000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_0">
		<text>So, did you unblock the memory module?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_1">
		<text>The hour ain't up. I told you I'd contact you when it's done.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_medic_ufo_memory_repaired_2">
		<text>Yes, here it is. It's ready for you to access the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_0">
		<text>I found a strange semi-artifact. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1">
		<text>Of course. Where did you find it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_11">
		<text>At Zaton, in the abandoned dredge station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1111">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_1112">
		<text>No thanks! I'll look for another buyer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_mercs_0">
		<text>What are the mercs doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_mercs_1">
		<text>We have a contract with them for the protection of the mobile laboratory. In anticipation of your question, I will tell you that I had no choice but to recruit them. Due to some secret military operation, we were not given the appropriate protection for laboratory deployment. That fact coupled with stalkers suddenly going bonkers for artifact hunting and I had no other choice but the mercenaries if I wanted to keep the laboratory safe.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_0">
		<text>What do you do here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1">
		<text>We research various phenomena.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1111">
		<text>What is the purpose of your research?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11111">
		<text>We are conducting fundamental research. In other words, we are not here to test suits, invent new drugs or things like that. We are trying to find a logical explanation for the things we see in the Zone. If we uncover the secrets behind even ten percent of the phenomena we see here, that would give global technological development a massive shot in the arm.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1112">
		<text>What do you know about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11121">
		<text>Not much, if I'm honest. We are just starting to understand the mechanisms that drive some of the phenomena we encounter, and unfortunately we're far from understanding the Zone as a system. This is particularly difficult by the fact that the Zone evolves over time. I don't mean the appearance of new anomalies or little things like that. I'm talking about more serious changes, ones that cannot always be spotted with the naked eye. The weakening of the magnetic field is an example of this. The saddest thing is that we don't know what this is all leading to. All that is left for us to do is to sit and wait.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1113">
		<text>How long have you been in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_11131">
		<text>Not long, about a week. That said, I did visit Sakharov's laboratory a few times. I still regret the fact that we failed to get this expedition off the ground faster. I told the people at the Ministry of Education many times that we must always have two fully equipped mobile laboratories ready to go at any moment... they just nodded their fat heads at me and that was it! Thanks to them we almost missed the greatest research opportunity the Zone has ever provided!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_scientists_1114">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_0">
		<text>Is there any information on the scanners I placed in the anomalies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_2">
		<text>Which anomaly are you interested in, specifically?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_21">
		<text>The anomaly by the parking lot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_211">
		<text>Yes, our devices indicate the presence of artifacts in that anomaly!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_212">
		<text>Unfortunately, there are no signs of artifacts in that anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_22">
		<text>Concrete Bath anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_23">
		<text>Bitumen anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_24">
		<text>Fen anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_25">
		<text>Ash Heap anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_artefact_spawn_26">
		<text>That's it for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_1">
		<text>I'm listening carefully.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11">
		<text> Recent events have made it very clear that our research team is not sufficiently prepared to conduct proper field work. You, on the other hand, managed to deal with the controller on your own! That is quite astounding!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111">
		<text>What's your point?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_1111">
		<text>My point is that it would be only logical for us to at least attempt to recruit such a capable expert as you. Our science group is most positively in need of your assistance. We need to take measurements, position scanners...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11111">
		<text>Go on...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111111">
		<text>I am trying to find the correlation between emissions and the appearance of artifacts in anomalies. I have a theory that the next emission can be forecast using the number and quality of artifacts that appear. In order to make specific calculations, I will need to gather statistics. All we need to do is position a few scanners in the middle of anomalies of different types.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_11112">
		<text>Sorry, but I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_111121">
		<text>That's a pity. You could have served science.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_2">
		<text>OK, I'll help you out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_21">
		<text>Excellent! You need to get the scanners from Novikov and position them in the anomalies marked on your PDA. When you're done, come back to see me - I have another matter that concerns scanners and measurements to discuss with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_3">
		<text>I'll think about it and come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_scanner_placed_0">
		<text>I put the scanners in the anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_scanner_placed_1">
		<text>Excellent! I already have the first results. I can't wait for an emission - it will provide us with the necessary statistical sample...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_1">
		<text>I'm listening very carefully!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_11">
		<text>When I got near it and got the scientific detector out, everything around me began to warp, as if it was being compressed. Then, after a while, dead stalker bodies dropped out of thin air! Then it stopped.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_111">
		<text>That's incredible! Obviously, the information is devastatingly scarce and nothing can be deduced from that for certain, but we will enter this description in our records. We'll call the anomaly a Space Bubble!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_found_guards_0">
		<text>Looks like you've got new guards?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_found_guards_1">
		<text>Yes, they're quite nice. We feel very safe with them around. Thank you for your efforts - here's your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_gauss_rifle_docs_0">
		<text>Have a look at these documents.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_gauss_rifle_docs_1">
		<text>Let's have a look... I won't ask how you got these, but this is simply incredible! Let me make a copy of this... Oh, by the way, here's your modest reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_0">
		<text>What happened to your guards?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1">
		<text>I don't know, they just disappeared!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11">
		<text>I have connections in the Zone. I could find you some new guards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_111">
		<text>That would be wonderful! They will be given full scientific support and the latest technological developments in exchange for their work! You'll get a reward, too!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1111">
		<text>Deal!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11111">
		<text>I can't wait!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_1112">
		<text>I've changed my mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_11121">
		<text>That's a pity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_12">
		<text>It happens.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_121">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_guards_2">
		<text>Our guards were killed! Gunned down right outside our bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_0">
		<text>I found some documents at the Jupiter plant.  Would you like to have a look?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_1">
		<text>That's interesting, but not very useful. Thanks for your efforts anyway. If you find anything else, bring it here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_11">
		<text>I was attacked by mercenaries while I was looking for documents. Here's their leader's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_111">
		<text>Wow, and I thought that they were here to protect us. Looks like I'll have to bring this up to my superiors... Thank you very much, young man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_docs_2">
		<text>Unfortunately, it doesn't contain any interesting information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_1">
		<text>There is something: we need to find out about the latest developments made at the Jupiter plant. I really need the technical documents concerning these developments. You should probably look for them in the administrative part of the plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_11">
		<text>I'll look for them and bring back whatever I find.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_12">
		<text>No, I won't be able to help you with that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_0">
		<text>I brought the documents back from Jupiter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_1">
		<text>That's interesting, but not very useful. Thanks for your efforts anyway. If you find anything else, bring it here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_11">
		<text>I was attacked by mercenaries while I was looking for documents. Here's their leader's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_info_111">
		<text>Wow, and I thought that they were here to protect us. Looks like I'll have to bring this up to my superiors... Thank you very much, young man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_11">
		<text>I'll try to find the anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_12">
		<text>I haven't got time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_0">
		<text>I'm here to see you about my participation in your research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1">
		<text>I know that I speak for all of the team when I say that we would be delighted if you agree to serve science once more. What are you interested in?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_11">
		<text>I would like to help with taking measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_112">
		<text>You're really willing to assist us in carrying out a full external scan? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1121">
		<text>Yes, I'll help - tell me what to do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1122">
		<text>No, I need to think things over again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12">
		<text>You mentioned positioning scanners.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_121">
		<text>I am trying to find the correlation between emissions and the appearance of artifacts in anomalies. I have a theory that the next emission can be forecast using the number and quality of artifacts that appear. In order to make specific calculations, I will need to gather statistics. All we need to do is position a few scanners in the middle of anomalies of different types.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1211">
		<text>OK, I'll help you out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12111">
		<text>Excellent! You need to get the scanners from Novikov and position them in the anomalies marked on your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1212">
		<text>I'll think about it and come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_122">
		<text>The scanners in anomalies are transmitting information. All we have to do is wait for the results. You can place a few more scanners in anomalies if you want. We could always use extra information and as your reward, we'll inform you when artifacts appear in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1221">
		<text>I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_12211">
		<text>Excellent! You need to get the scanners from Novikov and position them in the anomalies marked on your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_1222">
		<text>I'll think about it and come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_131">
		<text>Unfortunately, we have a rule which prevents us from assigning more than one task at a time to the same person. I'm sorry but we have to stick to it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_0">
		<text>Did you get the anomaly field measurement results from the squad I protected?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_31">
		<text>Oh yeah, your measurements clearly got mutant's and zombie's attention. It took some time and effort to fight them off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_311">
		<text>Hrm, so you think they reacted to the scans? Interesting. Well, in that case,  it looks like you're confirming Ozersky's hypothesis that mutants telepathically access various fields. I think it's worth discussing it with him. Here is your payment for the work you've done. You've earned it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_312">
		<text>Hrm, so you believe they reacted to the scans? Interesting. Well, in that case it seems Ozersky's hypothesis that mutants telepathically access various fields is confirmed by you as well and you should probably tell Ozersky about it. It's a pity about the stalkers. A portion of our modest funds will be used to pay compensation to their families. The rest is your fee for the work you've done for us. Thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_soldier_outfit_0">
		<text> Is there any way I could get a scientific suit?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_soldier_outfit_1">
		<text>No! The number of suits is strictly limited and I simply cannot afford to give them away!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_11">
		<text>What would you like to say to me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_12">
		<text>Have you by any chance seen the people responsible for guarding our bunker?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_13">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_start_14">
		<text>You won't believe it but someone killed our guards, right next to our bunker!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_0">
		<text>Do you need help?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1">
		<text>We're trying to collect a new type of samples at the moment. They don't have any anomalous effect on their own, but experiments we conduct with them produce incredible results!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11">
		<text>Keep going...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111">
		<text>Cut the crap and tell me what needs doing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111">
		<text>OK... The stalkers who found the psy-field believe that it contains a mutant lair. I don't really believe them... I mean, no mutant other than a controller can survive in an intermittent psy-field! Don't worry, our boys will deal with the mutants. We need you simply because regular contact with psy-fields has reduced our stalkers' resistance to their effects.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111111">
		<text>Let me get this straight: you want me to go into an unknown psy-field and get you a sample of something that might not even be there, and if it is there nobody knows what it looks like?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111111">
		<text>Exactly! This mission is essential for science in general and for our team in particular. Your help would be invaluable. If you have any doubts, go see Ozersky. He will conduct the necessary analysis, which will identify your current resistance to psy-emissions. You can also ask our stalkers and they'll explain it all to you. So, are you willing to aid science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111111">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111112">
		<text>You don't know? Your stalker squad is dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_2">
		<text>Given that you failed to show up at the tunnel the last time, it will be very difficult for me to convince the team to work with you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_21">
		<text>That was an accident.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_211">
		<text>I believe you, but our sample collection team is made up of peculiar people - you shouldn't let them down. I'll speak to them again and I should be able to persuade them into changing their minds. But don't fail me this time, I'm waiting for the sample.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_3">
		<text>Forgive me for this, but I must refuse. Your equipment is simply unsuitable for an intermittent psy-field - you will meet a swift and painful death, and I don't need that on my conscience.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_0">
		<text>I got you the sample.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_1">
		<text>Really? Show it to me, I can't wait to see it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_11">
		<text>I got your sample and as it turned out there was a controller in the tunnel. It tried to take over your squad and almost succeeded. I managed to kill it before it did.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_111">
		<text>You're amazing! You killed a controller and saved the stalkers from a psy-attack... If I didn't know it was true, I would never have believed you! It's excellent experience and a fantastic sample. Your contribution to science is noteworthy indeed. Thank you from me personally, on behalf of my team and all the scientists of the world!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_12">
		<text>Unfortunately the squad was attacked by a controller. I had to defend myself. The controller is dead, but so are the stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_121">
		<text>A controller, you say? How terrible, who could have known? I mourn the loss of those brave boys... They were loyal servants of science. Even though they were not technically scientists, they did more for science than many professors! Thank you and please take this modest reward...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_13">
		<text>Unfortunately the squad was attacked by a controller. I barely made it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_mercs_0">
		<text>What are the mercs doing here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_mercs_1">
		<text>Getting in my way. But that's my personal opinion. At first they kept asking me to fix this or attach that... And then yesterday they lost whatever shame they had left and started asking how our equipment works. I simply fail to see how that's going to help them guard the bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_0">
		<text>What equipment modifications can you perform?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_1">
		<text>You can see, this is a scientific complex... There's no Kevlar or weapons for spare parts here. What I can do is patch up body armor or modify it using one of my personal developments. As you can imagine, I've got plenty of top notch equipment to spare.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_2">
		<text>Thanks to you and the sample you retrieved from the psy-field, Ozersky was able to come up with something to protect people from emissions. I converted his idea into something practical... that I can install in your suit if you want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_3">
		<text>Well, other than the usual upgrades, I can offer you filtering and psy-protection modifications. After all, you were the one who helped to make them happen... Ozersky and Hermann were happy like pigs in shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_4">
		<text>Well, other than the usual upgrades, I can offer you isolation and psy-protection modifications. After all, you were the one who helped to make them happen... Ozersky and Hermann were happy like pigs in shit!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_new_upgrade_5">
		<text>I've got the full range of mods: isolation, filtering and psy-protection. A suit that has all of those installed will allow you to walk into any anomaly... And you might even be able to walk back out. By the way, thank you for participating in Hermann's research. Without that, I wouldn't have all these options for you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_0">
		<text>Tell me about your bunker.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1">
		<text>Hrm. What do you wanna know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1111">
		<text>What does the laboratory do?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11111">
		<text>I doubt even Hermann and Ozersky can answer that question. Obviously they do all sorts of research... But the end result is measly at best. Then again, you could have a chat with Ozersky... I was able to come up with a couple of decent suit modifications on the basis of his theories.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1112">
		<text>What do you know about the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11121">
		<text>Nothing in a scientific sense, but I've got a lot of practical experience of the Zone. The only thing of value here is something that increases your chances of survival. The Zone doesn't care whether you're a bandit or a stalker collecting artifacts to feed his family. Only those who are best suited to life in the Zone survive here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1113">
		<text>How long have you been in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_11131">
		<text>A while now. At first, I was hunting for artifacts just like everyone else, but my health was declining steadily until I realized I just can't do it anymore. Thankfully, I've got a brain cell or two, so it's not difficult to find work. I spent about a year with a faction made up of former scientists. They were good people... it's a pity they died in a blind pursuit of some hazy goal. After that I spent some time wandering the Zone and then I started working for the scientists. No regrets so far.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_about_scientists_1114">
		<text>That's all I wanted to know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b1_psi_emission_dialog_0">
		<text>I'm planning to go into the intermittent psy-field. You got any advice for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b1_psi_emission_dialog_1">
		<text>What can I say? I doubt you're familiar with the informational-energy field theory... You can be sure that brief exposure to the psy-field is not dangerous... in the long run, anyway. But don't relax too much when you're in there. Those who underestimate psy-fields end up as zombies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b33_about_snags_container_0">
		<text>Can you break into a steel container?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_b33_about_snags_container_1">
		<text>That's not for me. I don't have the right equipment... And it's against our health and safety rules.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_blackbox_0">
		<text>Can you decrypt a black box?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_blackbox_1">
		<text>I can, but I'm not going to. I used to do that kind of thing... And I didn't like it. Too much hassle... I get enough work from the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_csky_outfit_0">
		<text>What's special about the CS-3a?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_csky_outfit_1">
		<text>Other than the fact that I designed it?... It's one of the best suits in the Zone. That's why you're wearing it, right? It's light, mobile and has solid army body armor at its core. I added the anomaly protection stuff myself... It's a pity that we had a shortage of materials in those days... But what else do you expect in the middle of a swamp... Still, all it would take is a couple of patches and you've got a real modern suit... I've got plenty of top notch equipment to spare, so that's no problem either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_about_owl_0">
		<text>Do you work for Owl?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_about_owl_1">
		<text>No. He helped me get something the other day... A favor for a favor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_bring_detectors_0">
		<text>Owl asked me to bring you detectors. Here they are.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_tech_zat_b30_actor_bring_detectors_1">
		<text>Good. I'll do some work with them and return them to Owl with the guides... Anything else is personal business between you and Owl.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_0">
		<text>Oh! So you were the one selling weapons to bandits at Zaton!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_1">
		<text>Shh... Are you crazy talking about that shit here? We don't know each other, you got that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_11">
		<text>Got it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_12">
		<text>How about I tell the commander about your little business on the side?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_121">
		<text>And what are you going to tell him? You got nothing on me. I mean, you were the one who helped to take out the witnesses. You got no proof, and you'll look like an idiot accusing me of stuff with no evidence.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_0">
		<text>I found a PDA on some dead mercs. It contains a contract to assassinate me. With you as the client.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_1">
		<text>I've had enough of you... Listen, give me the PDA and I'll give you an excellent weapon used exclusively by elite Duty troops. So, how about it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_12">
		<text>OK, I'll take that shooter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_13">
		<text>Keep it. I don't need handouts from a backstabbing snake!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_0">
		<text>I have another PDA with a contract to assassinate me. You're the client, again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_1">
		<text>Damn it... Friggin' mercs... can't trust them to do shit... Listen, let's put an end to this... Here's what we'll do. The mercs are going to stop looking for you and you're gonna leave me alone. In order to compensate your losses, I will lead you to Duty's secret warehouse where you can take all the weapons you can carry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_11">
		<text>OK, let's do that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_111">
		<text>Good, let's meet there. The stash is next to the quarry.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_12">
		<text>I'm not going anywhere. You'll have to give me all that stuff right here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_121">
		<text>I don't have anything here! I'm not that stupid! Either we meet by the stash or you don't get anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_1211">
		<text>No, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b7_duty_illicit_dealer_b207_blackmail_with_pda_2_13">
		<text>I don't need handouts from a backstabbing snake!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_0">
		<text>I want to leave the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_1">
		<text>You sure? There ain’t no way back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_11">
		<text>I’m sure. Let’s go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_guide_leave_zone_12">
		<text>Actually... I’ll stay for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_2">
		<text>Let’s have a look... Well, your liver is bigger than I'd expect, but that's an occupational hazard, right? Apart from that, you’re as healthy as a burer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_stalker_lead_info_1116141">
		<text>It would be just about normal if it didn’t glow. It’s a scary thing, the way it is now. Go have a look for yourself... I doubt you’ll enjoy the visit though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_1112">
		<text>OK, it’s your choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_2">
		<text> "Former" Monolith fighters? Well, it’s your call... Will you vouch for them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b4_monolith_squad_dialog_2">
		<text> "Former" Monolith fighters? No, thanks. The last thing I need is a rabid mob of fanatics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_2">
		<text>Hah. Good boy. You take care of your own, and that means you know you gotta keep my palms nice and greasy. So what have you got for me, an artifact or the 15,000?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_14">
		<text>I brought an artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_141">
		<text>All right, which one?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_15">
		<text>I don't have an artifact worth that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1411">
		<text>Flame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1412">
		<text>Goldfish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1413">
		<text>Firefly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1414">
		<text>Snowflake.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1415">
		<text>Hrm... None, for now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_151">
		<text>Well, I've said what I had to say. Now I wanna hear you talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_break_dialog_0">
		<text>See ya.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_4">
		<text>Of course! The intermittent psy-field still needs to be studied, and the sooner, the better. Let me ask, how certain are you of the relative safety of this venture? We most positively need your assistance in obtaining a test sample. So, are you willing to help science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_0">
		<text>I may be able to find a few good people to staff your new research group.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_1">
		<text>Indeed? Such help would be most welcome and, I suppose, warrant a reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_11">
		<text>All right. I will hire the right people.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_12">
		<text>I'll think about it some more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_14">
		<text>Here it is. I found a controller in that tunnel. Then I killed him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_141">
		<text>You're amazing! You killed a controller and obtained what we needed... If I didn't know otherwise, I would never have believed you! It's excellent experience and a fantastic sample. Your contribution to science is noteworthy indeed. On behalf of me personally and scientists everywhere, please accept my sincerest gratitude!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_15">
		<text>Here it is. I found a controller in that tunnel. I barely made it out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_complete_151">
		<text>A controller, you say? How terrible, but who could have known? The important thing is that you brought us the sample and thereby made a noteworthy contribution to science. Thank you, and please take this modest reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_done_0">
		<text>How do you like your new research group?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_employ_stalkers_done_1">
		<text>Oh, just fine. Competent young men, I must say. Please take this. We appreciate your, err, human resources skills.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_about_dialog_31">
		<text>Wassup, bro? Obviously, I’m glad to see you, but I wouldn’t mind being on my own for a while either.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_0">
		<text>I’m here about the captive stalker. I want to buy him out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_1">
		<text>And I want respect for the bandits and our rules, buddy, but I ain't interested in unnecessary trouble either... 15,000 or a suitable artifact will do for now... I'm a fair man - I won't take more than I'm owed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_11">
		<text>Here’s the cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_111">
		<text>OK... I respect what you’re doing. Take this loser and tell the stalkers that next time the price will be higher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_12">
		<text>I don't have that much on me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_121">
		<text>OK, you ain’t got shit, what else is new?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_chief_actor_self_dialog_13">
		<text>I haven’t got anything suitable at the moment - I’ll come back later.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_a9_sell_info_1">
		<text>Let’s have a look... Well, there’s nothing of strategic importance here, but it could come in handy. I’ll buy all of these at 500 per document. Deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_3">
		<text>Let's have a look. Holy crap... This info would damage Duty’s reputation... a lot! I’ll buy it for 4000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_111">
		<text>Interesting. Well, I would be prepared to purchase it from you for 2000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_about_halfartefact_zat_b14_2">
		<text>Yes, but the price is the same as before: 2000.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_snag_b202_about_stole_114">
		<text>OK, see you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_1111121">
		<text>But that’s terrible! What on Earth could have happened to them? Hrm... Mutants are a possibility. I’ll have to ask Ozersky which type of monster it could be... Hrm. Nonetheless, the psy-field needs to be studied. This mission is essential for science in general and for our team in particular. We badly need your help with acquiring a sample. If you have any doubts, go see Ozersky. He will conduct the necessary analysis, which will identify your current resistance to psy-emissions. So, are you willing to aid science?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_11111112">
		<text>I’ll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_physicist_b1_variable_psi_emission_dialog_111">
		<text>Our research team, made up of local stalkers, recently found a psy-field that is highly unusual. According to our theories and the measurements taken, the nature of this field is such that it has intermittent psy effects, as opposed to emitting them permanently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_113">
		<text>Unfortunately, our research team is dead, and until we find a replacement, there's no chance of taking any measurements.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_b32_investigation_anomaly_0">
		<text>Please wait... Would you be so kind as to give me a moment’s attention?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_0">
		<text>What are the anomaly scan results?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_jupiter_products_0">
		<text>You got any other work for me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_11">
		<text>I’ve heard of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_111">
		<text>Unfortunately, I have not been able to convince Hermann to equip a search team yet... I admit, the rumors about this phenomenon are too contradictory, but something tells me that the Oasis exists. My intuition rarely lets me down, so if you can find it and bring me proof of its existence, I would be extremely grateful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_1113">
		<text>I would look for it, but I’ve already been to the Oasis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_legend_11131">
		<text>Hrm... Err... I think I must have misheard you. What did you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_0">
		<text>I'm here to pay Vano’s debt.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1">
		<text>Yeah, I remember him. His debt ain't small and with the juice running it's up to 7 Gs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1111">
		<text>OK, here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11111">
		<text>Tell Vano he don't owe us anymore.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_111111">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1112">
		<text>I don’t have that much.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11121">
		<text>Come back when you do.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1113">
		<text>Interest wasn’t part of the deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11131">
		<text>What are you talking about? Do you take me for a sucker - lending out cash without charging interest? It’s 7 Gs and that’s the end of it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1114">
		<text>Think carefully now. I’ve got my shooter here and I don’t mind using it... Tell me, what is your corpse gonna do with all that interest?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11141">
		<text>OK, OK, calm down chief! I’m sure we can come to an agreement. Just pay me 5 Gs and that’s his debt settled.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_11142">
		<text>Hah... shove that pea shooter up your ass, punk! It’s 7 Gs including interest. End of story.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1115">
		<text>Did you forget me? I’ve still got the shooter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1116">
		<text>I prefer to shoot you down for free.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_1117">
		<text>I’ll think about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalkers_dialog_debt_2">
		<text>7 Gs, including interest.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_1">
		<text>I ain’t up for any big jobs right now. I need to get my shit together... You know, I might even go home... find a proper job and forget these damn artifacts... I just don't know how I'd leave Grizzly... and Torba... We're real close now, always helping each other out... I don't know, maybe I just need to rest and get my head on straight...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_come_with_me_2">
		<text>I ain’t up for any big jobs right now.  I’m gonna work for the scientists and get my shit together... You know, I might even go home... Find a job on the outside... Ah, I don’t know. I need to just chill and get my head on straight...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalkers_choose_dialog_14">
		<text>So, you ready to save Mitay? I hope you don’t mind working together with some fellas I hired...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_0">
		<text>I have the PDA of Duty’s trader, Morgan. You interested?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_merc_pda_0">
		<text>I have a PDA which proves that Morgan has links to the mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_biochemist_oasis_give_artefact_12">
		<text>Actually... I’m gonna keep it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_11211">
		<text>I knew that the desire to advance science and do good in the world would triumph inside you in the end! All right, here is the plan. A stalker research group will take the measurements. Your job is to escort them, that is to protect them and guide them through difficult terrain. Good luck. The stalkers are waiting for you outside.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_start_11">
		<text>Howdy, stalker. Surprised to see an old man here? He-he. I came here with the boys for a change of scenery. I fix equipment and sometimes people too...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_start_12">
		<text>Now that you’re here, what can I do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_about_0">
		<text>How did you get to Pripyat?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_about_1">
		<text>Garry showed me the way. Those stalker fellas have been planning to come here for a long time, but they didn’t feel like dealing with the military. As soon as Garry said the army had taken off, I didn’t think twice about it. Have no fear, Uncle Yar is here! Hah!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_0">
		<text>I need medical assistance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_1">
		<text>Let this old man have a look...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_111">
		<text>There we go, you’ll live. If you get any swelling, just take a leak on it - I hear that helps.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_2">
		<text>You look healthy enough to me! You must be pulling an old man's leg, hah...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_barmen_start_dialog_11">
		<text>Welcome to my humble abode of pleasure and joy. You after joy, pleasure or both in equal measure?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_bandit_payment_dialog_1111">
		<text>Well, the boys are always saying that I'm too kind, like a fairy godmother, so you best be happy about this... I ain’t gonna be so kind next time. Now get out of here, loser!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_111113">
		<text>I’ve been there already. The bandits are dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_give_duty_1111131">
		<text>Wow, you’re hardcore! Thank you so much! Here, take this money - it was meant to pay the debt off but now it’ll go to someone who actually deserves it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_back_1_1">
		<text>Wow, you’re hardcore! Thank you so much! Keep the money that was meant to pay off the debt. Now it’ll go to someone who deserves it!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_1">
		<text>Our scanners registered unusual activity north of here... Judging by the received data, I expect that the anomalous formation there is unstable. Unfortunately, I can’t say any more than that from here. We need to conduct research in the field... The only thing I can say is that regular stalker detectors won’t be able to detect the anomaly - you’ll need a Svarog, one of our own inventions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_results_2">
		<text>Scanners continue to register unstable anomalous activity north of here. If you have something better than a regular stalker detector, a Svarog, for example, you could try to conduct research in the field.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_1">
		<text>Only from the swamp anomalous area so far. Despite this, Novikov has already found a practical application for it. Thank you for the work you have done and we look forward to the second batch of results.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_2">
		<text>Only from the anomalous area beyond Kopachy so far. Despite this, Novikov has already found a practical application for it. Thank you for the work you have done and we look forward to the second batch of results.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_scan_anomaly_complete_3">
		<text>Of course. I received the full results. To be honest, the volume of data that was produced is so great that it will take weeks if not months to process it fully. Despite this, Novikov has already found excellent practical uses for it. Thank you very much for your help.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_1">
		<text>No, nothing like that has happened here. Hrm... I did see one suspicious guy very recently though. I went for a walk and on my way back I spotted a stalker leaving Yanov. As soon as he clocked me, he started being rude for no reason and said something about knowing where I live or some shit like that. I just ignored him at the time, ‘cause I thought he was drunk or something but now that I think about it, it’s pretty dodgy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_11">
		<text>Where did he go?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_111">
		<text>North-east. I heard some shots being fired over there but that’s pretty normal around here. Ask Zulu - he’s in his tower day and night, so he might have seen something.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_112">
		<text>North-east. He probably went to the substation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_tech_b202_about_stole_13">
		<text>I see.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_vano_help_dialog_15">
		<text>What’s up, friend?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_how_are_you_0">
		<text>How are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_stalker_vano_pripyat_how_are_you_1">
		<text>I’m doing good. I mean, it ain’t easy but we’ll make it out of here. Together we can do anything!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_how_are_you_0">
		<text>How are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_leader_pripyat_how_are_you_1">
		<text>I’m not sure... I don’t feel great here. I have a feeling I need to move on. I might leave soon...don’t hold it against me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b220_trapper_bloodsucker_lair_hunted_0">
		<text>I wiped out the bloodsucker lair at Zaton. Completely.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_stalker_prisoner_free_actor_dialog_11">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_stalker_medik_need_health_care_11">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_contract_11">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_freedom_yar_pripyat_healing_11">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_employ_stalkers_12">
		<text>I need people to take measurements in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_employ_stalkers_12">
		<text>I need measurements to be taken in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_drunk_0">
		<text>Who’s that sleeping beauty?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_artefacts_1">
		<text>You found the artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_stalker_assistant_bunker_boredom_1">
		<text>You bet! There's nothing to do here - all we've got for entertainment is this backgammon board. This isn’t Pripyat... Man, if only I could complete this friggin’ contract, that’s where I’d be!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_stalker_tech_main_info_2">
		<text>[continue...]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b106_info_about_soroka_1112">
		<text>You can go to the quarry - that’s where Splinter died. Just before he passed on he told me that Flint stole his loot and left him to die in an anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_accuse_1111">
		<text>His name was Splinter. He walked into a gas anomaly and you ran off with his artifact. As you can see, he was able to tell me everything before he died.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_2">
		<text>I’m not going to ask where you got this from. Let’s make this simple: I’ll buy this PDA from you for 4,000. I’ve long been curious as to what our supply officer is doing when he’s not at work...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_duty_leader_b207_hiding_place_211">
		<text>Let’s have a look... Wow, what a piece of shit! Not only was he selling them our weapons, he handed the warehouse over to Freedom!!! Damn, we’ll have to organize a friendly meet & greet team right away.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_211">
		<text>Let’s have a look... I don't believe this shit! We knew about the warehouse and we even planned to pay a visit, but we didn't have a clue about the alarm because that scumbag didn’t say a word about it. Wait a second, I’ll warn the boys.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a6_freedom_leader_b207_hiding_place_2">
		<text>Well, I’ll give you 4,000 out of pure curiosity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b15_zulus_group_soldier_about_1">
		<text>Well, he ain't exactly a storm trooper but he can handle a gun just fine. He’s always got a sour look on his face though, as if his rations ain’t nothing but lemons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_scientist_nuclear_physicist_bubble_0">
		<text>I found a strange anomaly at the old cooling tower.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
