<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_descr">
		<text>The .45 caliber full metal jacket round has enjoyed popularity for more than a hundred years thanks to its heavy bullet and a relatively small propelling charge. As a result, the bullet in this round is relatively slow but highly accurate and provides considerable stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>.45 ACP Hydrashock rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_descr">
		<text>This unusual .45 ACP caliber round is comprised of a jacketed soft point bullet with an expanding hollow and a steel core.  It is a combination of jacketed expanding soft point and armor piercing bullets, benefiting, from the advantages of both and, suffering from their downsides.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>.45 Hydro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70 shot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_descr">
		<text>Standard 12-caliber round filled with 6 mm shot. Highly lethal at close range. Only suitable for use with smoothbore weapons.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12x70 shot </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76 slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_descr">
		<text>This heavy 12 caliber slug round is normally used for hunting big game, but is also good for other purposes. Instead of piercing, this hefty slug simply crushes through armor. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76 slug</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.45x39 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_descr">
		<text>Military 5.45x39 7H22 caliber armor-piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries. The bullet contains a hard-alloy armor piercing penetrator. Effective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.45x39 AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_descr">
		<text>Military 5.45x39 7H10 caliber improved piercing round for automatic rifles of Warsaw Pact countries. Provides better accuracy than the 7.62 caliber round thanks to reduced recoil and a 100 meter increase in range.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_descr">
		<text>A common NATO military 5.56x45 caliber armor piercing round, known under its SS190/M855 index, widely used by Western security agencies and special services. Effective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_descr">
		<text>A standard issue NATO 5.56x45 caliber round specially designed for accurate automatic fire. Provides good ballistic characteristics, having been designed on the basis of a hunting round. Widely known under its SS109 index.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54 mm 7H1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_descr">
		<text>A 7.62 caliber sniper round with a steel penetrator specially designed for the SVD. Unlike the machine gun round, the 7H1 provides tight groupings and excellent penetration characteristics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7.62x54 7H1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54 mm PP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_descr">
		<text>Cheap 7.62 caliber machine gun round. Its design makes it unsuitable for sniper rifles, so it is used only with the RP-74 machine gun.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x54 PP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9x18 mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_descr">
		<text>A full metal jacket round with a steel penetrator and a lead core under a metal jacket. Provides good stopping power but is ineffective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>9x18 mm +P+ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_descr">
		<text>This round contains a bullet with enhanced stopping power, while its European +P+ designation indicates "overpressure ammunition" with a 30% increase in muzzle velocity. Ineffective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9x18 +P+ </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_descr">
		<text>This basic 9x19 caliber round with a jacketed bullet has good characteristics while being simple to produce. The round is popular due to the fact that international conventions prohibit the use of expanding ammunition in combat. Ineffective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9x19 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19 mm JHP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_descr">
		<text>This 9x19 caliber jacketed hollow point bullet with an expanding hollow provides high stopping power and low ricochet propensity. Used by police and for self-defense. Ineffective against body armor due to its low penetration potential.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 JHP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_descr">
		<text>The SP-6 is a subsonic assault rifle round with a jacketed soft point bullet with a hard steel core that protrudes from the casing. Requires a silencer for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries. Effective against body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_descr">
		<text>The SP-5 is a subsonic sniper round with a bimetallic casing. The round contains a steel core with a gap behind it that is filled with lead. Requires a silencer for stealth firing. Used by special services of Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9x39 mm SP-5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>Batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209">
		<text>M203 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_descr">
		<text>40 mm grenade for the M203 underbarrel grenade launcher. This round has a 5 meter kill zone. Also suitable for use in the FT-200M integrated grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_s">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b">
		<text>OG-7V warhead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_descr">
		<text>Fragmentation warhead for anti-personnel warfare used with the RPG-7u grenade launcher. The main purpose of the warhead is to kill enemies in cover outside the range of hand grenades using the RPG-7u launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>OG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25">
		<text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_descr">
		<text>Regular fragmentation grenade for the GP-25 Koster underbarrel grenade launcher. This round has a 5 meter kill zone. The VOG-25 grenade is also used in the Tunder S14 complex and Bulldog 6 revolver-type grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope">
		<text>PSO-1m scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_descr">
		<text>A common Soviet-made 5.0x fixed zoom optical scope with a range scale. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount, which is standard in Warsaw Pact countries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_detector">
		<text>PSS-2x scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_detector_descr">
		<text>A 5.0x fixed zoom optical scope with a built-in heat visor used to identify heat sources typical of the human body. Designed for use by special forces. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision">
		<text>NSPU-3 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_night_vision_descr">
		<text>An image intensifier night vision 5.0x fixed zoom scope for combat in darkness. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT 4x scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom_descr">
		<text>An adjustable long-range 1.6-4x zoom scope that can use automatic adjustment to provide greater fire effectiveness. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_descr">
		<text>A 4x fixed zoom scope produced primarily in Western countries. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail. Often used for accurate fire from small arms at medium to long range.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk">
		<text>SUSAT Twilight x1.6 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_dusk_descr">
		<text>An optical SUSAT 1.6x higher contrast scope for combat in reduced lighting conditions. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision">
		<text>SUSAT Night x4 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_night_vision_descr">
		<text>A 4.0x fixed zoom scope with a night vision device for long range combat in darkness. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6">
		<text>SUSAT 1.6x scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_x1.6_descr">
		<text>An optical SUSAT 1.6x scope for combat at short to medium range. Attached to weapons by means of the NATO-standard Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7">
		<text>PSU-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_x2.7_descr">
		<text>A 2.7x optical scope for urban combat at medium range. Attached to weapons by means of a dovetail mount.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_silencer">
		<text>Silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_silencer_descr">
		<text>An effective silencer which can be modified on the go as required. The body of the silencer around the barrel contains a roll of fine brass mesh, while the front comprises a set of metal diaphragms with holes for the bullet to pass through. The set includes adaptors and sealants for most weapons. Normally used to thin out enemy ranks without drawing attention.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_f1">
		<text>F1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_f1_descr">
		<text>A defensive hand grenade, with fragments capable of piercing medium level body armor. The grenade has a 7 meter kill radius. Stalkers get F1 grenades from trading with the military, who write them off as having been used for fighting mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher">
		<text>GP-25 Koster</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_descr">
		<text>A single shot, front loaded, rifled underbarrel grenade launcher for assault rifles made in Warsaw Pact countries. The firing mechanism is self-cocking, with a manual safety catch and automatic shot prevention if incorrectly installed onto a rifle. Uses VOG-25 grenades.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_launcher_m203_descr">
		<text>A modified M203 grenade launcher that has been shortened by three inches, attached to weapons by means of a Picatinny Rail. Thanks to a changed mount, this grenade launcher is widely used around the world.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_rgd5_descr">
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small kill zone of 5 meters. Often used by stalkers to "smoke out" mutants due to its relatively low cost.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke">
		<text>Smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_smoke_descr">
		<text>A hand smoke grenade. Used to put up smoke screens. Once the grenade is thrown it takes 10 seconds for the smoke screen to expand.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_knife">
		<text>Knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan">
		<text>AC-96/2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74">
		<text>AKM-74/2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u">
		<text>AKM-74/2U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta">
		<text>Martha</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16">
		<text>Sawed-off Shotgun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_bm16_descr">
		<text>A sawed-off hunting shotgun with two side-by-side barrels, making it lighter and more compact than a full shotgun. One of the most popular weapons among bandits due to its combination of ease of concealment and extreme effectiveness in close combat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911">
		<text>Kora-919</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble">
		<text>Steppe Eagle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_desert_eagle_nimble_descr">
		<text>A hand-made pistol based on the Black Kite design. The components are finely tuned to achieve incredible accuracy for a handgun of this type.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle">
		<text>Black Kite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000">
		<text>FT-200M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort">
		<text>Fora-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g36">
		<text>GP37</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss">
		<text>Gauss rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza">
		<text>Tunder S14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_descr">
		<text>This assault rifle combined with a grenade launcher, which is similar to the AKM series, was specially developed for rapid response units. The main differences are its 9x39 caliber ammunition, bullpup layout and extensive configuration options. This weapon is highly valued by military stalkers due to its ability to kill enemies wearing body armor behind improvised cover at a distance during urban combat, as well as its excellent stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble">
		<text>Storm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_groza_nimble_descr">
		<text>An experimental version of an assault rifle and grenade launcher system, a Russian modification of the standard Tunder S14, this weapon was specially designed for units operating in the Zone. Notable for its increased magazine capacity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa">
		<text>HPSS-1m</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_hpsa_descr">
		<text>A modified model of a pistol from the first half of the 20th century, which is as reliable, powerful and accurate as the original. Pistols of this series deserve their reputation as one of the best handguns of the 20th century and are in great demand in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85">
		<text>IL 86</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300">
		<text>TRs 301</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5">
		<text>Viper 5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_descr">
		<text>This submachine gun has gained popularity around the world thanks to its reliability, ease of use and accuracy. Over the last few decades the Viper 5 was in service with special armed forces and police units worldwide. Not surprisingly, having flooded the global black markets, it eventually made its way to the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble">
		<text>Frasier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_mp5_nimble_descr">
		<text>A submachine gun prototype based on the excellent Viper 5 model. Designed as a next generation close quarter combat weapon, it benefits from a higher caliber, rate of fire and accuracy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pb">
		<text>PB-1s</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus">
		<text>Zulu's RP-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pkm_zulus_descr">
		<text>This weapon was previously owned by Zulu. Its special features include an enlarged ammo box and a particularly reliable retracting mechanism design. The modifications meant an increase in the weapon's weight, but that wasn't a problem for the last owner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm">
		<text>PMm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor">
		<text>Honorary PMm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_actor_descr">
		<text>An ancient PMm received by Degtyarev as a reward for "Successful execution of highly dangerous state orders, as well as valor and courage shown in the line of duty."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta">
		<text>Eliminator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6">
		<text>Bulldog-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rg6_descr">
		<text>This revolver-type grenade launcher uses six rifled front-loading barrels, identical to underbarrel launcher attachments. The drum is also front-loading. Widely used for rapid suppression of enemy firing positions and, when in the open, attacking defended fixed targets or fighting particularly tough monsters.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rp">
		<text>RP-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rp_descr">
		<text>This belt-fed machine gun is a portable modification with a complex two-stage feeding system. Despite its weight and low precision, this LMG has found admirers in the Zone. Used primarily to fight off outnumbering enemy forces during faction conflicts and clear out mutant lairs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7u</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220">
		<text>SIP-t M200</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble">
		<text>Alpine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_nimble_descr">
		<text>A unique model of the SIP-t M200 handgun. Part of a small limited edition made for an unidentified special forces unit. The model benefits from an increased magazine capacity, a high durability steel barrel and an ultradurable polymer receiver.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550">
		<text>SGI-5k</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_descr">
		<text>A relatively new assault rifle that has quickly found admirers around the world, despite lacking a "trendy" design. Weapons of this series are one of the best in their class, renowned for their reliability, accuracy and ease of use.  Despite being relatively difficult to obtain in the Zone, this assault rifle is often ordered by experienced stalkers at considerable expense.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok">
		<text>Strelok's SGI-5k</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig550_strelok_descr">
		<text>A Swiss-made SGI-5k assault rifle. Although it is hardly new, it is clear that the previous owner took good care of it: the weapon has been taken apart and put back together, with every component fine-tuned for optimum performance, increasing stopping power. The letter "S" has been carved into the stock, along with 16 small notches.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12">
		<text>SPSA-14 </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2">
		<text>SPSA-AUT</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_m2_descr">
		<text>The SPSA-AUT self-cocking shotgun is made only in Duty workshops. This weapon is intended for fighting large groups of mutants. Its improved feeding mechanism ensures a high rate of fire and the magazine capacity has been increased to 10 rounds. Uses 12x70 caliber rounds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble">
		<text>Carabineer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_nimble_descr">
		<text>An army shotgun designed specifically for assault units on the basis of the SPSA-14. Capable of automatic fire like its predecessor, but provides better recoil compensation thanks to a balanced shock free system.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd">
		<text>SVDm-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_descr">
		<text>An army sniper rifle that has been on the market for more than fifty years and has earned its reputation for exceptional reliability and ease of use. The SVDm-2 is normally used by the army to improve the effective range of its units, but stalkers respect this weapon for its armor-piercing properties, which allow it to penetrate mutant hide and army body armor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble">
		<text>Lynx</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svd_nimble_descr">
		<text>A hand-assembled version of the SVDm-2 sniper rifle. No different in appearance, it nonetheless provides an ideal combination of accuracy and stopping power.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu">
		<text>SVUmk-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble">
		<text>SVU2-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_nimble_descr">
		<text>This shortened sniper rifle with an increase rate of fire is the next step in the evolution of the SVUmk-2 sniper rifle. This weapon used to belong to Max, the legendary guardian of Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34">
		<text>Hunting shotgun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_toz34_descr">
		<text>This extremely common over-and-under hunting shotgun can offer better protection against mutants than a pistol, thanks to its accuracy and stopping power. Used mostly by rookies on the outskirts of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel">
		<text>Unidentified weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_umirotvoritel_descr">
		<text>An unknown weapon, the firing mechanism of which has not been established. The weapon appears faulty - squeezing the trigger doesn't do anything.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp">
		<text>UDP Compact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_descr">
		<text>Impeccable reliability and durability combined with excellent accuracy are the main noteworthy features of this weapon. Its minor drawbacks include its considerable size, relatively high center of gravity and massive bolt, which make it difficult to conceal but do not outweigh the weapon's positive features. The weapon is especially popular with the Zone's veterans.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble">
		<text>March</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_usp_nimble_descr">
		<text>A compact, large caliber pistol with short bolt movement and lightweight bolt assembly. Used to belong to a mercenary called Wolfhound. Appears to be a modified UDP Compact pistol.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_val">
		<text>SA Avalanche</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez">
		<text>Vintar BC </text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_descr">
		<text>A special military sniper rifle purpose-built for silent, flashless sniping during special operations where early detection of the shooter may be critical. The Vintar BC provides high armor-piercing capability and stopping power, as well as being equipped with an integrated sniper and optical scope. Highly rated by many stalkers despite its small magazine.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble">
		<text>Tide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_vintorez_nimble_descr">
		<text>A weapon made for military units on the basis of the silent sniper rifle. The rifle has higher stopping power than the Vintar BC, its predecessor, at the expense of its rate of fire, which allows the shooter to eliminate enemy forces one by one without revealing his position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_walther">
		<text>Walker P9m</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300">
		<text>Chaser 13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_descr">
		<text>A Western smoothbore shotgun that is extremely popular around the world thanks to its amazing reliability and faster reloading speed. Particularly valued for its functionality by the Zone's hunters. All of its parts are coated with an anticorrosion compound.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper">
		<text>Predator</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_wincheaster1300_trapper_descr">
		<text>A tailor-made pump-action shotgun which used to belong to Trapper. The hunter's only requirement in respect of his weapon was that it needed to kill predators in one shot. This philosophy was based on the belief that no matter how many people an animal had killed, it was still just an animal, and thus should not suffer.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_cardan">
		<text>Homemade batteries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_addon_scope_susat_custom">
		<text>SUSAT Mera scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_abakan_descr">
		<text>A modern assault rifle developed as a replacement for the ageing AKM 74/2. The main difference is its high speed 2-round burst firing mode, which allows two bullets to be fired at exactly the same spot on a target up to 100 meters away. This significantly increases the likelihood of hitting the target in comparison to the 1 round firing mode, which considerably improves kill potential, stopping power and armor piercing capability.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74_descr">
		<text>This weapon, designed in 1974, signaled the adoption of small caliber and low impulse rounds by Warsaw Pact countries. A descendant of the most popular assault rifle in the world, the AKM-74/2 has an even bigger muzzle brake, resulting in a reduction of what was already manageable recoil. This facilitates better accuracy and groupings, especially when fired in fast single shots or bursts. As before, the rifle is very simple and reliable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_ak74u_descr">
		<text>Despite being similar to submachine guns in size, weight and tactical purpose, this weapon is classified as an assault rifle due to the fact that its internal mechanism is identical to that of the AKM 74/2. The weapon is notable for its mobility in close quarters and high armor-penetration capacity, while its drawbacks are its short effective range, despite the relatively long bullet range, a tendency to overheat and high ricochet propensity.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_colt1911_descr">
		<text>An improved version of a classic automatic pistol, which passed all the major armed conflicts of the 20th century with flying colors and entered the new millennium with confidence. Produced by dozens if not hundreds of arms manufacturers around the world in both standard and modified configurations. The weapon’s only drawback, its mediocre magazine capacity, is largely compensated by the hard-hitting ammo it uses.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_eagle_descr">
		<text>The ultimate hand cannon - bulky, heavy and highly lethal. Developed as a specialized weapon for hunting medium-sized and large game, as well as for shooting competitions involving firing at steel body targets at distances over 50 meters. Its limited use in the Zone can be attributed to its price, size and weight, which are all double those of other pistols.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fn2000_descr">
		<text>This futuristic-looking weapon with a bullpup layout is actually a mass produced modular system, comprising a rifle & grenade complex with a computerized fire control system and a 40-mm grenade launcher. Despite its bulky appearance, the weapon is highly ergonomic, easy to use and benefits from good technical characteristics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_fort_descr">
		<text>A Ukrainian-made pistol predominantly used by law enforcement organizations. Provides higher accuracy, better ergonomics and has a larger magazine than the PMm.  These pistols make it into the Zone in large numbers thanks to the sale of defective weapons, which suffer from technical miscalculations in early design models. Despite this, the pistol is in demand among stalkers thanks to its good combat characteristics.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_g36_descr">
		<text>A new addition to the Western-made assault rifle family, which differs significantly from previous models in the series built on an automatic foundation with a semi-open bolt assembly, this weapon is more like American automatic gas-operated assault rifles with a short-stroke gas piston system. These changes ensure that the rifle is a first-rate example of a modern weapon - lightweight, reliable and ergonomic.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_l85_descr">
		<text>This rifle’s considerable number of drawbacks caused most of these weapons to be modernized, with the retired stock making its way to the Zone via the black market. The rifle's main advantages are its built-in 4x scope, high single-shot accuracy and reliable upgrade technology. When the weapon is fired in bursts, its accuracy decreases significantly and the rifle's basic internal mechanisms become somewhat unreliable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_lr300_descr">
		<text>A new step in the development of this famous weapon family. The changes were made to the upper half of the steel construction comprising the barrel, gas tube and bolt assembly, reducing the weapon’s weight, improving ergonomics and its gas system. The weapon is highly accurate, although its propensity to catch dirt makes it a poor choice for the Zone’s difficult conditions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pb_descr">
		<text>This pistol was developed in the second half of the 20th century on the basis of the PMm for use by special forces and scouting units. The front of the pistol’s barrel is covered with an integrated silencer, while the bolt mechanism is short, which prevents a back-moving spring from being located inside it, and it is therefore situated in the weapon’s handle. Morally obsolete, the weapon is still effective in the right hands.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_pm_descr">
		<text>This Soviet legacy is the most common pistol in the Zone and is one of the best compact self-defense handguns available. It is small, highly reliable, easy to use and maintain in working order. It also suffers from several drawbacks, including its short range, low firing accuracy and poor stopping power, while also losing out to modern pistols in its class in terms of weight and magazine size.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_protecta_descr">
		<text>A smoothbore combat revolver-type shotgun intended to provide extreme firepower for militarized units. The weapon benefits from a large magazine and a high effective rate of fire, but its bulkiness and considerable weight, combined with a long reload time, are the price to be paid for these advantages. Rare in the Zone and is used primarily to clear closed spaces of mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_rpg7_descr">
		<text>This grenade launcher from the 1960s made its way into the Zone from army depots. The weapon is a smoothbore single-shot recoilless launch system with an open-rear tube. Comes with a PGO-7 x2.7 optical scope. Although its huge size and weight make it an unlikely choice for stalkers, given its huge destructive power and ease of use, it has found admirers in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_sig220_descr">
		<text>The only remaining mass produced model of a globally renowned pistol, this weapon has earned a reputation for its excellent ergonomics and accuracy, and while its magazine is relatively small, it benefits from powerful ammo and a mechanism that functions like a Swiss watch. Some believe the SIP-t M200 to be the best mass produced .45ACP caliber handgun there is and it has certainly got a following among experienced stalkers and mercenaries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_spas12_descr">
		<text>This special purpose smoothbore automatic shotgun was designed in the second half of the 20th century and comes with pump-action and self-cocking firing modes. Used as an all-purpose weapon by the police and assault troops. Notable for its reliability and tactical flexibility. Despite its large weight, complex mechanism and considerable cost it is in demand in the Zone due to its effectiveness against mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_svu_descr">
		<text>A modernized version of the SVDm-2 sniper rifle in a compact bullpup design made on the order of rapid response forces. It allows faster precision fire and is considerably lighter, while its single shot firing accuracy at short and medium range is similar to that of its predecessor. These qualities have earned it the admiration of countless stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_val_descr">
		<text>A modified version of the silent Vintar BC sniper rifle, this assault rifle was designed as a special forces weapon. The rifle’s primary purpose is effective fire against enemies employing modern personal protection equipment without disclosing the shooter’s location. Thanks to its integrated silencer and 9x39 caliber round with a heavy subsonic bullet, the weapon’s noise and muzzle flash have been reduced to a minimum.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_gauss_descr">
		<text>A super-accurate hi-tech weapon known as item 62, this rifle was developed in secret laboratories located inside the Zone. The weapon operates by accelerating bullets to extremely high speeds using a system of electromagnets, which provides incredible stopping power with virtually no recoil.  The weapon is powered by using capsulated artifact fragments in the batteries.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_beretta_descr">
		<text>Martha pistols enjoy the reputation of a relatively reliable, albeit somewhat cumbersome weapon, around the world. In service with armed forces and police across the ocean, as well as various military and law enforcement organizations worldwide.  The pistol is equally popular with members of the underworld, thanks to its powerful round and magazine capacity. Marthas found in the Zone are usually dated, probably from retired stock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_wpn_walther_descr">
		<text>An excellent Western pistol known for its reliability, high capacity magazine and good accuracy, as well as being among the most ergonomic handguns in its class. One of the most widely used pistols in the Zone, both among professionals and rookies who can afford it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_descr">
		<text>Batteries that use a capsulated fragment of the Flash artifact as their power source. Manufactured using hi-tech equipment.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_cardan_descr">
		<text>These lower-capacity cells use capsulated fragments of the Flash artifact as their power source. Their lower capacity is due to makeshift production conditions and lack of specialized equipment.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
