<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="mp_autostation">
		<text>Vehicle station</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_large">
		<text>A weird place. This silent building likely conceals its share of secrets, but stalkers are drawn here for another reason - a generous supply of artifacts found in this high risk / high reward area. Think fast and act fast, then luck will surely be on your side.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_short">
		<text>A weird place. This silent building likely conceals its share of secrets, but stalkers are drawn here for another reason - a generous supply of artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_large">
		<text>A depot, located at the entrance to the Zone. Its tractors, buses and trucks have stopped in their tracks for good... No artifacts have been spotted here so far, but the place is popular with raiders, who hunt down rookies and kill them for loot. Seek cover in buildings and behind vehicles, and watch out for enemies on rooftops!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_short">
		<text>A depot, located at the entrance to the Zone. Its tractors, buses and trucks have stopped in their tracks for good...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_autostation_large">
		<text>Deserted depot building and adjacent territory. Some equipment and supplies can be found here - if you look hard enough. Watch out for powerful anomalies and snipers on the roof of the depot - that is a great vantage point overseeing almost every approach to the area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_autostation_short">
		<text>Deserted depot building and adjacent territory. Watch out for powerful anomalies and enemy snipers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_large">
		<text>An enigmatic and fascinating place. This pool was built to conduct experiments on someone or something, but its exact purpose will forever remain a mystery. There are no artifacts to speak of, so stalkers may only be drawn here by the remnants of bizarre assemblies and devices.  Watch the rooftops carefully and keep in mind the area's extremely high radiation levels.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_short">
		<text>An enigmatic and fascinating place. This pool was built to conduct experiments on someone or something, but its exact purpose will forever remain a mystery.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_darkvalley_large">
		<text>This dangerous part of the Dark Valley comprises a long street and a deserted institute. Who knows what they used to teach at the institute? The only thing to be learned here these days is survival! Oh, and keep a close eye on the roofs...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_darkvalley_short">
		<text>This dangerous part of the Dark Valley comprises a long street and a deserted institute...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_large">
		<text>This dreary desolate factory is the resting place of countless stalkers. A host of anomalies await visitors at every step, but they still flood in, attracted as though by a magnet to its valuable artifacts. Beware of radiation!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_short">
		<text>This dreary desolate factory is the resting place of countless stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_firestation_large">
		<text>The fire station whose entire forces were thrown to salvage the Chernobyl NPP in 1986. The tower is an excellent vantage point, overseeing the surroundings near and far.  Very few visit the upper floors of buildings and basements, though that may all be for the better. For some time now the Zone's factions have been at each others' throats in this area - fighting for this strategic position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_firestation_short">
		<text>The fire station whose entire forces were thrown to salvage the Chernobyl NPP in 1986. The station is an excellent tactical position.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_large">
		<text>Part of a huge junkyard, where heaps of radioactive refuse were dumped after the 1986 disaster, full of decrepit cranes and various equipment. Other local attractions include old dilapidated buildings and a huge hangar. Proximity to the Cordon and a relative abundance of artifacts draws in stalkers that prefer easy pickings.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_short">
		<text>Part of a huge junkyard, where heaps of radioactive refuse and equipment were dumped after the 1986 disaster.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_limansk_large">
		<text>A small district of the enigmatic city of Limansk - abandoned apartment blocks and one half-constructed building between them. When several expensive artifacts were found here, the news spread all over the Zone all too quickly. A few roads were opened to Limansk, and the shooting hasn't stopped for a minute ever since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_limansk_short">
		<text>A small district of the enigmatic city of Limansk - abandoned apartment blocks and one half-constructed building between them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_large">
		<text>An abandoned, godforsaken village in the depths of the Zone. A small, shallow, rusty lake, home to scores of wrecked vehicles, fills you with subconscious fear of the Zone's reality. Beware of snipers, but remember: the Zone favors the brave.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_short">
		<text>An abandoned, godforsaken village in the depths of the Zone. A small, shallow, rusty lake, home to scores of wrecked vehicles, fills you with subconscious fear of the Zone's reality.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_large">
		<text>An abandoned army base with forever immobile trucks and APCs, dilapidated headquarters and barracks. The deserted look, however, is deceptive: this is a real artifact goldmine, which means the enemy could be lurking around any corner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_short">
		<text>An abandoned army base with forever immobile trucks and APCs, dilapidated headquarters and barracks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_large">
		<text>This old village is a truly sinister place. If you're brave enough to come here, be ready to avoid a welcome in the form of a bullet to the head. No spot is safe here, so may your scope and silencer be with you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_short">
		<text>This old village is a truly sinister place. You may have made it here, but this is no time to relax.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pool_large">
		<text>This is no pool - more like a blood bath. Echoes of bullets, explosions and shrieks of the dying roam its tiled corridors... Few stalkers know the way here, but even fewer know the way out.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pool_short">
		<text>This is no pool - more like a blood bath. Echoes of bullets and explosions roam its tiled corridors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railraod_short">
		<text>A small railway station near the Rostok factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railroad_large">
		<text>A small railway station near the Rostok factory, full of rusted rail cars and locomotives, forever stopped in their tracks. An abundance of artifacts draws in fearless stalkers from all corners of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rembasa_large">
		<text>A repair base in the vicinity of a small village. All the vehicles that were in order got lifted to deal with the aftermath of Chernobyl. Over time, the rest of the equipment has been ransacked for spare parts. The area is full of dangers, such as treacherous swamps and contaminated reeds, in which, if you're lucky, you might find something truly valuable.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rembasa_short">
		<text>A repair base in the vicinity of a small village. The area is full of dangers, such as treacherous swamps and contaminated reeds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_large">
		<text>Piles of metal rust idly behind concrete walls. Before the turn of the century, the plant was in constant operation with the accompaniment of socialist slogans spewed forth from loudspeakers, but the building was abandoned long ago.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_short">
		<text>Old deserted plant: silent piles of metal behind concrete walls are all that’s left.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_sport_center_large">
		<text>A sports center in Pripyat located not far from the deserted school. The types of sport practiced here have changed greatly since 1986, as well as the number of enthusiasts willing to participate. Stalkers are drawn here by dubious fame, loot, and artifacts...and sometimes remain here forever.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_sport_center_short">
		<text>A sports center in Pripyat located not far from the deserted school.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_training_camp_large">
		<text>A very strange place. Many laugh at stalkers who claim to have seen it but it exists nonetheless. Gravitational anomalies have torn up the ground creating an alien landscape. The area is dominated by three huge towers, remnants of military hardware and floating islands of earth, ripped out of the ground.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_training_camp_short">
		<text>A very strange place. Gravitational anomalies have torn up the ground creating an alien landscape...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_large">
		<text>These were the fringes of the Rostok factory before Duty settled down here.  An eerie place, which is nonetheless rich in artifacts.  Every empty hangar or warehouse is full of deadly perils.  Be extremely careful and keep close watch over the white tower...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_short">
		<text>These were the fringes of the Rostok factory before Duty settled down here.  An eerie place, which is nonetheless rich in artifacts. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pripyat_large">
		<text>Few dare to venture into the deserted city of Pripyat, formerly home to employees working at the CNPP. Despite this, the streets of the dead city have been troubled recently by fierce gunfire in a small part of the town between the Prometheus movie theater, the pier and houses on Kurchatova Street.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pripyat_short">
		<text>A small part of Pripyat between the Prometheus movie theater, the pier and houses on Kurchatova Street saw fierce fighting between the few who made it into the dead city.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
