<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="jup_a10_actor_agree_back_vano_duties_name">
		<text>Debts: take money to the bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_actor_agree_back_vano_duties_text">
		<text>Vano owes the bandits money for a suit and can't pay it back because the interest builds up too quickly. He's asked you to deal with this problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_actor_back_vano_duties_name">
		<text>Debts: return to Vano</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_actor_back_vano_duties_text">
		<text>Tell Vano how his debt repayment went.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_kill_all_bandit_name">
		<text>Debts: deal with the bandits</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a10_kill_all_bandit_text">
		<text>Repaying Vano's debts has gotten messy. Take out the bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_get_reward_name">
		<text>Hostage: receive your reward from Mitay's friends</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_get_reward_text">
		<text>Mitay has been freed. Meet his friends at the bar to receive your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_name">
		<text>Hostage: free Mitay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_not_ready_name">
		<text>Hostage: talk to Grizzly to make sure he's ready</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_not_ready_text">
		<text>You must talk to Grizzly before attempting to free the hostage.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_power_name">
		<text>Hostage: free Mitay by force</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_power_text">
		<text>You must eliminate the bandits to free a stalker called Mitay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_power_wait_name">
		<text>Hostage: meet the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_power_wait_text">
		<text>Stalkers will help you to free the hostage. You need to meet them at night to attack the bandits together.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_ransom_name">
		<text>Hostage: arrange a ransom payment for Mitay's release</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_ransom_text">
		<text>Arrange a ransom payment with the bandit leader to free a stalker called Mitay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_free_prisoner_text">
		<text>Free a stalker called Mitay, who was taken hostage by the bandits.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_guide_prisoner_name">
		<text>Hostage: lead Mitay out of the bandit camp</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_guide_prisoner_text">
		<text>The bandit camp is too dangerous to hang around in. You must escort Mitay outside the camp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_talk_with_prisoner_name">
		<text>Hostage: talk to Mitay</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a12_talk_with_prisoner_text">
		<text>Mitay is relatively safe. Talk to him about your next course of action.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a9_way_to_pripyat_tech_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: talk to the technician about the underpass</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_a9_way_to_pripyat_tech_text">
		<text>The documents you found make it clear that there is an underground underpass located underneath the Jupiter plant that leads to Pripyat. The underpass has no power, is filled with gas, and the entrance to it has been blocked. You must find a technician who can activate the generator and open the underpass lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_at_text">
		<text>The memory module is in expert hands. You must wait for it to be unblocked.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_name">
		<text>UAV: unblock the memory module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_nitro_name">
		<text>UAV: collect the memory module from Nitro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_novikov_name">
		<text>UAV: collect the memory module from Novikov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_repaired_by_nitro_text">
		<text>Nitro has unblocked the memory module. You should collect the module to see what information it contains.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_repaired_by_novikov_text">
		<text>Novikov has unblocked the memory module. You should collect the module to see what information it contains.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_started_text">
		<text>You managed to salvage a memory module from the UAV. It must be unblocked for you to access the information it holds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b10_ufo_memory_wait_name">
		<text>UAV: wait for the memory module to be unblocked</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_art_name">
		<text>Oasis: find proof</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_art_text">
		<text>The Oasis has been found and this place really does have healing properties. You need to find some proof to take back to the scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_artifact_back_name">
		<text>The Oasis: take proof to the scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_artifact_back_text">
		<text>The Oasis has been found and this place really does have healing properties. You need to take the artifact you found there to the scientists as proof.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_name">
		<text>The Oasis: check whether the legend is true</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b16_oasis_text">
		<text>Ozersky, the scientist from the bunker, asked you to try to find the Oasis, a legendary place in the Zone. According to rumors, there should be some healing waters there, but nobody really knows whether it exists or not.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_agreed_to_go_name">
		<text>Kopachy: go with Uncle Yar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_agreed_to_go_text">
		<text>Uncle Yar needs help with something. Go to Kopachy village with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_destroy_mercs_name">
		<text>Kopachy: eliminate the mercenaries</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_destroy_mercs_text">
		<text>Looks like Uncle Yar anticipated the mercenaries' arrival. You must eliminate them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_following_yar_name">
		<text>Kopachy: stay close to Uncle Yar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_following_yar_text">
		<text>Uncle Yar asked you to stay close to him and keep quiet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_talk_to_yar_name">
		<text>Kopachy: talk to Uncle Yar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b19_talk_to_yar_text">
		<text>The mercenaries are dead. You should talk to Uncle Yar to get an explanation of what happened.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_bring_art_back_name">
		<text>Intermittent psy-emissions: take the anomalous formation to the scientists</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_bring_art_back_text">
		<text>Take the sample you found to Hermann as agreed. It looks like this is the source of intermittent psy-emissions, an item that is half-transformed through anomalous exposure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_get_art_name">
		<text>Intermittent psy-emissions: investigate the source</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_get_art_text">
		<text>Investigate the tunnel for some kind of anomalous formation. The scientists believe that the intermittent psy-field has a source, which will probably resemble an artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_join_squad_name">
		<text>Intermittent psy-emissions: meet Topol's squad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_join_squad_text">
		<text>Topol's squad went to the tunnel with the intermittent psy-emissions and you must meet them there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_meet_squad_name">
		<text>Intermittent psy-emissions: talk to Topol</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b1_meet_squad_text">
		<text>Join Topol's squad to go to the tunnel with the intermittent psy-emissions. The agreement is that stalkers will guard the tunnel while you search for what the scientists want.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_brought_all_text">
		<text>You should take all the radio technical materials you found to Nitro.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_brought_some_text">
		<text>Nitro needs radio technical materials. You can give him what you already have or try to find more.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_name">
		<text>Radio equipment: find materials for Nitro</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_text">
		<text>Nitro needs radio technical materials. He says you should look for them at the cement factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_01_name">
		<text>Theft: find out who is responsible for the theft</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_01_text">
		<text>Ask stalkers at Yanov if they've seen anyone suspicious who could have stolen things from a personal box.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_02_name">
		<text>Theft: check the substation</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_02_text">
		<text>You need to check out the substation, as that's where the suspicious stalker who may be responsible for the theft was headed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_03_name">
		<text>Theft: take your things</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b202_actor_items_stolen_03_text">
		<text>All the items Snag stole should be in his stash in the sewers behind the substation.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b206_anomalous_grove_get_plant_name">
		<text>Anomalous plant: get a plant sample</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b206_anomalous_grove_get_plant_text">
		<text>An area filled with anomalous vegetation has appeared near the edge of the quarry. Ozersky has asked you to get a plant sample for his research.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b206_anomalous_grove_have_plant_name">
		<text>Anomalous plant: give the sample to Ozersky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b206_anomalous_grove_have_plant_text">
		<text>You must take the plant sample to Ozersky. In exchange, Ozersky will convince Hermann to hand over a scientific suit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b208_burers_hunt_kill_burers_name">
		<text>Hunting: eliminate unidentified mutants</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b208_burers_hunt_kill_burers_text">
		<text>A group of stalkers encountered unidentified mutants in the tunnels north of the Jupiter plant. Investigate the area and eliminate the mutants.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b208_burers_hunt_take_reward_name">
		<text>Hunting: get your reward for killing the mutants in the tunnel from Trapper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b208_burers_hunt_take_reward_text">
		<text>Mutants in the tunnels north of the Jupiter plant have been eliminated. You should inform Trapper and collect your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_1_name">
		<text>Hypothesis: place the scanner in the center of the landslide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_1_text">
		<text>Place the scanner in the center of the landslide to test Ozersky's hypothesis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_2_name">
		<text>Hypothesis: wait for the experiment to end</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_2_text">
		<text>The scanner is now in active mode and has begun to register mutant presence. You must wait until enough data has been collected to confirm or disprove the hypothesis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_3_name">
		<text>Hypothesis: take the scanner</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_3_text">
		<text>Enough data has been collected to confirm Ozersky's hypothesis. Take the scanner.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_4_name">
		<text>Hypothesis: give the scanner to Ozersky</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b209_hypotheses_4_text">
		<text>You must give the scanner to Ozersky. The data collected should be enough to confirm his hypothesis.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b211_kill_bloodsuckers_name">
		<text>Hunting: kill the swamp bloodsuckers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b211_kill_bloodsuckers_text">
		<text>A group of swamp bloodsuckers has been spotted in Fen, behind the cement factory. Local stalkers have asked you to eliminate them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b211_take_reward_name">
		<text>Hunting: get your reward for killing the swamp bloodsuckers from Trapper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b211_take_reward_text">
		<text>The swamp bloodsuckers are dead. You should collect the reward put up by local stalkers from Trapper.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b212_jupiter_kill_chimera_name">
		<text>Night hunt: kill the chimera</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b212_jupiter_kill_chimera_text">
		<text>Chimeras are nocturnal predators and nobody knows the whereabouts of this one's daytime lair. You must kill it at night when it comes out to hunt by the ventilation complex.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b212_jupiter_tell_animalboy_about_chimera_name">
		<text>Night hunt: tell Trapper that the chimera is dead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b212_jupiter_tell_animalboy_about_chimera_text">
		<text>The killer chimera is dead and Fox, the hunter, has been avenged. Tell Trapper about this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_2_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_2_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get two sets of tools: one for basic work and one for fine work. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_3_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_3_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get two sets of tools: one for basic work and one for calibration. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_1_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get a set of tools for basic work. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_2_3_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_2_3_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get two sets of tools: one for fine work and one for calibration. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_2_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_2_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get a set of tools for fine work. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_3_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_get_tools_3_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get a set of tools for calibration. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_mechanic_toolkit_search_name">
		<text>Tools: bring Nitro tools</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b217_mechanic_toolkit_search_text">
		<text>Nitro has asked you to get three sets of tools: one for basic work, one for fine work and one for calibration. The technician will pay you for the tools and will be able to perform more advanced weapon and armor modifications.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_actor_outfit_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: find a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_actor_outfit_text">
		<text>You will need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to go through the Pripyat 1 underpass, as it has been filled with carbon dioxide mixed in with an unknown substance.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_monolith_guide_to_zulus_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: take Strider to see Zulu</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_monolith_guide_to_zulus_text">
		<text>You must take Strider to see Zulu and introduce him as a new member of the squad. Zulu may not be welcoming if a fighter wearing a Monolith suit shows up on his own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_monolith_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: talk to Strider about a protective suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_monolith_text">
		<text>The Pripyat 1 underpass has been filled with carbon dioxide mixed in with an unknown substance. You must inform Strider that he will need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to go through the underpass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_pripyat_group_gathering_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: assemble a squad to go to Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_pripyat_group_gathering_text">
		<text>Nitro could open the Pripyat 1 underpass lock, but he refuses to go into the Jupiter plant without protection. He further recommends that you get a few people to go through the underpass with. You already have Zulu, and he has suggested that you send new recruits to him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_pripyat_group_zulus_talk_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: talk to Zulu about going to Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_pripyat_group_zulus_talk_text">
		<text>Nitro could open the Pripyat 1 underpass lock, but he refuses to go into the Jupiter plant without protection. He further recommends that you get a few people to go through the underpass with. He suggested that you speak to Zulu, as he could help you assemble a squad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_guide_to_zulus_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: take Sokolov to see Zulu</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_guide_to_zulus_text">
		<text>Sokolov has agreed to go to Pripyat and could take a scientific suit when he leaves the bunker. You should take him to see Zulu and introduce him as a new member of the squad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: talk to Sokolov about a protective suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_talk_to_scientist_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: talk to Ozersky about a suit for Sokolov</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_talk_to_scientist_text">
		<text>Sokolov is willing to wear a scientific suit for protection, but Hermann is unlikely to let him take one from the bunker. You should talk to Ozersky - he's nicer and easier to deal with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_tell_outfit_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: tell Sokolov about the scientific suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_tell_outfit_text">
		<text>Ozersky is very happy with the plant sample. He has asked you to tell Sokolov that he can collect his scientific suit from Hermann.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_text">
		<text>The Pripyat 1 underpass has been filled with carbon dioxide mixed in with an unknown substance. You must inform Sokolov that he will need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to go through the underpass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_bring_money_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: get Vano money for the suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_bring_money_text">
		<text>The suit for which Vano owed money to the bandits had a closed-cycle respiratory module. Vano had to pawn it to pay his debts. Now he needs 3,000 to buy it back.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_guide_to_zulus_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: take Vano to see Zulu</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_guide_to_zulus_text">
		<text>Vano is willing to go to Pripyat. You must take him to see Zulu and introduce him as a new member of the squad. Vano can buy back his suit on the way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: talk to Vano about a protective suit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_stalker_text">
		<text>The Pripyat 1 underpass has been filled with carbon dioxide mixed in with an unknown substance. You must inform Vano that he will need a suit with a closed-cycle respiratory module to go through the underpass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_accuse_flint_end_text">
		<text>Flint, AKA Magpie, is a sneaky son of a bitch. You should expose him to the stalkers at Zaton or other factions. This will teach him a good lesson.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_accuse_flint_first_text">
		<text>Flint is showing off and talking about things that he hasn't even seen. It would be good to expose his deceit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_accuse_flint_name">
		<text>False claims: deal with Flint</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_accuse_flint_second_text">
		<text>Flint is clearly taking credit for the achievements of others. He needs to learn to mind his tongue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_accuse_flint_third_text">
		<text>Flint's showboating is beyond belief - you should talk to him and get him to see your point.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_senya_accuse_flint_text">
		<text>Flint, AKA Magpie, is a sneaky son of a bitch. You should expose him to the stalkers at Zaton or other factions - that would be revenge of the highest order.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_get_scanners_task_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: get scanners from the technician</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_get_scanners_task_text">
		<text>Get scanners from Novikov. Hermann wants to collect artifact formation statistics and the scanners must be placed in the center of several anomalies for this purpose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_task_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: place the scanner in the anomaly</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_task_reward_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: collect your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_task_reward_text">
		<text>Collect the reward promised to you for placing scanners in anomalies. Now that the scanners are in position, Hermann can begin to collect artifact formation data.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b32_task_text">
		<text>Place the scanner in the center of the anomaly. Hermann wants to collect artifact formation statistics and the scanners must be placed in the center of several anomalies for this purpose.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_bring_fuzz_kolobok_name">
		<text>A contract with the scientists: bring Garry the Kolobok artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_bring_fuzz_kolobok_text">
		<text>Garry needs the Kolobok artifact in order to complete his contract with the scientists. Bring him this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_bring_mincer_meat_name">
		<text>A contract with the scientists: bring Garry the Meat Chunk artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_bring_mincer_meat_text">
		<text>Garry needs the Meat Chunk artifact in order to complete his contract with the scientists. Bring him this artifact.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_contract_started_name">
		<text>A contract with the scientists: bring Garry the Meat Chunk and Kolobok artifacts</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_contract_started_text">
		<text>Garry needs the Meat Chunk and Kolobok artifacts in order to complete his contract with the scientists. Bring him these artifacts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_thanks_for_2_artifacts_name">
		<text>A contract with the scientists: artifacts delivered</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b43_thanks_for_2_artifacts_text">
		<text>Garry has both artifacts and his contract is complete.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b46_duty_founder_pda_name">
		<text>Duty history: give the Duty founder's PDA to interested parties</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b46_duty_founder_pda_text">
		<text>You found the personal PDA of the founder of Duty, who died in the anomaly. You should get this PDA to someone who would be interested in the faction leader's last moments.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b46_spatial_bubble_name">
		<text>Anomalous activity: investigate the area using an improved detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b46_spatial_bubble_text">
		<text>Scientists' scanners have registered unusual activity north of the bunker. Investigate the area using an improved detector.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_bunker_guards_01_name">
		<text>Guarding the scientists: find reliable people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_bunker_guards_01_text">
		<text>The scientists' bunker is unprotected. You must find reliable people to guard it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_bunker_guards_02_name">
		<text>Guarding the scientists: return to Hermann for your reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_bunker_guards_02_text">
		<text>You have found guards for the scientists' bunker. You should return to Hermann for the reward you're due.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_01_name">
		<text>Last developments: find documents at the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_01_text">
		<text>Hermann is interested in the Jupiter plant's last developments. Find the documents in the administrative section of the plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_02_name">
		<text>Last developments: take the documents to Hermann</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_02_text">
		<text>The documents you found indicate that all technical documentation was moved outside the plant. Although it's not much, you should convey this information to Hermann.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_03_name">
		<text>Last developments: take the documents and Black's PDA to Hermann</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b47_jupiter_products_03_text">
		<text>A mercenary attack took place while you were searching for the documents. According to the PDA you found on Black, their leader, they were sent to prevent the scientists from looking for the documents. At the same time, the documents you found indicate that all technical documentation was moved outside the plant. You should convey this information to Hermann and show him Black's PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_help_name">
		<text>Monolith survivors: talk to Yanov residents about cover</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_monolith_squad_help_text">
		<text>A squad of Monolith fighters has broken free of the spell that possessed them. They're looking for cover from emissions and mutants. You need to talk to the residents of Yanov station about allowing the Monolith squad to take cover there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_stalkers_come_duty_text">
		<text>Take Duty recruitment officers to the former Monolith squad. If the Monolith fighters join Duty, they'll be able to take cover from emissions and mutants at Yanov station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_stalkers_come_freedom_text">
		<text>Take Freedom recruitment officers to the former Monolith squad. If the Monolith fighters join Freedom, they'll be able to take cover from emissions and mutants at Yanov station.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b4_stalkers_come_name">
		<text>Monolith survivors: take recruitment officers to the former Monolith squad</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_anom_1_guard_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: cover the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_anom_1_guard_text">
		<text>It looks like the taking of measurements in the anomaly attracted mutants. You must cover the stalkers until they have collected all the data required.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_anom_2_guard_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: cover the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_anom_2_guard_text">
		<text>It looks like the taking of measurements in the anomaly attracted zombies from Kopachy. You must cover the stalkers until they have collected all the data required.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_get_reward_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: talk to Hermann</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_get_reward_text">
		<text>The anomaly measurements have been completed - inform the scientists of this and collect your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_get_to_anomal_place_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: talk to the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_get_to_anomal_place_text">
		<text>Talk to the stalker squad responsible for taking measurements - you need to choose which anomaly to go for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_travel_home_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: talk to the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_travel_home_text">
		<text>All the required measurements have been taken, so you can head back to the scientists' bunker together with the squad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_travel_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: talk to the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_travel_text">
		<text>Measurements have been taken from the anomaly, so you need to talk to the squad to discuss where to go next.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_watch_topol_squad_six_name">
		<text>Anomaly research: cover the stalkers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_watch_topol_squad_six_text">
		<text>Hermann has offered you the job of covering stalkers while they take measurements in anomalies.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b8_heli_4_crash_name">
		<text>Stingray 4: investigate the crash site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b8_heli_4_crash_name_2">
		<text>Stingray 4: find the reason for electronic burn out</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b8_heli_4_crash_text">
		<text>Investigate the Stingray 4 crash site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b8_heli_4_crash_text_2">
		<text>You must find the source of the powerful electric charge which hit the Stingray 4 helicopter.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_blackbox_decrypting_name">
		<text>Stingray 1: give the black box to a technician for decryption</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_blackbox_decrypting_text">
		<text>The Stingray 1 black box survived the crash. It must be taken to a technician for decryption for you to access the information it holds.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_blackbox_descrypted_after_3_name">
		<text>Stingray 1: wait for black box decryption to be completed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_blackbox_descrypted_after_3_text">
		<text>Nitro has agreed to decrypt the black box. He said it would take around three hours. You must wait for him to finish.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_go_for_blackbox_descryption_name">
		<text>Stingray 1: return to Nitro for information held by the black box</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_go_for_blackbox_descryption_text">
		<text>Nitro should have completed the decryption process by now. Go see him to get the information held by the black box.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_heli_1_crash_name">
		<text>Stingray 1: investigate the crash site</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b9_heli_1_crash_text">
		<text>Investigate the Stingray 1 crash site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: get to Pripyat</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_text">
		<text>You must get through the Pripyat 1 underpass and reach the military evacuation point in Pripyat.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gases_check_chemistry_workshop_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate the chemical compound workshop at the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gases_check_chemistry_workshop_text">
		<text>The chemical compound workshop should contain information about the flooding of the Pripyat 1 underpass with some sort of gas.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_corps_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate the administrative section of the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_corps_text">
		<text>The guide does not know of a safe route to Pripyat, but he has suggested where you can find information about underground tunnels that lead from the Jupiter plant to the city. You should start with the administrative section.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_electrical_workshop_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate the laboratory section of the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_electrical_workshop_text">
		<text>The documents found in the administrative section mention evacuation of the production complex from the Jupiter plant. Information concerning this matter should be in the laboratory section.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_transport_workshop_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: check the Pripyat 1 underpass transportation lock</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_gates_check_transport_workshop_text">
		<text>The entrance to the underground underpass is behind the transportation lock. Investigate the area and look for any information concerning the underpass.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_archives_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate Department 1 of the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_archives_text">
		<text>There should be information about the Pripyat 1 underpass in Department 1. This information could be very useful, so you should check there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_delivery_department_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate the delivery department of the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_delivery_department_text">
		<text>Judging by the note in the laboratory workshop, the evacuation was supposed to have been carried out by the delivery department, so you should check there as well.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_repair_workshop_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: investigate the repair workshop of the Jupiter plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_check_repair_workshop_text">
		<text>The delivery department had information about losses during transportation of something referred to as item 62. According to the records, the repair workshop was charged with handling this matter - you should check there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_tell_stalker_guide_name">
		<text>Road to Pripyat: talk to the guide</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_a9_way_to_pripyat_tell_stalker_guide_text">
		<text>According to the recording in the black box of one of the helicopters, the military units were supposed to converge on evacuation point B28. According to the maps found in the other helicopter that took part of the mission, this point is located in Pripyat. You'll have to find some way of getting there - talk to the guide about it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b207_depot_reward_task_name">
		<text>Duty warehouse: take what you're owed</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b207_morgan_depot_task_name">
		<text>Duty warehouse: meet Morgan</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b207_morgan_depot_task_text">
		<text>Morgan the trader has offered you access to Duty's warehouse as payment for your silence about his business. You need to meet him near the quarry as agreed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_gate_text">
		<text>You must open the gate to keep going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_door_text">
		<text>You must open the door to keep going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_hall_door_text">
		<text>You must activate the power supply to the gate to keep going.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="pas_b400_pripyat_control_text">
		<text>You must unblock the gate to keep going. This can probably be done from the control room.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_employ_stalkers_name">
		<text>Research group: Hire the right people</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_employ_stalkers_text">
		<text>A research group working for the scientists has perished. You must staff a new group so research can continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_employ_stalkers_reward_name">
		<text>Research group: Return to Hermann for the reward</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b6_employ_stalkers_reward_text">
		<text>You've found the right people for a new research group. Now return to Hermann to collect your reward.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_do_scientist_quest_name">
		<text>Pripyat 1: complete Ozersky’s mission</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b218_soldier_do_scientist_quest_text">
		<text>You need to complete Ozersky’s mission involving the anomalous plant to get a protective suit for Sokolov.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b200_tech_materials_inside_text">
		<text>Nitro needs radio technical materials. You need to find them in the cement factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_flint_and_senya_text">
		<text>It was Flint who left Splinter to die in the anomaly. Talk to him and find out why he did it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_revenge_senya_name">
		<text>Retribution: avenge Splinter</text>
	</string>
	<string id="jup_b25_revenge_senya_text">
		<text>Find whoever left Splinter to die in an anomaly, having taken the artifact and left. Unfortunately, Splinter didn’t manage to name the villain, so all that’s known about him is that he is a member of Freedom.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b207_depot_reward_task_duty_text">
		<text>Lieutenant Colonel Shulga has permitted you to take any equipment you want from the Duty warehouse if you manage to capture it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="zat_b207_depot_reward_task_freedom_text">
		<text>Loki has allowed you to take any equipment you want from the Duty warehouse as long as it’s held by Freedom fighters.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
